<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Po-33 on NearTao&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/po-33/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Po-33 on NearTao&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:27:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/po-33/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #06 - Something</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/06/beatober2021-06-something/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:27:56 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=3347</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And now for something completely different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uFkvE6DVNqs?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I just decided to do what I could with the pocket operators I have on hand&amp;hellip; PO-32, PO-33, PO-35&amp;hellip; and see what would come from it. I&amp;rsquo;ll definitely get back to the MPC Live and Eurorack, but just needed a change of pace for a bit. Probably will do another PO track or two for the time being and go for something a bit longer, I suspect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - STBB #697 - Good &#39;ol Claude</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/07/15/track-stbb-697-good-ol-claude/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 11:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=704</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/good-ol-claude&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/good-ol-claude&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s challenge on &lt;a href=&#34;https://stbbforever.com/viewtopic.php?f=2&amp;amp;t=711&#34;&gt;STBB Forever is #697 - Claude Debussy&lt;/a&gt;. Rules were pretty open, go find your own Claude sounds. I ended up listening to a *lot* of this Youtube track&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qRZmdzCGLYw?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t listen to the whole thing, but I did consume a lot of it. There is a lot of great music in here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - On the Road</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/07/09/track-on-the-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 17:06:20 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=681</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/on-the-road&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/on-the-road&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a track I have been working on for about a week on the PO-33. All the sampling and mixing was done within the little box. I continue to like this little device because it really forces you to think about a potentially crippling amount of sampling time and a very real four note polyphony limit. Some of the previous tracks I have done really ran into the polyphony wall, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t exactly drop notes the way I would expect at least.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - STBB #695 - Running Forever</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/07/01/track-stbb-695-running-forever/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 23:14:35 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=634</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/stbb-695-running-forever&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/stbb-695-running-forever&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track comes courtesy of &lt;a href=&#34;https://stbbforever.com/viewtopic.php?f=2&amp;amp;t=691&amp;amp;sid=7d0cdf19c7200d2c7faafcb7c573a9ee&#34;&gt;STBB Forever BB #695&lt;/a&gt;, there were two tracks to chop up. The rules were effectively to chop whatever, use your own drums, no external instruments, and you needed to drop a change up in the track. I&amp;rsquo;m interested to see what others do this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to the MPC BB this week, I was really crunched for time to work on this. This time however I decided I would just do the track in the PO-33, and make it a quick flip. So I loaded the tracks into the MPC, but didn&amp;rsquo;t even bother chopping on the MPC, I just shuffled the starting point around the tracks and sampled in what ever I wanted to start or stop, and was able to get four or five interesting chops pretty quickly from the first track. For the second track, I just sampled roughly a loop, and let the auto chopper do it&amp;rsquo;s magic, or horrible destruction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - MPC 283 - Road to Mama</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/06/30/track-mpc-283-road-to-mama/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 23:41:48 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=626</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/mpcbb-283-road-to-mama&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/mpcbb-283-road-to-mama&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This picture comes courtesy of Photoshop Camera on the iPhone with one of the goofy filters. I was out RV&amp;rsquo;ing with my family and my parents for a couple of days over the weekend&amp;hellip; which held me up from having time to pull together more of a track. I was split on the track this week, and was messing around on Sunday afternoon on the MPC, and the yesterday I flipped to try to put a track together on the PO-33.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - Glitchnique</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/05/27/track-glitchnique/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=390</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you can believe it&amp;hellip; this came as a result of two different tracks built pretty much at the same time on the PO-33. This one was made up of 12 patterns, the other one used the other 4 to mess around (I&amp;rsquo;ll post the other track below). The same samples led to completely different inspirations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/BRw5bR-GOIU&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/BRw5bR-GOIU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely sure that I&amp;rsquo;ll keep doing these kinds of visual videos or not&amp;hellip; it added a bit more production time to something I just wanted to goof around with. Plus, since it was posted (a month ago) it&amp;rsquo;s only gotten one view&amp;hellip; so yeah&amp;hellip; not terribly popular. It was fun to play around with the software on my iPad though, so I suppose it isn&amp;rsquo;t a complete loss. I&amp;rsquo;ll just need to keep my mind open and learn.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who&#39;s Home - PO-33 #Jamuary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/01/21/whos-home-po-33-jamuary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=359</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not really happy with this, but I also had a bit of a gap for #Jamuary. Guess it was too much to think I&amp;rsquo;d put something together every day. On the other hand, it is freeing to have just taken a few takes, and going for the best of them so that I can move on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There really isn&amp;rsquo;t anything too special here, and I actually sampled way more than I ended up using. Some of the other tracks I&amp;rsquo;ve posted I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking of going back and actually tracking them out and mixing them up a bit, but this one I was super into last week, and now it just kind of falls flat for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Its my Jam - PO-33 Track</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/01/10/its-my-jam-po-33-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=340</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The image is courtesy of a road trip I did with my family from the East Coast out to Montana. On the way back we stopped at an amethyst mine, and I got some really cool pictures of some older beat up vehicles. There was some really cool stuff going on here, and we got some neat amethyst crystals to bring back home with us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the song, nothing too fancy here, just using samples of thumps and bumps from everyday objects. A lot of the magic is just pitching things up and down, using filters&amp;hellip; and then just jamming it out. I&amp;rsquo;m going to stick with the PO-33 a bit longer, but a lot of the initial magic playing around with the FX again is a bit gone, it has now gone from being novel to producing some pretty similar sounds to my ear. The device is still fantastic, and it might just be time for me start considering what I am going to move on to for a device to keep going on making tracks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glass Mythology - PO-33 Track</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/01/09/glass-mythology-po-33-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=330</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The image comes courtesy of a business trip to Bangalore. The pool with the blue lights looked amazing so I had to take a picture. I&amp;rsquo;ll have to keep an eye out for more of these eye catching images&amp;hellip; and maybe I can do a better job getting a &amp;ldquo;live&amp;rdquo; photo on my phone&amp;hellip; or a video&amp;hellip; so I can work out some neat video tricks versus just having a video of me clicking on guitar pedals and such.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Afternoon Breeze - PO-33 Track</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/01/08/afternoon-breeze-po-33-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=317</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The image is from my daughter. While we took a trip out to Montana she kept borrowing my phone to take strange pictures with odd filters. This is one of many featuring one of our dogs. It looked intense enough to be a good track image. Enjoy the image of my dog slowly zooming in while listening to a electro song plays!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funny thing&amp;hellip; I was going to do another house track, and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I&amp;rsquo;d place it quite in that genre, is it electro house? I don&amp;rsquo;t think it is fast enough for Techno&amp;hellip; Somebody who has more refined taste might be able to clarify the music genre for me. I just thought it sounded cool!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winter Happiness - PO-33 Track</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/01/07/winter-happiness-po-33-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 18:40:30 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=308</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I used some Washi tape to label the write and record on the PO-33 on the case. I keep pushing the wrong one and deleting samples or otherwise overwriting stuff I don&amp;rsquo;t want to. I&amp;rsquo;m just not keeping the two clear in my mind. Also, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t help that the write button with the white dot reminds me of a record button&amp;hellip; but yeah, it is still me! :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently I&amp;rsquo;m really sticking with one or two drum loops, some vocals chopped up by and amateur (well the PO-33), an instrument sound, and maybe a bass sound. I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to do something different to push myself to not fall into a track. And&amp;hellip; This track fell out of the sky! Well rather, I just recorded off some more samples to see what I could do to push the PO-33 a bit more. By pushing, I mostly mean doing even more FX and changing the FX up more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Tiny House - PO 33 Track</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/01/07/my-tiny-house-po-33-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 02:12:54 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=301</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had intended in jamming out on the MPC today, but I ended up grabbing the PO 33 again&amp;hellip; Producing another small track. Seriously folks, I am surprised at how much big sound can come out of such a small device! This is maybe 30 minutes worth of playing around max.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want a laugh, this is maybe seven, max eight, seconds of audio samples. If I actually put the effort in to trim down the wasted space in the drum track, I might be able to get it down to four or five seconds. Honestly, I&amp;rsquo;m not bothered by it, but it really goes to show even with the old school hardware and multiple limitations, those older machines really could knock out some bangers without too much effort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Early Morning Chat - PO-33 Track</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/01/05/early-morning-chat-po-33-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=291</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although I&amp;rsquo;ve been happily selling off gear, I&amp;rsquo;ve still got the Teenage Engineering Pocket Operators I picked up a while back. I was feeling like putting something together super fast, and while I was planning on recording off samples, creating drum programs, all that fun stuff&amp;hellip; I also didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spend too much time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip; I reached for my trusty PO-33 and decided to sample in some beats. Originally I was going to use the internal microphone, but while this is sometimes interesting, there was a bit too much background noise (ie, the kid wouldn&amp;rsquo;t stop singing Frozen songs). I had to use the line in, which honestly does tend to have a fuller sound, the microphone is fine, but often it does lack the bottom end a bit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
