<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>News on NearTao&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on NearTao&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 17:35:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/news/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Native Instruments selling to Francisco Partners</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/21/native-instruments-selling-to-francisco-partners/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 17:35:21 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1826</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not sure how many people are NI fans&amp;hellip; I used to be deep into the ecosystem years ago&amp;hellip; but this is pretty big news!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tinyurl.com/yy7uznun&#34;&gt;Native Instruments selling to Francisco Partners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the release of Machine+, and the sheer number of instruments, effects, and downloadable content for expansions, there will clearly be a lot happening at Native Instruments over the next few years. I&amp;rsquo;ll be interested to see where they continue to go with the stand alone boxes. The technology continues to deliver on more and more portable power, and there&amp;rsquo;s certainly a market for NI to capitalize on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2020-08-25 News - Sticky Situations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/08/25/2020-08-25-news-sticky-situations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 22:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=937</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nydailynews.com/careers-finance/sns-bb-startups-tap-college-student-talent-pool-20200819-ce5e5hwnzfbbpltypepcp7r6dq-story.html&#34;&gt;Startups tap a new talent pool: Pandemic-weary college students&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just going to lead with this thought: college students, please continue to get your degrees!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to manage a team of roughly fifty employees, and I had plenty of college students and interns. We would frequently extend internships, and occasionally bring interns on as full time employees. Often this was done to help retain talent, but I would always talk to these employees to make sure that they would continue their school.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2020-08-24 - The Big Melt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/08/24/2020-08-24-the-big-melt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 17:40:59 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=919</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Articles and videos that hit my feed and some thoughts on them. Just my opinions&amp;hellip; take it or leave it :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/08/apple-apologizes-to-wordpress-no-longer-requires-free-app-to-add-purchases/&#34;&gt;Apple apologizes to Wordpress, no longer requires free app to add purchases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I read last week that Apple was removing the Wordpress app from the Apple store I thought things were getting a little strange. The application never had payments in place, and you had to go to the Wordpress site to pay for your subscription. I suspect that given everything going on with Epic and the Fortnight fiasco that Apple is just getting overly sensitive about companies removing their ability to get a 30% cut.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
