<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Album on NearTao&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/album/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Album on NearTao&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 15:39:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/album/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Album: Embrace Your Roots</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/06/14/album-embrace-your-roots/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 15:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=100</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This here is the fourth album I put together, and it is steeped in Ableton Live&amp;hellip; Live 2.0 and beyond I believe. I&amp;rsquo;d have to go back and look&amp;hellip; if I could even find the old project files&amp;hellip; woof. Most of this is just taking loop libraries, sometimes chopping them, but probably mostly just placing the loops on the timeline and mixing the volume levels. I had been reading a lot about Ableton at the time and it was getting a lot of hype. Note: I still miss the old warping method&amp;hellip; *sigh*&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album: A Passing of Time</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/05/19/album-a-passing-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 12:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=409</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was the third album I put together and was still heavily influenced by Acid Pro, I think I was using Acid Pro 4.0. I was getting far more comfortable using loops, the interface, and was starting to incorporate the Triton Studio into my productions too. Sometimes I would play a lot by hand, other times I was just playing chords and letting the arpeggiator do a lot of the work for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album: Eclectic Electronica</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/11/08/album-eclectic-electronica/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=89</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found more album and artwork things! So let&amp;rsquo;s just get right to it for this, my second album, and originally published (okay, I burned it myself and printed out all the artwork) as a two album discography for friends and family. I&amp;rsquo;m willing to bet that all the copies made it to the trash or got exposed to the sun ruining my nicely burned CDs. Yeah, that was a thing back in the day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album: Aboriginal Dream</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/10/26/album-aboriginal-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 00:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=85</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well&amp;hellip; I figured out to mount my old NAS box, and while it is a treasure trove of media, it is also a big, unsorted mess. It&amp;rsquo;s going to take some time for me to dig through and find albums, artwork, and put it all together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the moment I think I have settled on Bandcamp as a target to upload content. It seems to be reasonable service wise compared to soundcloud. I&amp;rsquo;ll keep playing around though. Below is the album, enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
