<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Ableton-Live on NearTao&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ableton-live/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ableton-Live on NearTao&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 20:50:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ableton-live/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Track - I Really Don&#39;t Mind</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/10/15/track-i-really-dont-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 20:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1106</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/i-really-dont-mind-ableton&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/i-really-dont-mind-ableton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track I threw together for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mpc-forums.com/viewtopic.php?f=40&amp;amp;t=204552&#34;&gt;MPC Forums Beat Battle #293&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s still open if you wanted to check it out and post up your own take. The sample to flip this time around is Brenton Wood &amp;ldquo;Trouble&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I just loaded the track into the MPC Live, set it to chop on transients with a setting of 50, and then just started looking for samples I thought sounded cool. Was this lazy? Probably, but for this beat battle I wanted to force myself outside of the mindset of using perfect loops, and some of those transients were janky as heck, making me think way outside of the box.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - Just Breath</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/10/14/track-just-breath/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 20:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1101</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/just-breath&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/just-breath&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really wanted to do something kind of epic, kind of 8-bit, and kind of fun&amp;hellip; hopefully this track hits those beats for you. All of the tracks were done on the MPC Live mk2, and I exported the stems for arrangement out in Ableton Live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most abusive thing I did was decimating that clap hit into a bit crunched bunch of noise, the rest was pretty standard flare, with maybe a bit of automation thrown in for effect just to give the track some movement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - Space Dust</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/10/13/track-space-dust/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 21:11:55 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1090</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/mpcbb-292-space-dust&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/mpcbb-292-space-dust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put this track together last week for the MPC BB 292, and then forgot to post about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first trick, to get the really over cooked sound from the track, I ended up pitching the track up 3 octaves before playing it, and then sampled it into my Akai S950. This really stripped away a lot of the high end information, but also made the low end quite a bit punchier to my ears. Initially I pitched it up so much because I just didn&amp;rsquo;t have the sample time to record a nearly 6 minute song into the roughly 23 seconds of sample time&amp;hellip; and pitching the content up so extremely really let me squeeze it all in there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - STBB703 - Greatest Destiny</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/08/27/track-stbb703-greatest-destiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 12:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=954</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/stbb703-greatest-destiny&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/stbb703-greatest-destiny&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track&amp;hellip; well the rule was to use the sample&amp;hellip; and do something outside your comfort zone. I rarely put any kind of silence in my track, so I wanted to force myself to have breaks throughout the song, but have it sound as natural as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the track was put together on the MPC Live mk2, but I also did load the finished track into Ableton Live for some further poking and prodding. The middle section that kind of functions as a drop, and the outro were both done in Ableton. I figured it was a short enough track, but needed something to mix it up a bit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electro Funk - Robot Love</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/08/14/electro-funk-robot-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 16:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=865</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/robot-love&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/robot-love&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track has been a bit of a labor of love&amp;hellip; haha. I decided to jump into the next challenge for Electro Funk, and was listening to a lot of tracks from the era. If you want to check out the main post on MPC Forums for the Electro Funk Challenge, well go on over &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mpc-forums.com/viewtopic.php?f=7&amp;amp;t=200241&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Been a lot of discussion again, and I think it was the third page I dropped a number of YouTube videos, most of which are in the right style.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - STBB #697 - Good &#39;ol Claude</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/07/15/track-stbb-697-good-ol-claude/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 11:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=704</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/good-ol-claude&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/good-ol-claude&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s challenge on &lt;a href=&#34;https://stbbforever.com/viewtopic.php?f=2&amp;amp;t=711&#34;&gt;STBB Forever is #697 - Claude Debussy&lt;/a&gt;. Rules were pretty open, go find your own Claude sounds. I ended up listening to a *lot* of this Youtube track&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qRZmdzCGLYw?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t listen to the whole thing, but I did consume a lot of it. There is a lot of great music in here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - On the Road</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/07/09/track-on-the-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 17:06:20 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=681</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/on-the-road&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/on-the-road&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a track I have been working on for about a week on the PO-33. All the sampling and mixing was done within the little box. I continue to like this little device because it really forces you to think about a potentially crippling amount of sampling time and a very real four note polyphony limit. Some of the previous tracks I have done really ran into the polyphony wall, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t exactly drop notes the way I would expect at least.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - STBB #696 - Disco Gummy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/07/07/track-stbb-696-disco-gummy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 18:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=661</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For this week, the drop was what&amp;hellip; 300+ clips. The rules were to use at least three, and you had to put product placement in your track of at least five seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/stbb-696-disco-gummy&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/stbb-696-disco-gummy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the &lt;a href=&#34;https://stbbforever.com/viewtopic.php?f=2&amp;amp;t=701&#34;&gt;STBB Beat Battle #696 Funky-Disco-Trip&lt;/a&gt; I tore threw a bunch of loops that I found interesting to work with, and decided to use Ableton Live this time to put it together. I haven&amp;rsquo;t used Ableton Live a whole lot in the last few years, but I still mostly know my way around, and it&amp;rsquo;s like riding a bicycle right, just hop back on?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Audio Book Vocal Processing Pt. 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/07/06/audiobook-vocal-processing-pt-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 19:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=677</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well I just (hopefully) wrapped up the audio processing for my sister&amp;rsquo;s book. Since the last post, I probably could have done three other posts about the series of events that happened. Suffice it to say that there are some competing formats, tools, and audiobook sites that aren&amp;rsquo;t exactly in alignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip; I had gotten my sister&amp;rsquo;s book all processed, converted to .mp3 format, and she was quite happy with the sound. Unfortunately she doesn&amp;rsquo;t really understand audio processing or audio file formats, so this kicked off a chain of unfortunate re-exports. Each process and export job probably took me 60-90 minutes&amp;hellip; and since I had only ever expected to do this twice, I never automated the job. Each time I ended up processing the files, it was &amp;ldquo;just one more change&amp;rdquo; which had me shrug, and go off and do a whole bunch of clicking to re-process the files again. After time five, you&amp;rsquo;d think I would have learned my lesson. Which I did, but maybe not the one you&amp;rsquo;d think.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moving from Ableton Live to an MPC</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/06/24/moving-from-ableton-live-to-an-mpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=608</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are some explanation I gave over at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mpc-forums.com/viewtopic.php?f=48&amp;amp;t=198904&amp;amp;p=1798905#p1798905&#34;&gt;MPC Forums&lt;/a&gt; to help explain how an MPC works if you&amp;rsquo;re coming from and Ableton Live environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came from Ableton myself… and it&amp;rsquo;s a much different environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main things to get your head wrapped around on the MPC is sampling and sample management, programs (drums and key groups mostly), tracks and how to drop notes across various tracks to group things, and sequences to hold each section of your song.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Audio Book Vocal Processing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/06/19/audio-book-vocal-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 12:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=585</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My sister has released the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/SOMNIUM-Beyond-Darkness-D-Sterling-ebook/dp/B087T5TVSS#ace-g1639449406&#34;&gt;SOMNIUM Beyond the Darkness&lt;/a&gt; on Amazon as a kindle book and as a paperback book, which is an excellent read for young adults and adults alike. She&amp;rsquo;s been looking to expand out into the audio book space, which makes sense to me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She had been looking into some voice actors who could read the book. When I heard the audio quality of the demo, it was rather poor. We were hoping that it was just a quick demo, but it suffered from a lot of background noise. My sister passed on links to the voice actor, and the demo&amp;rsquo;s she had on her website were great. After I gave my sister a few questions to ask and suggestions for contract negotiations, unfortunately it fell through. We suspect that the voice actor recorded her website demo at a professional studio, and likely recorded the demo she produced for my sister at home. Total bummer, but it&amp;rsquo;s better to both live and learn, and get through these miss steps early is what I always say.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No More Technology - #Jamuary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/01/11/no-more-technology-jamuary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 21:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=349</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No eurorack modules were harmed in the making of this video. The PO-32 (Tonic) makes up the drums, the PO-35 (Voice) is how I got the &amp;ldquo;No More Technology&amp;rdquo; hook, and&amp;hellip; the lead/bass came from some Eurorack mess. I recorded all of this into Ableton Live for some FX processing. All of this was recorded back in October/November, and I&amp;rsquo;ve meant to create a finished track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of #Jamuary though, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d break out some gear and refine the track a bit more. I&amp;rsquo;m really trying to cap myself to about 30-60 minutes of production time this month for each song. This is good in some ways because it&amp;rsquo;s forcing me to get ideas down, but it is bad in a few other ways since I&amp;rsquo;m really not mixing/mastering anything. Leaving this track with a bit more of a tinny sound than I&amp;rsquo;d like, but hey it is what it is.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
