<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Boss-Sp-202 on NearTao&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/boss-sp-202/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Boss-Sp-202 on NearTao&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 02:05:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/boss-sp-202/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Track - Isolation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/11/13/track-isolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 02:05:39 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3551</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not sure why, but this feels like it is in the space of the &amp;lsquo;peak sound&amp;rsquo; I&amp;rsquo;ve been working towards with this setup. Still a bit noisy and still a bit awkward to control sometimes, but hands on, a bit glitchy, and something that can sustain momentum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/t1mUOeepWNw&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/t1mUOeepWNw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The track started the day as something happier, but as it wore on, I just kind of went into my own space of wishing, longing, dreaming, but all at a distance with some strange energy. Not the track I had set off to put together but it might be the track I needed to put together right now. I do like this, and hope that others get something out of it too, but I guess I just had poured a lot more self reflective vibes here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Music Studio Audio Setup - Zoom H6 Issues and How I Addressed Them</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/11/09/music-studio-audio-setup-zoom-h6-issues-and-how-i-addressed-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 13:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3535</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on trying to figure out where I am having issues with my audio setup, to try and get a hotter signal in my video recordings. So I drew up a rough sketch to see if I could get some notes on what the issue might be and go from there&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/audio-setup-sketch.jpg?w=1024&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The long component with the knobs/buttons on it that is unlabelled is the Behringer RX1602 that I picked up&amp;hellip; I just forgot to label it apparently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #19 - A Night With Friends</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/19/beatober2021-19-a-night-with-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3416</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well&amp;hellip; here it is for today&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/wcvIsJlfGCI&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/wcvIsJlfGCI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The track gave me some problems. Mostly Total Recall&amp;hellip; I just realized that it triggers or rather changes parameters on the down event of a clock or gate&amp;hellip; and Pam&amp;rsquo;s was sending a gate for 50% of a beat, meaning that the change was happening on 1.3 instead of 1.1 of a bar. Doh! This was giving me all kinds of problems, and I&amp;rsquo;ll need to rethink how I&amp;rsquo;m using Total Recall. The quick fix was to change the gate width from 50% down to 1%, but I still feel like this leaves some margin for error. Back to the drawing board a bit for how I&amp;rsquo;m using Total recall. Surprisingly, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t even noticed this until today&amp;hellip; I guess the more ambient sounds just weren&amp;rsquo;t making me notice it so much, but the arp today&amp;hellip; woah boy&amp;hellip; was it messing with my timing&amp;hellip; took a few tries before I got to the &amp;ldquo;is it me, or is it you&amp;rdquo; thought&amp;hellip; I guess at least it wasn&amp;rsquo;t me this time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #18 - Late Night Drifters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/18/beatober2021-18-late-night-drifters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:52:42 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3408</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yah&amp;hellip; sometimes we just need to simplify!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/ldJchNxMaWQ&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/ldJchNxMaWQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could&amp;rsquo;ve made this into a longer track, but yeah&amp;hellip; I think keeping it short and simple definitely kept it moving and interesting. At least I feel like I got more out of it than I would have otherwise trying to layer a ton of sounds in and then having a big mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effectively I made the four tracks on the MPC to begin with, and spent the time making sure I was happy with the eight bars first, pretty similar to what I did yesterday. From there I just starting assigning tracks to different outputs on the MPC, and then driving them through different effects in eurorack, and then, as usual, I chased it with the SP 202 and SP 303 at the tail end to just add the dust, grit, and grunge for the song.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #16 - Simple Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/16/beatober2021-16-simple-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 14:08:12 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3394</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Decided to keep it simple today&amp;hellip; really simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/3bMvOTQSWq8&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/3bMvOTQSWq8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What all is going on? The picture comes from Neural Blender again&amp;hellip; still having fun with this, I still need to buy some credits and go to town here. Even if the images are not necessarily directly useful, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely got some inspiring and striking looks to a lot of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well&amp;hellip; the spacey ambient sound was some piano riffs I loaded up into the Morphagene, which was a pain because the piano audio was quite dynamic for its&amp;rsquo; range, going from really quiet -20db/-30db area to 0db. Sending it from the 3/4 outputs on the MPC (which I am sure are outputting at either 0db or possibly +4db, need to read the manual again) meant that until I dropped the track down to -9db it was just getting somewhat pleasing, but mostly awful noise on the high end. Certainly I could have used a LPF to clean it up, but honestly I wanted a cleaner sound here. Once I had the audio recorded, I then manipulated the gene size until I had something that seemed relatively musical and seemed like a nice enough progression. I then clocked the Morphagene from Pamela&amp;rsquo;s New Workout so that it would play relatively at a speed with the track. From here I used the Mimetic Digitalis to change the cutoff on the Sqwak Dirty LPF to have the sound change over time while the track played.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #15 - Funk Your Style</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/15/beatober2021-15-funk-your-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 01:16:54 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3389</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay&amp;hellip; today felt pretty good&amp;hellip; but did like&amp;hellip; five&amp;hellip; maybe six takes&amp;hellip; was getting a bit of a jam going and then would make a mistake&amp;hellip; this take came together pretty well though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/JGcR613&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/JGcR613&lt;/a&gt;_21U&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my pretty traditional setup I&amp;rsquo;ve been going for lately, but with the SP 202 and SP 303 added to the end of the chain&amp;hellip; oh and I&amp;rsquo;ve added in the Zoom H6 at the end of chain to function a bit as a mixer/audio router&amp;hellip; the RCA to 1/4&amp;quot; adaptors are what is causing me the biggest headache in this setup&amp;hellip; but it is kind of nice having the 202 do LPF duties at the end of the chain, and then the Vinyl FX from the 303 to do some compression and wow/flutter duties&amp;hellip; and a hint of vinyl noise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - New Paint</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/24/jamtember2021-track-new-paint/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 17:27:04 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3243</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Man&amp;hellip; the MPC Live mk2 rarely crashes on me&amp;hellip; and lost some work&amp;hellip; I suspect I know what I did&amp;hellip; but *sigh*&amp;hellip; anyways&amp;hellip; regrouped and did this&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/new-paint&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/new-paint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is just one of my watercolor paint sets&amp;hellip; almost went with a rain motif instead&amp;hellip; boy is it raining out right now!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - Wanderlust</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/23/jamtember2021-track-wanderlust/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 16:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3236</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hah&amp;hellip; this shook out after three or four failed attempts to get something jamming right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/wanderlust&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/wanderlust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picture is from the trip to Yellowstone&amp;hellip; I mean&amp;hellip; if you ever can&amp;hellip; you got to go. Just amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah yeah yeah&amp;hellip; another vaporwave style&amp;hellip; and I swear, I&amp;rsquo;ll get some videos up of the process I&amp;rsquo;m doing&amp;hellip; honestly nothing too fancy, but I should probably see if I can get something similar to work just within the MPC instead of needing two&amp;hellip; retro/older&amp;hellip; Boss SPs&amp;hellip; yet&amp;hellip; it is frequently working&amp;hellip; so what do I know.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - Shawty</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/22/jamtember2021-track-shawty/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 00:55:29 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3232</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay&amp;hellip; needed to try something different&amp;hellip; and this is both short and way out there&amp;hellip; but kind of dig it more than the last track for the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/shawty&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/shawty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now off to do family stuff&amp;hellip; peace!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - Don&#39;t Forget Grandma</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/22/jamtember2021-track-dont-forget-grandma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 22:08:27 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3226</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip; you literally have to smile when you hear the song and see the pic together&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s like illegal or something if you don&amp;rsquo;t. Now&amp;hellip; you don&amp;rsquo;t have to like either individually, but as a total package&amp;hellip; well&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/dont-forget-grandma&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/dont-forget-grandma&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is of my grandmother, or as many people knew her, as the world&amp;rsquo;s grandma. She was a great woman who cared for everybody. Honestly, she was amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways&amp;hellip; just standard song duty for the day, kinda hit or miss again for me&amp;hellip; probably time to push myself in another direction, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to see what happens if I just do the same style/process for a month. What I think is happening is that I&amp;rsquo;m getting faster at the process, but also getting pickier&amp;hellip; who&amp;rsquo;d have thought?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - Everything Hurts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/21/jamtember2021-track-everything-hurts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 23:41:26 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3219</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well&amp;hellip; this kind of went into the DnB direction&amp;hellip; and I just gave it a shot&amp;hellip; takes 30 seconds to come together, which isn&amp;rsquo;t really great&amp;hellip; but maybe next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/everything-hurts&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/everything-hurts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the picture. Well this is my friend bee. Found the poor guy hanging out on my deck post, and wasn&amp;rsquo;t flying away. So I gave him some honey, which he ate up for a while. Later the honey and the bee were gone. Either I saved the bee&amp;rsquo;s life in its&amp;rsquo; time of need, or I ended up attracting something bigger that ate the bee. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure. But as my friend, I am going to imagine that I saved the bee, and in the future he&amp;rsquo;s going to communicate to his bee buddies that I helped save his life and that he&amp;rsquo;ll return the favor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - Flying Low</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/20/jamtember2021-track-flying-low/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 16:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3214</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well not really what I meant to do&amp;hellip; had a sample prepared on the 202&amp;hellip; and then in a rush I deleted it&amp;hellip; yo&amp;hellip; not my finest. Next time I need to leave a sticky note or something for something *face palm*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/flying-low&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/flying-low&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways&amp;hellip; this was&amp;hellip; I dunno&amp;hellip; just another thing tossed together. Haven&amp;rsquo;t been feeling some of the stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting together, but still committing to doing something, anything&amp;hellip; at least once a day. And folks are posting for beatober&amp;hellip; do I go for it? Maybe&amp;hellip; but gonna have to do something different, cuz I&amp;rsquo;m definitely finding it hard to squeeze the time in the last few days.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - At The Garden Gates</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/16/jamtember2021-track-at-the-garden-gates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 21:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3198</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I mean&amp;hellip; who doesn&amp;rsquo;t love gnomes, am I right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/at-the-garden-gates&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/at-the-garden-gates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just knocked this out in maybe 30 minutes&amp;hellip; the mix is a bit off, definitely some of the parts could use some filtering or eq&amp;hellip; but hey&amp;hellip; gotta keep rolling these things out!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - By The Pool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/15/jamtember2021-track-by-the-pool/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 22:42:41 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3194</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yeah yeah yeah&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s still kind of like summer out here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/by-the-pool&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/by-the-pool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This picture is from a trip years ago&amp;hellip; bumper boats and all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a quick thing I knocked out as a second track for the day&amp;hellip; definitely had fun!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - Lambic Eight</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/15/jamtember2021-track-lambic-eight/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 13:06:10 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3186</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Word&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/lambic-eight&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/lambic-eight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I just used the picture from a website&amp;hellip; sue me&amp;hellip; well don&amp;rsquo;t&amp;hellip; but I didn&amp;rsquo;t happen to have eight lambic around to photograph&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is yet another track in the vaporwave style&amp;hellip; or rather&amp;hellip; dumping some loops/sounds into the SP-202 and making something pitched down&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m probably abusing this too much by now for making a track a day for the month&amp;hellip; but hey&amp;hellip; if it works? Keep on filtering? Keep on trying out the new synths on the MPC from 2.10? I mean heck yeah!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - Raving Mad</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/13/jamtember2021-track-raving-mad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 23:15:06 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3174</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shot off a second track for the day&amp;hellip; this time some DnB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/raving-mad&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/raving-mad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is of my daughter&amp;rsquo;s teddy bear, from years ago when we took a train ride in northern New Hampshire. Tea and scones were absolutely had, at this simply fabulous tea party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The track was pretty simple&amp;hellip; just did my vaporwave thing&amp;hellip; found four loops that seemed to work together&amp;hellip; though this admittedly took a while today&amp;hellip; because I tried five or six combinations that seemed fine, but when recorded as Lofi on the SP-202 and then slowed down they sounded quite poor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - Constant Barrage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/13/jamtember2021-track-constant-barrage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 19:24:36 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3168</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not exactly sure what I was trying to do here&amp;hellip; but this is all inside the MPC&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/constant-barrage&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/constant-barrage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a picture of one of my dogs eyeballs&amp;hellip; really close up&amp;hellip; hah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The track was really just taking some samples, a few of them run through the SP-202, and then seeing what I could put together. In particular I spent a lot more time on the drums in the SP-202, with a bit of added distortion from the SP-303 to just give them a bit more punch.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - Always</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/12/jamtember2021-track-always/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 15:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3156</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mostly happy with how this track came out&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/always&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/always&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picture is just of the SP-202&amp;hellip; just thought it looked kinda cool all lit up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The track itself came together pretty quickly, though I did have to go tweak a number of samples once I ran it through YAM&amp;hellip; all of a sudden I was noticing all kinds of clipping and noise. The atmospheric sound at the beginning was full of so many pops and clips. I didn&amp;rsquo;t remove all of them, but definitely reduced it a bit by just tweaking the program. The bass was just super noisy, probably as a result from having run it through the SP-202 a bit, so I had to drop a LPF on it to clean it up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - Check Your Inbox</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/10/jamtember2021-track-check-your-inbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 15:59:28 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3145</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just another quick one&amp;hellip; really dug the time stretched loop and figured I&amp;rsquo;d drop another quick sketch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/check-your-inbox&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/check-your-inbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really, just worked through sampling a few loops into the SP 202, then PITCH and FILTER 1 to taste, and then running it through the SP 303 for some extra flavor as usual. Hype came in for the rescue for a few other sounds just to round it out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - When The Wind Blows</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/09/jamtember2021-track-when-the-wind-blows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 23:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3137</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I know, two tracks in one day&amp;hellip; but I&amp;rsquo;m having too much fun making fake vaporwave tracks with the SPs, and my second power adaptor showed up so I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to hook back up the Boss SP-303 as well. This lead to making this song with both the 202 and 303. Magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/when-the-wind-blows&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/when-the-wind-blows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another picture from Hawaii, but I ran it through a stormy PS Camera filter. This particular picture was from the helicopter ride, so dang fun!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - Exponential Horizon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/09/jamtember2021-track-exponential-horizon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 19:34:05 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3132</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick sketch&amp;hellip; nothing fancy&amp;hellip; but had fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/exponential-horizon&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/exponential-horizon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just four samples&amp;hellip; most of which I ran through the SP-202 and pitched down and used the filter, some chopping, and nothing else too fancy. Honestly, just wanted to put together some 8 bar loops and see where things went from there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You just bought a Boss SP-202, what next?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/07/you-just-bought-a-boss-sp-202-what-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 21:16:45 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3081</guid> 
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;forum&#34;&gt;Forum&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While &lt;a href=&#34;https://gearspace.com&#34;&gt;GearSpace&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.modwiggler.com&#34;&gt;ModWiggler&lt;/a&gt; both have some subforums with a bit of information on the Boss SP-202, the best place to find information is at &lt;a href=&#34;https://sp-forums.com&#34;&gt;sp-forums.com&lt;/a&gt;. There is a specific forum at SP-Forums that is dedicated to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sp-forums.com/viewforum.php?f=2&amp;amp;sid=33900420201c63e79ffab7e8c46fccd3&#34;&gt;Boss SP-202&lt;/a&gt;, and while it is pretty quiet, there is a lot of good information contained, and was a solid source for getting some details for this specific page. You can get access to the forum anonymously, but to post it appears you&amp;rsquo;ll need an invite from somebody on the forums. I don&amp;rsquo;t have an account on sp-forums, so I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to get you an invite :(.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - Sudden Grace</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/07/jamtember2021-track-sudden-grace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 21:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3074</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just knocking something out fairly quickly over lunch for day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/sudden-grace&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/sudden-grace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is from years ago&amp;hellip; Aruba I think? I&amp;rsquo;ll have to look it up and see if I can figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make the track, I did another fake 4 bar loop to turn into a vaporwave track. So quite similar process to the last few days. The big difference here is *way* more automation, filtering, and for the first half of the song I used the Air Halfspeed plugin to make the vaporwave component feel slower. The whole track was going much much slower than I usually go for, so I really just tried to lock in what felt like a leaned way back vibe and go with it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - Breakfast Lunch Dinner</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/03/jamtember2021-track-breakfast-lunch-dinner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 01:40:36 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3042</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I did some of the work yesterday for this track&amp;hellip; just happened to have some extra time to kick it off. Then today&amp;hellip; happened. A lot going on, but I really wanted to get some more going for the track by adding a few more sounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/breakfast-lunch-dinner&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/breakfast-lunch-dinner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is from Hawaii, and I had gotten my wife a coconut to drink. She loves it&amp;hellip; I keep trying to drink coconut water, but frankly it is not for me. I&amp;rsquo;m sure it is healthy, but just not my thing. My wife can drink it for breakfast, lunch, and dinner though!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
