<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Chase-Bliss on NearTao&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/chase-bliss/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chase-Bliss on NearTao&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 17:47:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/chase-bliss/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Waking to Sunshine - Akai MPC X/Live Program</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/12/31/waking-to-sunshine-akai-mpc-x-live-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 17:47:11 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=259</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/waking-to-sunshine.zip&#34;&gt;Waking to Sunshine&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/waking-to-sunshine.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got a relatively small backlog of programs to upload, but it is a backlog none the less. As I said in the previous post, one of my dogs got super sick, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten in the habit of having a lot of posts on standby to cover me when I get busy. Also, I&amp;rsquo;ve played with putting a few Youtube posts together, but I do not really have the proper camera, lighting, and other recording equipment at this time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moody Bass - Akai MPC 1000 Program</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/11/27/moody-bass-akai-mpc-1000-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 23:49:12 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=183</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been getting back into using guitar pedals for external effects processing, and had some fun messing with the Chase Bliss Mood again. This started life as an Ableton Live clean Stratocaster patch that I put together, and played through the Mood. What I played initially sounded like an unaffected guitar, but with the Mood always listening, and using the old blood side&amp;rsquo;s always listening micro granular in tape mode, I came up with this bass sounding loop &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/moody-01.wav&#34;&gt;Moody Bass 01&lt;/a&gt;. This was recorded into my MPC 1000, and I sliced it into a drum kit &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/moody-bass-mpc-1k.zip&#34;&gt;Moody Bass&lt;/a&gt; for the MPC 1000 on JJOS. You can certainly take the initial loop and chop it in a different way, but I decided to just do a relatively clean chop and tightened up the start and end points in the drum kit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chase Bliss Generation Loss First Impressions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/11/05/chase-bliss-generation-loss-first-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 02:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=148</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While I was traveling to Bangalore for work Chase Bliss dropped the Generation Loss, and unfortunately I missed the pre-order window on Reverb. I tried to check it out the next day, but it was already sold out. I spent the next few days wondering if I really needed this device, or it was going to be an effect I should just pass on. I checked out the Knobs &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XPONrJAyqfc&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; as well as Andy Othling&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=O2g-xM7Oj4k&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; and I have to say, they both intrigued me. So I setup a feed on Reverb to keep me apprised of whenever Generation Loss might start showing up on the scalper market on Reverb and eBay.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
