<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Reason-Studio on NearTao&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/reason-studio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reason-Studio on NearTao&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 02:10:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/reason-studio/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Emotional Adjustment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/27/jamcember-emotional-adjustment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 02:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1511</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is not what I had intended to create&amp;hellip; but that seems to be par for the course for trying to do a track a day :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/emotional-adjustment&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/emotional-adjustment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intent for this track was to put some content together in Reason and then make some create patterns that changed chord structures throughout the song. Started off good, made a bunch of chords, arpeggios, and bass lines to flow in a Bb Minor&amp;hellip; chord progression of I-VII-v-ii&amp;hellip; resulting in Bbmb7, AbM7, Fm/Ab, Cmb7&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - New Found Glory</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/21/jamcember-new-found-glory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 16:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1465</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is Monday the 21st, and that means it is time for the 21st track!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/new-found-glory&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/new-found-glory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is from my trip to Athens Greece with some filters on it. Nothing fancy, but the statue was incredible to see in person. It&amp;rsquo;s made out of plexiglass or glass and stacked up to look like a person. We walked by the statue quite a bit for our family trip, and would definitely go there again!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Tea In The Dark</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/20/jamcember-tea-in-the-dark/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 23:58:28 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1455</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day twenty&amp;hellip; I can feel that the end of jamcember is nearing :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/tea-in-the-dark&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/tea-in-the-dark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I went back to the now &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo; standard of making some loops in Reason Studio, working on some sound design to get some interesting sounds, and then bouncing the loops out to be chopped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few things I tried to switch it up. First, I made four bar loops, but extended them out to eight bars, because I wanted the ambience to flow through to the start of the first bar, instead of hearing the loop in the first bar kind of catch up. Something sounds a bit off&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s possible that I have an LFO that is not sync&amp;rsquo;d to the track, or maybe my copy/paste of notes was bad. I tried it&amp;hellip; and while it didn&amp;rsquo;t work quite how I wanted, well&amp;hellip; it still produced results.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - The Long Way</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/18/jamcember-the-long-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 15:40:58 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1437</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Eighteen days, it&amp;rsquo;s been eighteen days, dropping a beat every day, so many ways&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/the-long-way&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/the-long-way&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track&amp;hellip; I am still making loops in Reason Studio and looping them&amp;hellip; this might be the last one for the month&amp;hellip; not because I don&amp;rsquo;t like the results, but just so I can experiment with some other track making techniques&amp;hellip; or who knows&amp;hellip; go back to finishing off some older tracks. The next few days we shall see.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Where Will I Find You</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/17/jamcember-where-will-i-find-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 01:10:09 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1430</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day&amp;hellip; Seventeen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/where-will-i-find-you&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/where-will-i-find-you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just like this track&amp;hellip; guess I have nothing else to say about it today :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay&amp;hellip; I was being lazy yesterday&amp;hellip; cleaning up after the blizzard kind of got to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this track I really decided to pair down the frantic energy and focus a bit more on natural sounding instruments with some air, space, and environment to them. As I said yesterday, I am quite happy about how it came out, though mixing was a bit of a pain due to how different the levels were on all of the tracks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Yeeting It</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/16/jamcember-yeeting-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 17:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1421</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sixteen days feels like more time making a track a day than it really is :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/yeeting-it&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/yeeting-it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture comes courtesy of my wife&amp;rsquo;s hand while we were visiting in Bangalore last year and she asked to get some Henna artwork done on her hand. Had a great time out there and would love to go back. The food was incredible!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the track, probably approaching the last days during this month of pulling content off of Reason Studio daily and then chopping up loops for inspiration, so I&amp;rsquo;ll be looking around for another sound source or two for the month just to push myself in other directions. I&amp;rsquo;ve been itching to do some sound recording, and who knows, maybe I go industrial?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Why Are You Here</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/15/jamcember-why-are-you-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 12:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1415</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fifteen fifteen fifteen fifteen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/why-are-you-here&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/why-are-you-here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still having a blast making loops in Reason and exporting it out to the MPC for chopping up. This track had a lot going on with it, and I had fun making the initial four bars&amp;hellip; but once I got started tracking it out into a song things really went sideways. The transitions just didn&amp;rsquo;t work and the track started to fall apart. I think it was more a case of a few different sounds just not supporting each other very well and while I was having fun making the four bar loop it wasn&amp;rsquo;t obvious, but when trying to put transitions together it became a bit jarring.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Welcome Tangerine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/14/jamcember-welcome-tangerine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 22:53:43 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1408</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Has it already been fourteen tracks?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/welcome-tangerine&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/welcome-tangerine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track needed some mixing love, I tried to nail it, but I still think the saw synth is a bit intense. Perhaps this is what the track needed? I&amp;rsquo;m not sure. After this many tracks can I really be sure of anything?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I am sure that all of the content was yet again produced in Reason Studio, and I ran it through the Yorgos Arabatzsis Mastering. I&amp;rsquo;m getting a bit more of a handle with both making loops in Reason Studio 11, and working with YAM to get the sounds I am looking for, and pushing the sounds I don&amp;rsquo;t like back.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Faerie Dust</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/13/jamcember-faerie-dust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 14:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1401</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The thirteen day is upon us, and it is good&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/faerie-dust&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/faerie-dust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another track that I spent some time putting together four bar loops in Reason Studio 11 in order to get some content that I could chop up and mangle in the MPC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything too special about the chops, but the bass line was played out a bit wonky to start, and I just kind of went with it. The first two bars are super simple, and then the last two bars get a lot more complex. From there, I built a lot of the melody and chords around it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Hello Sputnik/Goodbye Sputnik</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/12/jamcember-hello-sputnik-goodbye-sputnik/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 15:09:27 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1391</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the twelfth day, there was two&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/hello-sputnik&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/hello-sputnik&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/goodbye-sputnik&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/goodbye-sputnik&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track was a ton of fun to put together. I wanted to change my perspective on making tracks this month, and decided to focus on chopping up samples, but 100% making my own content. So this project started as a deep dive into Reason Studio 11 to really really really get into some sound design. I knew I wanted to go glitchy and spacey, and I think I pretty well delivered on those themes in this track. So all drum patterns, loops, everything were initially created in a 30 minute session in Reason, and then I bounced and exported six tracks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Waves H-Comp Hybrid Compressor is FREE right now and on sale through August 30th</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/08/24/waves-h-comp-hybrid-compressor-is-free-right-now-and-on-sale-through-august-30th/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 15:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=912</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I know I haven&amp;rsquo;t usually posted plugins or anything&amp;hellip; and maybe I should&amp;hellip; but sometimes a deal is a deal. Just happened to see this when logging into the Propellerheads site and stumbled upon the shop to see that the Waves H-Comp plugin is currently free at  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reasonstudios.com/shop/&#34;&gt;https://www.reasonstudios.com/shop/&lt;/a&gt; on sale for $49 through August 30th&amp;hellip; and with promo code FREECOMP it is free. Just grabbed it yesterday. I still need to install it and check it out, but hard to pass up a free plugin, especially when it is usually going for $200.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
