<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Eurorack on NearTao&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/eurorack/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Eurorack on NearTao&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:06:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/eurorack/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Couple of SP-404 mk2 tracks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/12/13/couple-of-sp-404-mk2-tracks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:06:19 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3602</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Still having fun with the mk2! I find it to occupy a nice space between my other gear, it&amp;rsquo;s not as powerful as the MPC Live as a sampler or for creating patterns, but there&amp;rsquo;s also something refreshing about being limited. Also, the product line has been quite focussed on resampling in the past, and the 404 mk2 really isn&amp;rsquo;t different from that regard. To get the most out of it you&amp;rsquo;re encouraged to sample from your line/instrument/mic inputs and use fx to sculpt a sound from there. Yeah yeah&amp;hellip; super natural for people who have been there, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been seeing some people saying they are not into resampling&amp;hellip; and what the SP to be something it probably never will be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting the Tape Grain Glitch case back into working order... plus Track - Sounds From the Universe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/11/30/getting-the-tape-grain-glitch-case-back-into-working-order-plus-track-sounds-from-the-universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 22:28:55 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3591</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More or less took a couple week musical break. Two things happened. First, I wanted to do some more case modifications to my make noise case… and having to take it apart, drill and Dremel… it was a several day investment of time for getting it all squared away, measure everything to get it to fit, get it back together… and just hope that I haven&amp;rsquo;t overloaded the power supply!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - Looking For A Solution</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/11/15/track-looking-for-a-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 16:17:07 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3557</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Felt good putting this together! :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/F9XIBjI1QNY&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/F9XIBjI1QNY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - Isolation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/11/13/track-isolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 02:05:39 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3551</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not sure why, but this feels like it is in the space of the &amp;lsquo;peak sound&amp;rsquo; I&amp;rsquo;ve been working towards with this setup. Still a bit noisy and still a bit awkward to control sometimes, but hands on, a bit glitchy, and something that can sustain momentum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/t1mUOeepWNw&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/t1mUOeepWNw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The track started the day as something happier, but as it wore on, I just kind of went into my own space of wishing, longing, dreaming, but all at a distance with some strange energy. Not the track I had set off to put together but it might be the track I needed to put together right now. I do like this, and hope that others get something out of it too, but I guess I just had poured a lot more self reflective vibes here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MPC Forums Beat Battle #321 - How You Flop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/11/13/mpc-forums-beat-battle-321-how-you-flop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 14:09:29 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3546</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First, shout out to MPC Forums, and check out the Beat Battle #321 thread if you want to see what others are up to at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mpc-forums.com/viewtopic.php?f=40&amp;amp;t=212572&#34;&gt;https://www.mpc-forums.com/viewtopic.php?f=40&amp;amp;t=212572&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/CEdn4CfaI6A&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/CEdn4CfaI6A&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess this track was about 90 minutes to put together? A lot of the time was spent chopping, and then finding different lines. I gave a stab at an initial 8 bar sequence and figured it was okay enough. I know I normally go at this as one long sequence, but I really want the sound to change over the course of the track, so although each 8 bar sequence could more or less stand on it&amp;rsquo;s own, I felt it would be fun to make a few different once and then use song mode (for once) to chain them together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Music Studio Audio Setup - Zoom H6 Issues and How I Addressed Them</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/11/09/music-studio-audio-setup-zoom-h6-issues-and-how-i-addressed-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 13:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3535</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on trying to figure out where I am having issues with my audio setup, to try and get a hotter signal in my video recordings. So I drew up a rough sketch to see if I could get some notes on what the issue might be and go from there&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/audio-setup-sketch.jpg?w=1024&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The long component with the knobs/buttons on it that is unlabelled is the Behringer RX1602 that I picked up&amp;hellip; I just forgot to label it apparently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - Learning to Exhale</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/11/08/track-learning-to-exhale/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3528</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Honestly, this was my excuse to play with the Strymon Starlight and not make a beat&amp;hellip; I still have time for a beat though :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/8L9Kz-b2efY&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/8L9Kz-b2efY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the patch is *relatively* simple&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s mostly 0chd LFOs running around to just give some movement to the patch, and a DPO running into an RxMx/Optimix so I can ping it, then into a Magneto for some delay, and then into the Starlight for the final pad/wash effect that comes in and goes out. There is a Marbles that is clocked by a Tempi, and the output of the Marbles is being quantized by Harmonaig to generate the pitch on the DPO. The RxMx has the LFOs coming into it to move which oscillator and how much width is being selected. Not much beyond that going on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strymon Starlight Has Arrived</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/11/08/strymon-starlight-has-arrived/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 20:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3522</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well that was quick, I think I ordered it on Thursday last week, and it showed up today. Just recorded off a few videos checking it out and seeing what it is or is not about. So far, seems like an interesting sound sculpting reverb kind of instrument. I look forward to digging deeper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/3zcQbaH4cRQ&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/3zcQbaH4cRQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/kABOD0Vg7l8&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/kABOD0Vg7l8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - What Feels Right</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/11/07/track-what-feels-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 20:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3519</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just trying out vocals in a track again&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/8UyPFsyFz-8&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/8UyPFsyFz-8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - Starlight By The Beach</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/11/06/track-starlight-by-the-beach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 18:54:02 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3512</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I did a thing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/3P5SMy9Ul-w&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/3P5SMy9Ul-w&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well the track didn&amp;rsquo;t use the eurorack for much, but I did a bit of processing through it before recording a bunch of audio into the SPs, then chopping that content up on the MPC to actually play it. Given all the noise it became a bit of a hassle to prepare all of the samples on the MPC because it just couldn&amp;rsquo;t find the start/end with threshold very well, but it felt like it was worth the effort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracks - Dissonance in Heaven &amp;amp; Slow Day Go Day</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/11/05/tracks-dissonance-in-heaven-slow-day-go-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 02:12:31 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3508</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Managed to get enough time today to get a couple more tracks together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/0cM2vs5v-QU&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/0cM2vs5v-QU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/GIYdhjnNA0s&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/GIYdhjnNA0s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - Influence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/11/04/track-influence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 16:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3504</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a somewhat simple lunch break track&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/OvOWOcHukWI&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/OvOWOcHukWI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track was so many takes to get to this somewhat still janky state. At least fifteen, and the worst is that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t setup the input/recorder properly to actually capture any takes. I had a good one or two in there, and then realized I was recording off of the microphone and not off of the Zoom H6 inputs. Doh!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was also fighting with some CV outputs from the MPC to gates into the Pam&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; because&amp;hellip; and I&amp;rsquo;m rolling my eyes at myself, I had not recorded off the triggers at all. So it was constantly loosing sync, the resets were doing what I wanted, but well&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m sure you can get the idea. I really need to create a template for my setup so that I don&amp;rsquo;t have to keep remembering all this twiddly bits that can cause me a problem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - Looking At The Edge of the World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/11/03/track-looking-at-the-edge-of-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 23:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3501</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And another one&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/NaDqpkEFIec&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/NaDqpkEFIec&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - A City At Peace</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/11/02/track-a-city-at-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3487</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Had a long day, day off for my daughter, and some arguments. She&amp;rsquo;s not happy that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t pay for her to eat at Starbucks, and I&amp;rsquo;m not happy to be treated as a piggy bank. So put this together to just decompress and relax a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/&lt;/a&gt;_l0eLSWeR4g&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So just used the same setup/patch in the eurorack as yesterday, but I did leave the guitar track (on accident) going straight to the outputs. Honestly, it was probably the right choice, but well&amp;hellip; it is what it is :D&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MPC Forums Beat Battle #320 - Nectar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/11/02/mpc-forums-beat-battle-320-nectar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:29:28 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3483</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just dropping this here&amp;hellip; had fun&amp;hellip; but a super quick one&amp;hellip; maybe 30 minutes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/9kxWr0k9Pog&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/9kxWr0k9Pog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - The Streets Watch Back</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/11/01/track-the-streets-watch-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 23:41:35 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3478</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Been trying to work out some issues, and make tracks louder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/vDzTg5h65RI&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/vDzTg5h65RI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track I tried to push into using the morphagene for a bit of ambient noise to bring in and out to an okay effect. Probably something that is better to automate with an envelope so have it swell in over time, but that&amp;rsquo;ll mean considering a rewatching of how everything is setup, which I suppose I am due for anyways, since over the last month I have had some grumbles about how some of the gates, attenuators, and other things have been configured. I can effectively get 4 discrete signal paths out to the Befaco STMix, and so far I&amp;rsquo;ve tried applying a path like MPC Live -&amp;gt; Morphagene -&amp;gt; Sqwak Dirty -&amp;gt; Mimeophon -&amp;gt; Data Bender -&amp;gt; STMix, and while this works, it has left Beads out, which I&amp;rsquo;ve then added in by peeling off the signal from Sqwak Dirty -&amp;gt; Beads -&amp;gt; STMix. There is some value in having two discrete paths for the same voice, but I think I need to consider what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to get, and which types of sounds or effects make the most sense.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #31 - Project Morpheus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/31/beatober2021-31-project-morpheus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 22:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3472</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Based on feedback, tried to make this track much louder, and maybe got a little too carried away. Now I think it has pushed into a bit too crunchy and toasty territory. I probably should not have been driving the STMix so hard :/.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bass line is only 2 bars long and absolutely needs some variations to move it around, or something to tie off every 4 or 8 bars… just something different. Ah well, this was fun and definitely deserves a second try at thinking about how to drive all the content through the eurorack anyways, and might be something to expand on some more to build out into a set.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober #30.1 - We Must Go Deeper &amp;amp; #30.2 - A Valuable Lesson</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/30/beatober-30-1-we-must-go-deeper-30-2-a-valuable-lesson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 00:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3493</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A twofer day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/vcqiASOpMNk&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/vcqiASOpMNk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/CMi97Ejvyn8&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/CMi97Ejvyn8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #29 - Air Pollution</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/29/beatober2021-29-air-pollution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 17:35:44 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3469</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A day track this time&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/HbXDBwXj53k&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/HbXDBwXj53k&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded off some samples onto the SP-202, slowed them down, and tried to get a bit of the LoFi 1 crunch to get a bit into the Vaporwave space, but this is definitely not 80&amp;rsquo;s inspired or reminiscent… so I guess it is something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resampled the loops back into the MPC so I could line them up better and get everything into sync, then added drums. There&amp;rsquo;s a touch of Mimeophon on the instruments, and the Instruments/Bass/Drums are getting some Data Bender treatment. I suspect the Bass being so dang low is a mixing problem… especially since I didn&amp;rsquo;t take the time to mix the track. Oops… will save it off and see if it is a track to come back to in the future to refine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #28 - When the Mirror Looks Back</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/28/beatober2021-28-when-the-mirror-looks-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 22:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3462</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Scurried off and used loop mode to record me noodling around on the Triton Studio until I found something that felt decent. I ended up unplugging a bunch of patch cables because there was some CV in place that was messing with me, so ended up with about 10 different but similar recordings, but had a lot of accidental drops and other problems. Was trying to hit something a bit more fun and wacky for today&amp;hellip; and I guess I got there&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #27.1 - Internet Etiquette &amp;amp; #27.2 - Everyday Carry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/27/beatober2021-27-internet-etiquette/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 22:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3457</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just trying to see how much I could squeeze a track down&amp;hellip; with four tracks and pushing the Mimeophon and Data Bender harder than I usually do&amp;hellip; got some interesting results for sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/80IZwgB8wvw&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/80IZwgB8wvw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly excited by what came out for the first track so decided to give it another try and see what I could do with the 20 minutes before I have to go pick up my daughter&amp;hellip; like this a bit more :D&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #26 - Trance With Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/26/beatober2021-26-trance-with-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 21:24:06 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3454</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not feeling this one so much&amp;hellip; but I tried&amp;hellip; so there&amp;rsquo;s that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/aEj-0QGcDgY&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/aEj-0QGcDgY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #25.1 - God In the Code &amp;amp; #25.2 - Behind The Curtain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/25/beatober2021-25-1-god-in-the-code-25-2-behind-the-curtain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3450</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Got around to two tracks today&amp;hellip; guess we&amp;rsquo;ve got a double feature woohoo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/glYhE2bn6oo&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/glYhE2bn6oo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/dEHasgqAjiY&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/dEHasgqAjiY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #24 - These Lonely Streets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/24/beatober2021-24-these-lonely-streets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 23:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3445</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another day and not as much time to dedicate to the track as I&amp;rsquo;d like&amp;hellip; still mostly happy with how it came out though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/24Y1qDwL7X4&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/24Y1qDwL7X4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More of a laid back/chill track for today. With of course, buffers galore, glitch effects, etc&amp;hellip; this required over a dozen practice runs because I was trying to get a bit more movement and hands on with the track, but was causing some incredibly disorienting pitch shifts and swells. The practice helped a lot though, and I think I ended up making a lot less mistakes in this track than some of the previous ones I&amp;rsquo;ve done.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #23 - Ghost Mirage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/23/beatober2021-23-ghost-mirage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 19:52:48 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3440</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just something a little jazzy, a little funky&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/hY7RDyr6lPA&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/hY7RDyr6lPA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The track started out life back in August at my sister&amp;rsquo;s house while visiting, and was a subset of a jam session that I did with my brother in law. Sadly, no guitar or other instrument takes were had, so I had to add in some electric piano, pads, and bells to fill the track out a bit, and give it a bit of a jazzier feel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #22 - Bitter Sweet Symphony</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/22/beatober2021-22-bitter-sweet-symphony/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:13:35 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3436</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was initially just testing out my reconfigured setup&amp;hellip; but figured I&amp;rsquo;d run with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/L3tj2vKJC&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/L3tj2vKJC&lt;/a&gt;_c&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I&amp;rsquo;m abandoning the configuration I am working on for getting multiple tracks together, just that I was getting some more concepts together :D Nothing technically I haven&amp;rsquo;t done before, but this is all tracks that I played out, tweaked notes, velocity and all that fun stuff, to try and get a sound I was going for. Hopefully the levels are working better&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #21 - Mr. Big</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/21/beatober2021-21-mr-big/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 22:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3429</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yeah! Finally getting a vision of some sounds/ideas to put together into a big ol&amp;rsquo; mix and mash of tracks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/G7u&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/G7u&lt;/a&gt;_6dGFtv4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been so focussed on trying to just get a track done, or only having a half hour that I kind of just forgot about my original goal of putting a set of tracks together. I certainly played around with it a lot, a month or two ago, but I have been more focussing on just doing a track a day for the last couple of months that it passed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #20 - Witching Hour</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/20/beatober2021-20-witching-hour/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 23:12:43 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3425</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/MEcwa9kV-P8&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/MEcwa9kV-P8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I got myself some credits on NeuralBlender&amp;hellip; and actually started buying some art&amp;hellip; whaaaaat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decided to spend some time today trying to think about a way to use the Morphagene as a sample player of some sort&amp;hellip; and got a couple samples going&amp;hellip; didn&amp;rsquo;t go for anything crazy or off the rails&amp;hellip; but they both got some more action today than usual&amp;hellip; so instead of just using them as a passthrough for the MPC outputs, they got some real sounds going&amp;hellip; haha.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #19 - A Night With Friends</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/19/beatober2021-19-a-night-with-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3416</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well&amp;hellip; here it is for today&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/wcvIsJlfGCI&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/wcvIsJlfGCI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The track gave me some problems. Mostly Total Recall&amp;hellip; I just realized that it triggers or rather changes parameters on the down event of a clock or gate&amp;hellip; and Pam&amp;rsquo;s was sending a gate for 50% of a beat, meaning that the change was happening on 1.3 instead of 1.1 of a bar. Doh! This was giving me all kinds of problems, and I&amp;rsquo;ll need to rethink how I&amp;rsquo;m using Total Recall. The quick fix was to change the gate width from 50% down to 1%, but I still feel like this leaves some margin for error. Back to the drawing board a bit for how I&amp;rsquo;m using Total recall. Surprisingly, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t even noticed this until today&amp;hellip; I guess the more ambient sounds just weren&amp;rsquo;t making me notice it so much, but the arp today&amp;hellip; woah boy&amp;hellip; was it messing with my timing&amp;hellip; took a few tries before I got to the &amp;ldquo;is it me, or is it you&amp;rdquo; thought&amp;hellip; I guess at least it wasn&amp;rsquo;t me this time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #18 - Late Night Drifters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/18/beatober2021-18-late-night-drifters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:52:42 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3408</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yah&amp;hellip; sometimes we just need to simplify!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/ldJchNxMaWQ&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/ldJchNxMaWQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could&amp;rsquo;ve made this into a longer track, but yeah&amp;hellip; I think keeping it short and simple definitely kept it moving and interesting. At least I feel like I got more out of it than I would have otherwise trying to layer a ton of sounds in and then having a big mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effectively I made the four tracks on the MPC to begin with, and spent the time making sure I was happy with the eight bars first, pretty similar to what I did yesterday. From there I just starting assigning tracks to different outputs on the MPC, and then driving them through different effects in eurorack, and then, as usual, I chased it with the SP 202 and SP 303 at the tail end to just add the dust, grit, and grunge for the song.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #17 - Looking for Redemption</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/17/beatober2021-17-looking-for-redemption/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 23:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3403</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This track was fun, but I also had a lot more time today to be picky with sound selection, make some various sections, and then add in eurorack for some extra spice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/frcc&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/frcc&lt;/a&gt;_5iL7yo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track started from the much cleaner track recorded on soundcloud that I did pretty much everything on the MPC, and then just ran it through and end chain of SP-202 and SP-303. I actually made a few other tracks that didn&amp;rsquo;t make the cut because they just clashed a bit too much with everything going on here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #16 - Simple Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/16/beatober2021-16-simple-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 14:08:12 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3394</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Decided to keep it simple today&amp;hellip; really simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/3bMvOTQSWq8&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/3bMvOTQSWq8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What all is going on? The picture comes from Neural Blender again&amp;hellip; still having fun with this, I still need to buy some credits and go to town here. Even if the images are not necessarily directly useful, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely got some inspiring and striking looks to a lot of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well&amp;hellip; the spacey ambient sound was some piano riffs I loaded up into the Morphagene, which was a pain because the piano audio was quite dynamic for its&amp;rsquo; range, going from really quiet -20db/-30db area to 0db. Sending it from the 3/4 outputs on the MPC (which I am sure are outputting at either 0db or possibly +4db, need to read the manual again) meant that until I dropped the track down to -9db it was just getting somewhat pleasing, but mostly awful noise on the high end. Certainly I could have used a LPF to clean it up, but honestly I wanted a cleaner sound here. Once I had the audio recorded, I then manipulated the gene size until I had something that seemed relatively musical and seemed like a nice enough progression. I then clocked the Morphagene from Pamela&amp;rsquo;s New Workout so that it would play relatively at a speed with the track. From here I used the Mimetic Digitalis to change the cutoff on the Sqwak Dirty LPF to have the sound change over time while the track played.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #15 - Funk Your Style</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/15/beatober2021-15-funk-your-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 01:16:54 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3389</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay&amp;hellip; today felt pretty good&amp;hellip; but did like&amp;hellip; five&amp;hellip; maybe six takes&amp;hellip; was getting a bit of a jam going and then would make a mistake&amp;hellip; this take came together pretty well though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/JGcR613&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/JGcR613&lt;/a&gt;_21U&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my pretty traditional setup I&amp;rsquo;ve been going for lately, but with the SP 202 and SP 303 added to the end of the chain&amp;hellip; oh and I&amp;rsquo;ve added in the Zoom H6 at the end of chain to function a bit as a mixer/audio router&amp;hellip; the RCA to 1/4&amp;quot; adaptors are what is causing me the biggest headache in this setup&amp;hellip; but it is kind of nice having the 202 do LPF duties at the end of the chain, and then the Vinyl FX from the 303 to do some compression and wow/flutter duties&amp;hellip; and a hint of vinyl noise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #10 - Lower Form of Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/10/beatober2021-10-lower-form-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 23:47:09 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3362</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay&amp;hellip; still tired, but at least off my butt to do some music today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/Epye6mwfQiQ&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/Epye6mwfQiQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/beatober2021-10-lower-form-of-life?si=0e5b7175bf7e46f983f267b9d685bfb2&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/beatober2021-10-lower-form-of-life?si=0e5b7175bf7e46f983f267b9d685bfb2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still hitting a problem recording audio&amp;hellip; but I think it is me&amp;hellip; as the two tracks don&amp;rsquo;t seem to be the same. I recorded several takes, but somehow the last recording didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to match between the YouTube video and the soundcloud audio&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m doing something wrong. Probably too tired to do everything correctly&amp;hellip; doh!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #07 - Stand Up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/07/beatober2021-07-stand-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:23:57 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3351</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So uhm&amp;hellip; apparently I forgot how to operate my gear&amp;hellip; clearly what happens when I take a break for a single day and use the pocket operators&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/T7jdc69J9G8&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/T7jdc69J9G8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/Y9qm7r8DNZc&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/Y9qm7r8DNZc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this track I disconnected the entire hot mess from a couple days ago&amp;hellip; and just really went to focus on basics. I decided I wanted to try recording in a few chords into the Morphagene and then using Pam&amp;rsquo;s New Workout on a random LFO to send a change to which splice was selected&amp;hellip; and it works pretty nicely except for one problem. The Morphagene doesn&amp;rsquo;t switch to the next sound until partway through playing&amp;hellip; so either I need to work out clocking issues, or change config.txt settings or&amp;hellip; something. It works fine for this track more or less, but required some playing around and bumbling around to get some rhythm that sounded like it could work with it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #05 - Round the Bend</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/05/beatober2021-04-round-the-bend/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:10:43 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3338</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yeah&amp;hellip; not really sure what to make of this&amp;hellip; other than way too many patch cables&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s a serious mess. I don&amp;rsquo;t really know what I have done any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/uHuwoBYhsns&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/uHuwoBYhsns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/beatober2021-05-round-the-bend?si=febb14d725bb4c58952327fa889ade2e&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/beatober2021-05-round-the-bend?si=febb14d725bb4c58952327fa889ade2e&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image is just my work pc&amp;hellip; with a mysterious rocket flying into it? I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;hellip; I hardly could muster the energy to pull this together. Guess it&amp;rsquo;s just one of those brained out lame tracks&amp;hellip; that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t really figure out what to do with it&amp;hellip; and everything I did made it worse. Good thing it was maybe 20 minutes of time invested, instead of a lot of work that would make me sad.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 Jam #04 - Jimmy Jam</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/04/beatober2021-jam-04-jimmy-jam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 19:52:26 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3329</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We all gotta struggle&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/6g9KiCwxqs0&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/6g9KiCwxqs0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/beatober2021-jam-04-jimmy-jam&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/beatober2021-jam-04-jimmy-jam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright putting this track together was a pain&amp;hellip; I had too many different elements going on, and out of the *nine* recording attempts&amp;hellip; only one was halfway decent. My biggest problem is that about a third of what I put together just didn&amp;rsquo;t mesh with the other parts of the track. I&amp;rsquo;d keep recording and trying to decide which way to go with it, but it just wasn&amp;rsquo;t happening. The synth lines didn&amp;rsquo;t gel, the Lofi arps didn&amp;rsquo;t gel, it just didn&amp;rsquo;t want to come together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 Jam #03 - Rizzo Rizzo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/03/beatober2021-jam-03-rizzo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 23:39:50 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3322</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dance?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/5ePsvtqa&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/5ePsvtqa&lt;/a&gt;_fo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/beatober2021-jam-03-rizzo&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/beatober2021-jam-03-rizzo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this track I built it up off of 16 clips from an expansion, made sure to use each one&amp;hellip; and then did a track explode on the MPC, set the pads 1-8 to output to 5/6 (and thus on the bottom chain of FX of the eurorack), and set pads 9-16 to output to 3/4 (the top chain of FX of the eurorack).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mostly me just using track mutes from here, and then turning knobs on the eurorack to jam out, cut up, glitch, and otherwise morph and destroy the various elements of the track that are playing. A few places feel like they didn&amp;rsquo;t quite work, but hey&amp;hellip; gotta try right?!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #01 - Up Close</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/01/beatober2021-01-up-close/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 21:11:47 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3306</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alright, it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Beatober&lt;/em&gt; and time to try and focus a bit more on beats again. Just trying to kick the tires on a stringing a single song together between the Eurorack and Akai MPC Live mk2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/uy&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/uy&lt;/a&gt;_K090EF_g&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/beatober2021-01-up-close?si=a78bc5bed4a44a29b9bb9b39fe640180&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/beatober2021-01-up-close?si=a78bc5bed4a44a29b9bb9b39fe640180&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is just from my dog being sleepy on the chair beside me. Felt like a good chill out song and she&amp;rsquo;s not chilling out much more than this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as putting this all together&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve been slowly building out the rack patch, and I setup the Akai MPC outputs 3/4 as the drums going through the top of the rack, and outputs 5/6 for the piano and bass on the bottom of the rack. This is then all going into the ST Mix for mixing a somewhat clean signal together with a copied and glitched out signal. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of knobs to be trying to keep in mind while also muting and unmuting parts, so I probably just need to work out my process a bit more consciously to keep it all in my head.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Jam Session - Slick Fool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/30/jamtember2021-jam-session-slick-fool/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 23:31:30 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3301</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last track/jam for the month&amp;hellip; going to see what I can put together for beatober next :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/in3OUNSvj6U&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/in3OUNSvj6U&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time messing around for the month, and wanted to fix up a few things on my patching. For this, I ended up just doing two different track ideas and routing one track through 3/4 of the MPC, and the second track through 5/6 of the MPC. This then went into both the Morphagenes, mostly because it was already hooked up this way. In fact, I tried to mostly use what I&amp;rsquo;ve been building up for a patch over the last two days, but I did straighten out my mixer to have the ST Mix have 1) Track 1 FX chain A 2) Track 1 FX chain B 3) Track 2 FX chain A 4) Track 2 FX chain B. This helped me keep some sanity for which ST Mix knobs were controlling which parts of the sound.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - Sunny Side Up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/29/jamtember2021-track-sunny-side-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:04:26 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3290</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some house music&amp;hellip; recorded some of the jam off to the Wav Recorder&amp;hellip; and some of it made it to the YouTube video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/sunny-side-up&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/sunny-side-up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is just a quick doodle that I did on my iPad. Just done in ProCreate&amp;hellip;. just now&amp;hellip; while thinking about what to do with this track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the YouTube video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JTZKFYO1Bwg?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So a few notes here&amp;hellip; I am routing all of my output on the MPC out either 3/4 or 5/6, and into the Eurorack, and then processing everything through a couple different chains including Morphagene, Mimeophon, Beads, Sqwk Dirty, and Data Bender, and then going out to the ST Mix.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - One Hit Striker</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/28/jamtember2021-track-one-hit-striker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 16:04:03 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3280</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to use some of the patching done yesterday for the ambient tracks to make some DnB&amp;hellip; woohoo!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Practice Session first&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s plenty of mistakes, offbeat content, and a few places that some of the sounds got a bit too wild&amp;hellip; oops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/pg0K1Gk5toI&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/pg0K1Gk5toI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here I did a few more takes and settled on the following take as the &amp;lsquo;final&amp;rsquo; for this track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/mgsyQkY1LUk&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/mgsyQkY1LUk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who want a higher quality version of the audio for this final (probably) take you can get it at SoundCloud from below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - Floating Above</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/27/jamtember2021-track-floating-above/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3274</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another track with the Euro&amp;hellip; and another late night jam session&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/UIBf3vv6FqM&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/UIBf3vv6FqM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Didn&amp;rsquo;t play the patch much, and heck it wasn&amp;rsquo;t even terribly complicated. Mostly just two different sounds loaded into the Morphagenes, one piano loop that I ran through the Beads which gave a kind of organ type of sound, and the other was some bell kind of sound that I ran through the Mimeophon that is making that more low end drone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - Passed the Sunrise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/27/jamtember2021-track-passed-the-sunrise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 16:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3267</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a straight up Eurorack event today&amp;hellip; nothing else&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/Ip&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/Ip&lt;/a&gt;_SaybZesY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above is the recording that I did on the eurorack, from just a couple of samples in both the Morphagenes and stretched to their limits. There is some digital artifacting or clipping sounds, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest, it is hard to tell if it is coming from something in the chain specifically I am doing wrong, or just a side effect of the Data Bender doing it&amp;rsquo;s thing and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t paying attention to what I had it doing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - Green Light</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/26/jamtember2021-track-green-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:34:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3257</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just messing around way more today than I have all month&amp;hellip; but this is for better or worse lol :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the Jam Session&amp;hellip; just loaded up a kit and figured I&amp;rsquo;d mess around for 10-15 minutes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/gOaEgEJVQDg&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/gOaEgEJVQDg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Near the end I had no idea what I had in the Morphagene buffers, and just kind of went with it. Not really choices I should have made, but whatever&amp;hellip; just messing around.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - Latitude</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/25/jamtember2021-track-latitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 20:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3248</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is two takes&amp;hellip; I recorded some YouTube videos and uploaded to soundcloud as well&amp;hellip; take two is better, but just wanted to show what the heck I was doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/latitude-take-1&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/latitude-take-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/latitude-take-2&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/latitude-take-2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And&amp;hellip; here are the YouTube videos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/Y9hKEfEy244&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/Y9hKEfEy244&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/m9KpYLJNtMU&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/m9KpYLJNtMU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways&amp;hellip; for those who are interested&amp;hellip; finally gettin Beads added to the case and was just messing around with the Beat Slicer mode to see how well it would work by itself and with Data Bender. I&amp;rsquo;m digging it, but feel like I need to get a bit more control over it on the MPC side&amp;hellip; or record some better sequences/patterns into the Eurorack modules (Pams/Tete/Mimetic Digitalis&amp;hellip; whatever)&amp;hellip; or not. Definitely going to keep trying but I feel like this was a bit too much glitch.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Setup The Akai MPC X/One/Live II to Sync With Eurorack</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/07/26/how-to-setup-the-akai-mpc-x-one-live-ii-to-sync-with-eurorack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 20:58:46 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=2950</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just posted a video up on some of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve done over the last few weeks to experiment with getting the new MPC line to talk with Eurorack and get everything in sync. It&amp;rsquo;s nothing to fancy or special, but felt like this might be useful for others who are trying to figure out how to do something similar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qJvdQfDjhzg?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is interest, I&amp;rsquo;ll work on putting another post together to outline the details more fully, but this just seemed like a good place to start.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MPC Forums Beat Battle 315 - Tailgating Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/07/25/mpc-forums-beat-battle-315-tailgating-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 20:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=2954</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been messing around trying to get an Ambient DnB setup working, and ended up thinking the concept might fit well with the MPC Forums Beat Battle 315 this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the two live played recordings that I took.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GD8?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/AZo?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: So I decided to do a third iteration of the track, because all the tapping noises were bugging me. Anyways&amp;hellip; here&amp;rsquo;s revision three.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syncing your MPC Live mk2/X/One to Eurorak Pamela&#39;s New Workout</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/06/03/syncing-your-mpc-live-mk2-x-one-to-eurorak-pamelas-new-workout/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 16:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=2907</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/sfs5zI07JQw&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/sfs5zI07JQw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This video shows how to sync up your MPC Live mk2/X/One over CV gates to a Pamela&amp;rsquo;s New Workout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I&amp;rsquo;m not too worried about the variance in the BPM that shows up at higher levels. I&amp;rsquo;ve monitored the gates being sent over CV and have seen that it is not dropping gates, so over time the average will be correct, even if there is a small variance in the BPM at a specific gate trigger.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NT-Modular-Be Spoke Accordian</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/05/13/nt-modular-be-spoke-accordian/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=2793</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Was kind of hunting around for a bit of an accordion sound, and figured this was close enough to a synthetic sound as I was going to make with the modular case today. It&amp;rsquo;s very similar to the NT-Modular-Wet Lazers key group I put together, just a few patch changes for how the filter operates and which wave table I was using out of the Disting EX Plus Alpha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/nt-modular-be-spoke-accordian.zip&#34;&gt;nt-modular-be-spoke-accordian&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/nt-modular-be-spoke-accordian.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NT-Modular-Wet Lazers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/05/13/nt-modular-wet-lazers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 23:29:05 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=2788</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay&amp;hellip; queue up the kinda cheesy FX sounds&amp;hellip; this is mostly just the Disting EX routed through Squawk Dirty To Me for filtering. Honestly it&amp;rsquo;s not *that* special, but I did do a little bit of LFO routing into a VCA into the resonance CV control to get that slight vibration sound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/nt-modular-wet-lazers.zip&#34;&gt;nt-modular-wet-lazers&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/nt-modular-wet-lazers.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did try briefly to see if it was quick to use velocity CV out from the MPC, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t get it working with just a few knob twiddles, so frankly&amp;hellip; I failed at it. Going to need a bit more reading of the manual again to see how to get it going.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NT-Modular-Last Breath</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/05/11/nt-modular-last-breath/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 14:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=2781</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a super simple patch I put together on the modular, simple because this smaller case only has a handful of modules in it. While it isn&amp;rsquo;t complete yet, I wanted to test out and see how well it did or did not work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/nt-modular-last-breath.zip&#34;&gt;NT-Modular-Last Breath&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/nt-modular-last-breath.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sound is basically an oscillator running on the Disting EX in dual mode, so that I could also get an envelope generator, because I don&amp;rsquo;t have that in this case at the moment. The oscillator is fed into the VCA, which is modulated by an LFO running positive on the Left channel, and running negative on the Right channel, this creates a kind of panning tremolo effect. I think routed that audio output into another pair of VCAs so that I could control the volume by the envelope. From there, the audio is running into a stereo filter to augment the sound a bit and give it some resonance to adjust the sound a bit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Akai MPC Live/X/One Channel Level 0db Digital Distortion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/19/akai-mpc-live-x-one-channel-level-0db-digital-distortion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 20:25:02 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1807</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over at MPC Forums &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mpc-forums.com/memberlist.php?mode=viewprofile&amp;amp;u=105910&#34;&gt;Monstre Sensible&lt;/a&gt; kicked off a thread &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mpc-forums.com/viewtopic.php?f=48&amp;amp;t=209558&#34;&gt;Export Song&lt;/a&gt;. A key question asked what happens to audio over the 0db mark, and if this could be considered headroom. I was ready with the &amp;ldquo;here is the manual page&amp;rdquo; to describe the behavior, but Akai didn&amp;rsquo;t actually document what happens in the manual. So&amp;hellip; time to get some scientific experiments started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response I setup a little test, using a normalized single cycle loop, and hooked it up to my Eurorack oscilloscope so I could see what was happening. In theory, this should determine if we have digital distortion in the MPC Live/X/One on the Channel Volume or not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - I Am A Cheap Date</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/23/jamcember-i-am-a-cheap-date/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 00:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1481</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is it time to start the count down?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/i-am-a-cheap-date&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/i-am-a-cheap-date&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well this one was a bit more of a pain to get started. I have had a mild headache most of the day and just didn&amp;rsquo;t want to put any energy into making a track&amp;hellip; however the show must go on!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is courtesy of my basement&amp;hellip; and the dead spider is courtesy of the glass apparently trapping it in. I don&amp;rsquo;t exactly know what made me think of the picture or the title for the track, but somehow they are now linked in my brain waves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - Flying Monsters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/11/16/track-flying-monsters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 16:05:37 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1216</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/flying-monsters&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/flying-monsters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track came together last night from just patching and trying to see what I could do after not really messing with Eurorack for a few weeks. My wife and I have been ramping up to keep the house cleaned for showings, and it was just something that I haven&amp;rsquo;t given myself time to do. Plus, having a mess of wires hanging out all over the place probably wasn&amp;rsquo;t the best thing for pictures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Edge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/08/17/on-the-edge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 14:02:55 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=852</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/on-the-edge&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/on-the-edge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track comes courtesy of my Eurorack build. I am working on trying to clean up content I have recorded on the 4MS WAV RECORDER, and found this. It was reasonably complete enough that I figured I&amp;rsquo;d just post it up as is. There isn&amp;rsquo;t anything too fancy going on, but it was fun to put together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t really a finished project, and was something I was more interested in playing around with some ideas for a live performance. It was really just pulling together a bass line, some drums, and a freaked out probably over processed evolving space sound. From there I just used some basic mixing components to evolve some of the sounds by turning knobs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Endless Space - Patch and Play</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/07/27/endless-space-patch-and-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 15:16:54 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=780</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the first patch I put together on the new build out of my Eurorack. Just a short video messing around with the patch&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OLeRQdCS0P0?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - Endless Space</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/07/20/track-endless-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 15:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=743</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the first track I put together using my new euro rack modular setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/endless-space&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/endless-space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m trying to remember this patch&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ll post a picture and kind of describe it as best as I can. It was more a test to see how cable routing goes, and if I need longer cables. Turns out so far it isn&amp;rsquo;t too bad, and there&amp;rsquo;s a little something for everybody in every corner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Euro Racking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/07/19/euro-racking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 15:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=737</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I reached out to Erik and sent him this picture so he knew I had the case in hand:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/3b1989f0-f4b8-439f-9186-2a59c4b9548f%5F1%5F105%5Fc.jpeg?w=768&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I managed to strong arm the case up to my desk, and upon turning it on I can tell you the noise from the power was very very high! I was concerned that it was a dirty power supply, but figured that once I had racked everything the sound might go down&amp;hellip; sometimes power supplies make a lot of noise when they don&amp;rsquo;t have a load on them, or too much of a load. You never know.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modular Case Has Arrived</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/07/17/modular-case-has-arrived/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 14:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=729</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well I got the notice from UPS that the case was on it&amp;rsquo;s way, and it will be here today! Super excited to get my hands on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a few pictures of the package and opening up the packaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/3b1989f0-f4b8-439f-9186-2a59c4b9548f%5F1%5F105%5Fc.jpeg?w=768&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UPS delivery person said this was one of the best packaged shipments he has ever seen, and I have to agree. We flipped it (shhhh&amp;hellip; don&amp;rsquo;t tell Erik Needham). This is a beefy case, and I have to say, it looks like some pretty good quality wood for the case.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - Chest Pain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/07/10/track-chest-pain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 18:38:46 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=686</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/chest-pain&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/chest-pain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track came together pretty quickly. Maybe two hours of goofing around on the MPC Live mk2 at most. The core of it started with me patching on my modular system, and seeing what tones I could create, and then sync&amp;rsquo;ing that to the MPC Live mk2 over CV&amp;hellip; well technically gate signals. You can see from the picture that this is honestly not a terribly complicated patch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/8bad7823-6b1f-479f-b535-ad0aeb3ee990%5F1%5F105%5Fc.jpeg?w=883&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This patch is what is making that sometimes bass, sometimes bloopy sound in the track. Effectively Tempi is being clocked by the MPC Live mk2 gate out, which is then clocking the Wogglebug, Brains, and a strike on the RxMx. DPO is doing the oscillator duties today, and being run into the FxDF 6db slope that is then patched into RxMx. In turn, RxMx is being filtered by the QPAS which is then going to the output. Of note, Pressure Points/Brains is being used to modulate the 1v/octave to generate the change in tones, as well as the left !! on QPAS, and the Wogglebug step modulation is driving the QPAS filter changes. I went this way to create a fair mix of &amp;ldquo;in control&amp;rdquo; and somewhat random modulation, which I recorded in as an eight bar loop in the MPC Live mk2 Looper.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Erik Needham Modular Case</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/07/08/erik-needham-modular-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 14:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=723</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I ordered a case from Erik Needham back in January. I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting patiently for six months or so now I think. It&amp;rsquo;s been a balance of waiting to get the modules together I wanted, and trying to get more room by selling off gear I don&amp;rsquo;t want to use any more. If you want to check him out go to his Instagram &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/needhamwoodworks/&#34;&gt;Needham Woodworks&lt;/a&gt; or look him up on &lt;a href=&#34;https://reverb.com/marketplace?query=Needham%20woodworks&#34;&gt;Reverb&lt;/a&gt;. Definitely some great stuff.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Akai MPC Live mk2 / One CV outs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/06/15/akai-mpc-live-mk2-one-cv-outs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 13:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=542</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, and looking to integrate CV output from your MPC so that you can track out gate and CV to devices that will take CV input, you&amp;rsquo;ll find a difference from the MPC X to the MPC Live mk2 / One. On the MPC X, it has eight discrete CV output jacks, so you can connect a TS 1/8&amp;quot; cable to the jack to each of the CV ports for each channel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modular Tennessee</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/05/22/modular-tennessee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 18:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=433</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a patch I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with on my eurorack gear while I am awaiting the case to get everything installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intent for this recording wasn&amp;rsquo;t to get a clean sound&amp;hellip; and yeah&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m just using my cellphone mic. I was mostly testing out a new stand I got to see how much bump/wabble/wiggle the stand introduced in the video. You can hear some background noise (sorry about that), but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too interested in hooking up a proper audio recording device to sync everything. Probably next time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No More Technology - #Jamuary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/01/11/no-more-technology-jamuary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 21:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=349</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No eurorack modules were harmed in the making of this video. The PO-32 (Tonic) makes up the drums, the PO-35 (Voice) is how I got the &amp;ldquo;No More Technology&amp;rdquo; hook, and&amp;hellip; the lead/bass came from some Eurorack mess. I recorded all of this into Ableton Live for some FX processing. All of this was recorded back in October/November, and I&amp;rsquo;ve meant to create a finished track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of #Jamuary though, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d break out some gear and refine the track a bit more. I&amp;rsquo;m really trying to cap myself to about 30-60 minutes of production time this month for each song. This is good in some ways because it&amp;rsquo;s forcing me to get ideas down, but it is bad in a few other ways since I&amp;rsquo;m really not mixing/mastering anything. Leaving this track with a bit more of a tinny sound than I&amp;rsquo;d like, but hey it is what it is.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
