<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Akai-S950 on NearTao&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/akai-s950/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Akai-S950 on NearTao&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 13:02:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/akai-s950/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MPCBB304 - Lucky Number</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/02/23/mpcbb304-lucky-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 13:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=2416</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This track was just to mess around with recording onto the Akai S950 at a ridiculous bandrate and pitched up a lot so I could get most of the track into the S950 to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/mpcbb304-lucky-number&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/mpcbb304-lucky-number&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the track is pretty muddy, and a bit of a mess, but whatever I had fun putting it together. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that there is anything worth digging into for production techniques because it was mostly just finding sections that kind of worked, looping some content, and messing with FX.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Akai VX90 Heart Akai S950 Samples n Programs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/02/21/akai-vx90-heart-akai-s950-samples-n-programs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 13:05:37 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=2382</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was just testing a few things on the VX90/S950 combo setup and figured I would record off a few key groups to see how things were sounding. Below are the files if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in checking them out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am pretty sure that Cherry Crush was the first key group that I recorded yesterday after getting everything setup and working again. I recorded a sample into the S950 and then worked on tweaking the filter and resonance to see what kind of sweet spots I could find.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configuring an Akai VX90 and Akai S950</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/02/20/configuring-an-akai-vx90-and-akai-s950/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 16:06:40 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=2294</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spent a few hours messing around with the configuration, and trying to get everything to work. It is not exactly straight forward, and I had to dig through a lot of old posts and try and understand what exactly different sources were trying to tell me. I found a few that indicated that it should work polyphonically, but didn&amp;rsquo;t exactly describe the steps to get there, or said things a little too generically. I can say, I now have it all working (yeah!), and will go through how to get this setup step by step, where you might hit a few problems, suggestions to test out issues. Let&amp;rsquo;s get into it :D&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Fortress of Self</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/22/jamcember-fortress-of-self/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 14:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1472</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mixing it up a bit for the twenty second track&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/fortress-of-self&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/fortress-of-self&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture comes courtesy of a trip to Munich. Not so much a tourist type of city, but there&amp;rsquo;s a lot to see there. I think that particular shot came from a train ride that I took with my family to go check out the Olympic Stadium out there. It was interesting to see, but kind of sad at the same time to see something that had so much funding and investment put into it that ended up not being kept up and maintained as much as you&amp;rsquo;d hope. I suspect that a lot of the Olympic areas around the world are like this, and I suppose when things get back to normal I will have to travel around to check out more for myself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MPC Programs - NT S950 Volume 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/11/30/mpc-programs-nt-s950-volume-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 18:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1292</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Got some more S950 programs sampled, but first, here&amp;rsquo;s the link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/nt-s950-v4.zip&#34;&gt;NT - S950 v4&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/nt-s950-v4.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big thing I learned this time around was that from the Sampler menu, if you select a mono source and set the sampling to mono&amp;hellip; well I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to use Fission to covert the samples to mono. That saved some headaches for sure!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall notes for the auto sampling:&lt;br&gt;
\* 430 Mono samples&lt;br&gt;
\* Should play from C-2 to G8&lt;br&gt;
\* Sampled C0 to C5 in most cases, with a stride of 4&lt;br&gt;
\* Generally 16 samples per program&lt;br&gt;
\* Only one Sample Layer at velocity of 127&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S950 and S1000 White Noise and Drum Break Comparison</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/11/27/s950-and-s1000-white-noise-and-drum-break-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 21:16:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1272</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A conversation started on MPC Forums about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mpc-forums.com/viewtopic.php?f=11&amp;amp;t=206423&#34;&gt;MPC &amp;amp; S900/950 Routing Question&lt;/a&gt;. We got into details about how the S900/S950 worked, which then lead into S900/S950 samples sounding more full on the S1000 and later. I ended up taking a stab at sampling both white noise and a drum break on the S950 with a bandwidth of 3000 and 19200, and then playing the notes across the key group to get some samples together. Below is the project and recordings from the S950 and S1000 for your own listening.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MPC Programs - NT S950 Volume 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/11/20/mpc-programs-nt-s950-volume-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 13:14:55 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1260</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m back at it for another round of sampling off of my trusty Akai S950&amp;hellip; still working like a champ. Before getting into the details, here&amp;rsquo;s the link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/nt-s950-v3-1.zip&#34;&gt;NT - S950 v3&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/nt-s950-v3-1.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good news is that I am getting faster at sampling, but the bad news is that I made a mistake on a few of the programs and called them S95 instead of S950. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t too big of a deal since the .xpm files are text editable since they are in a human readable format, but it was a bit of a chore to rename all of the samples, edit the file to do a search and replace of S95 to S950, and then hope everything worked out okay. Still, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t so bad, and I have gotten some more samples together for your enjoyment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MPC Samples - NT S950 Volume 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/11/17/mpc-samples-nt-s950-volume-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 13:51:59 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1232</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spent some more time last night recording off of the Akai S950&amp;hellip; and I can tell you I continue to really dig the low end sound. Before digging in a bit, here is the link:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/nt-s950-v2.zip&#34;&gt;NT - S950 v2&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/nt-s950-v2.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to a few days ago, this is MPC X/Live/One formatted for the program file, but the samples are 44.1k/16-bit mono, so you can load them into most MPCs and samplers. I was definitely a bit faster at flying through the low end key group and setting it to record notes down to C0, though I still forgot to check and change C5&amp;hellip; in about half the cases this resulted in one less sample for the program.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - Space Dust</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/10/13/track-space-dust/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 21:11:55 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1090</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/mpcbb-292-space-dust&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/mpcbb-292-space-dust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put this track together last week for the MPC BB 292, and then forgot to post about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first trick, to get the really over cooked sound from the track, I ended up pitching the track up 3 octaves before playing it, and then sampled it into my Akai S950. This really stripped away a lot of the high end information, but also made the low end quite a bit punchier to my ears. Initially I pitched it up so much because I just didn&amp;rsquo;t have the sample time to record a nearly 6 minute song into the roughly 23 seconds of sample time&amp;hellip; and pitching the content up so extremely really let me squeeze it all in there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Akai S950 Memory Upgrade</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/05/23/akai-s950-memory-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 15:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=448</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Akai S950 is not too hard to upgrade, and there are not too many options. One upgrade that can be important is to increase the amount of memory that your S950 has, since it can triple your sample time. Before you start though, make sure you don&amp;rsquo;t forget to unplug the Akai S950 from power. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to accidentally fry your S950 or yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can get access to the memory ports to install by taking the bottom off. To make life easier I normally draw a small picture and place the screws onto the picture so that I can put the same screw back into the same spot. This helps so that you don&amp;rsquo;t accidentally put the wrong screw into the wrong spot and accidentally strip out the metal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LoFi Buttery Piano - Akai MPC X Program</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/03/08/lofi-buttery-piano-akai-mpc-x-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 23:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=369</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let me start by explaining the patch a bit, and how I got here&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life started off on the Akai S950, using piano multi samples from G1 through C4, every sixth note&amp;hellip; My goal was to get some of that S950 12-bit grit and artifacts, but still keep it relatively free of the crazy stretching artifacts you can get by just sampling a single note and stretching it across the entire keyboard. This way, it maintains a lot of the characteristics of a piano, instead of heading into the field of creating what sounds like a more synthetic instrument.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Old School Cinema for Akai MPC X/Live</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/10/19/old-school-cinema-for-akai-mpc-x-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 14:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=141</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The patch &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/nt-old-school-cinema.zip&#34;&gt;Old School Cinema&lt;/a&gt; started life on the Pocket Operator Tonic. I recorded the hits into the Akai S950 at 10khz, because I was afraid that some of the longer bass notes would exhaust the sample memory, and honestly I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to be chopping on the S950 for an hour. I was able to squeeze everything into the roughly 60 seconds of sample time I had available at the 10khz sampling rate. Honestly, I could have probably squeezed it in a bit better, but I was trying to let some of the longer notes ring out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Akai S950 Clean Bass for MPC X/Live</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/10/19/akai-s950-clean-bass-for-mpc-x-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=137</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is just a &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/nt-950-analogue-clean-bass-01.zip&#34;&gt;Clean Analogue Bass&lt;/a&gt; recorded on the Akai S950. Nothing too special, and I kept the sample size down. The sample range is from C0 through C4 so there is a pretty good range to play with.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Akai S950 Tape Grand Piano for MPC X/Live</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/10/17/akai-s950-tape-grand-piano-for-mpc-x-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 23:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=106</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is my next patch for my MPC X &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/nt-tape-grand-piano.zip&#34;&gt;Tape Grand Piano&lt;/a&gt;. I started with a multisample Grand Piano sampled into the Akai S950 at C/F note intervals. So samples a bit stretched, but it sounds pleasant enough, and certainly a bit more realistic than the strings a made recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The patch was again routed through a tape effect to give it some not so subtle tape warble. A pretty big problem that I had making this patch, is that it is over 60 samples, and while the auto sampler in the MPC X/Live is nice, it isn&amp;rsquo;t a complete solution. So I ended up spending a fair amount of time trimming the samples, only to remember that there is still a bug that if you record the content through a single input, it still records the sample as stereo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Akai S950 String Program For MPC Live/X</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/10/16/akai-s950-string-program-for-mpc-live-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 21:07:33 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=43</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey everybody!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I spent some time trimming recording in a string sample into the Akai S950.  It was about 20 seconds or so long.  The idea was to make something that could be pitched up reasonably high and still have a reasonable length to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I completed sampling into the S950, I used my Akai MPC Live to create a mono sampled key group patch from the content.  The auto sampler tried to put in loop points, but they were completed busted, so I disabled sample looping.  I have to say, I do like some of the sounds in the lower keys (C0-C1), as the stretching from the S950 sounds pretty heavy and dark.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
