<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity on NearTao&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity on NearTao&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 16:19:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/productivity/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A boat at sea</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/11/18/a-boat-at-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 16:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1225</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just another quick painting that I did. I was testing out how well the paper would handle darker paint, and I&amp;rsquo;m still going to say with the pencil board behind the page, it is hardly relevant and doesn&amp;rsquo;t really impact my ability or distract me from writing on the next page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve come to the conclusion that controlling the amount of water you put on the page is important, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed the color lifting off of the page and rubbing on older pages yet. Better I haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed water coloring on one page impacting a painting on the other side of the paper. I am positive I can make this a problem, but so far it hasn&amp;rsquo;t bothered me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mixed Media on Hobonichi Tomo River Paper</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/11/06/mixed-media-on-hobonichi-tomo-river-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 23:34:21 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1193</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since I have my travel water color kit sitting on my desk, and I ended up doodling a bit during some meetings, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d do a little mixed media and see how well the paper would handle it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start, I just did a pretty simple design sketch with a mechanical pencil (a Kuru Toga for those who want to keep track). This was not anything too fancy, and I tried to keep the impression light so that when I got to coloring the water wouldn&amp;rsquo;t pool too much. Of course, since I had already written on the other side of the page, this was bound to be a little suspect, but I wanted to try. Regardless, with the writing board behind the page, it worked well enough to get a rough outline down on paper. I suspect there is room to try some embossing techniques in the future, but for now I&amp;rsquo;ll just keep it in mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watercolor on Hobonichi Tomo River Paper</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/11/05/watercolor-on-hobonichi-tomo-river-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 20:13:26 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1185</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While I have been waiting on 2021 to roll around, I&amp;rsquo;ve been taking notes and doodling in my Hobonichi Notebook. Today I figured I&amp;rsquo;d give a try to see how the paper would react to water color. Anybody who&amp;rsquo;s tried to do water color on non watercolor paper (or even with water color paper) knows that the paper will bunch and curl a lot. I&amp;rsquo;ve really appreciated how well Tomo River paper has held inks in the past, so I figured it&amp;rsquo;d be worth a try.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hobonichi 2021 Haul</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/10/26/hobonichi-2021-haul/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 14:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1173</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My Hobonichi order finally showed up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img%5F1320-e1603722484626.jpeg?w=750&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The packaging from Hobonichi has always been fun, and the quotes are interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img%5F1321.jpeg?w=750&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; and as always, everything is well organized inside of the box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img%5F1322-e1603722702324.jpeg?w=750&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I figured I would pick up a couple of the Drawer Pouches that match as close as I could with my Porter cousin case. From the pictures I wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite sure what I was going to get, but wanted to check them out. Both seem like they probably are better with flatter content, though I will give it a try and see if I can get washi tape to fit in here well enough or not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Case For a Clean Inbox</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/10/22/the-case-for-a-clean-inbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 18:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1163</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Folks, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen many of your counts of unread emails, messages, and other backlogs. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how you keep the mental space to keep track of all of this information coming at you. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m getting too old, but I just find it to be a sign of a cluttered mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, I really strive to keep inbox zero, or in other words, no email is sitting in my inbox. For me, the problem is that the longer something sits in the inbox whether it is read or unread, the more likely you are to ultimately do nothing with it. Is this procrastination, optimism that somebody else will deal with the email, or lack of interest, frankly it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. In all cases it results in something that takes up mental space that you&amp;rsquo;d be better off freeing yourself from. These little things can add up to real setbacks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2019 Every Day Carry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/10/21/2019-every-day-carry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 18:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1149</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Below is what I had for my “every day carry” back in 2019.  This is the last iteration where I have dropped a thicker wallet and gone from 8-12 cards and cash, down to 4 cards.  The notebook and pen are new, but being about the same size as my phone I hardly notice it day to day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img%5F0086.jpg?w=768&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I am thinking about what I keep in my pockets or otherwise on my person I like to ask myself a few questions&amp;hellip; “Why do I carry this”, “how often do I use this”, and “what utility does this provide” are all pretty good, and help me make sure I keep focus on what I am lugging around.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ooooooof</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/10/16/ooooooof/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 22:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/2019/10/16/ooooooof/</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So reality is starting to set in as I try and consider all of the content I have ever created, and where the heck it is. Servers are gone, my network addressable storage (NAS) won&amp;rsquo;t mount on my computer. I have a bit of a road in front of me to recover my digital life again. I am not giving up already, but it looks like I may have to face some harsh realities about the time investment I need to put in so I can accomplish what I set out to do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
