<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Akai-Mpc-1000 on NearTao&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/akai-mpc-1000/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Akai-Mpc-1000 on NearTao&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 02:03:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/akai-mpc-1000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chip Bass - Akai MPC 1k Program</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/01/04/chip-bass-akai-mpc-1k-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 02:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=239</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another mystery sample and program here. It is now nearly a month old, and I cannot remember what the heck I did at *all* for this one. I suppose the dog excuse is still valid and in play, but woof&amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;the dog ate my homework&amp;rdquo; never worked in school, and I suppose it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really do much here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are my notes this wondrous day? Well check it out below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Classy Piano - Akai MPC 1k Program</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/01/02/classy-piano-akai-mpc-1k-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 02:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=236</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well now, this has been sitting in my drafts for way to long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where did this even come from? Oh yeah, I made the loop in Reason, using a piano patch&amp;hellip; which one *shrug*, I forget. But I definitely used the Scream FX to add some wow/flutter, how much? I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;hellip; take a listen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So apparently the danger I have is not writing enough notes down when I prepare these posts, and I also need to get myself better into the habit of just writing the content of these posts&amp;hellip; below, the next two lines are what I wrote.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sloppy Piano Chops - Akai MPC 1k Program</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/12/04/sloppy-piano-chops-akai-mpc-1k-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 01:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=242</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I broke down and got a guitar pedal board today, so I could more easily work with multiple pedals. Before it was one at a time, but not any more. Now I can run them in series and mix and match for some more interesting effects. I&amp;rsquo;ll have to start posting about putting the pedal board together and powering it. Oh and hacking on the plastic to get everything to fit, but I&amp;rsquo;ll leave that for another day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MPC 1k Q-Link Repair</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/12/03/mpc-1k-q-link-repair/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=216</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oh the joys of owning older gear.  Q2 on my MPC was super sketchy.  Loading up the JJOS v3 test menu showed Q2 was going from a range of about 300-500, and normal operation is 0-1000.  Another fun problem was that moving Q1 was also making a subtle change to Q2.  That&amp;rsquo;s definitely not supposed to happen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I figured there were a few things to try in order to resolve this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LoFi House - Akai MPC 1k Drum Program</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/12/02/lofi-house-akai-mpc-1k-drum-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 01:46:55 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=230</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I decided to play around with Reason again, and ended up recording the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/lofi-house-mpc-1k-program.zip&#34;&gt;LoFi House MPC 1k Program&lt;/a&gt;. Really nothing too fancy, but other than routing drums through a 12-bit distortion Rack Extension, with a bunch of tweaking to filter it a bit. Honestly, each drum hit could be better tweaked for a tighter sound, but I ran out of sampling steam. Perhaps I&amp;rsquo;ll come back to a round two (or three) of these samples and trying and put something together a bit more consistent. So nothing too epic, but I figured it would be fun to play around with.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>String Loss Program for Akai MPC 1000</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/11/30/string-loss-program-for-akai-mpc-1000/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 13:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=211</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This came as an experiment playing with some string sounds from the OP-1 String engine and and using the Chase Bliss Mood for the effects. I recorded into the granular tape effect, and sent the output through the slip effect, giving the sound quite a level of character. The initial recording is &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/string-loss.wav&#34;&gt;String Loss&lt;/a&gt;, and to me it evokes a bit of a cutting and driving sound that exists somewhere between the string and organ family of sounds. It was pretty simple to chop up into a program, which resulted in &lt;a href=&#34;//neartao.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/string-loss-mpc-1k.zip&#34;&gt;String Loss MPC 1k&lt;/a&gt;. At the moment, I&amp;rsquo;ve really just been playing with the straight chops at different velocities, but I think for the song I&amp;rsquo;m building up I&amp;rsquo;m going to lean into some pitch shifting of the parts to see how I can really push the sounds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cheap Piano - Akai MPC 1000 Program</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/11/29/cheap-piano-akai-mpc-1000-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 01:48:37 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=204</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m pulling together on a track on my MPC 1k, and have been playing around with a few piano sounds. The initial sound comes from the OP-1, from the Fake Piano patch under the DR Wave engine. I liked this sound as a starting point, and it reminds me a bit of the old Casio keyboards from the 80&amp;rsquo;s. I changed the presets a bit, and in particular turned off the Spring reverb as this was giving it a bit too much presence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
