<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Yorgos-Arabatzsis-Mastering on NearTao&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/yorgos-arabatzsis-mastering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Yorgos-Arabatzsis-Mastering on NearTao&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 22:15:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/yorgos-arabatzsis-mastering/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #31 - Project Morpheus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/31/beatober2021-31-project-morpheus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 22:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3472</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Based on feedback, tried to make this track much louder, and maybe got a little too carried away. Now I think it has pushed into a bit too crunchy and toasty territory. I probably should not have been driving the STMix so hard :/.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bass line is only 2 bars long and absolutely needs some variations to move it around, or something to tie off every 4 or 8 bars… just something different. Ah well, this was fun and definitely deserves a second try at thinking about how to drive all the content through the eurorack anyways, and might be something to expand on some more to build out into a set.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #13 - Bringing the Dirt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/13/beatober2021-13-bringing-the-dirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 01:04:16 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3376</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The picture comes courtesy of NeuralBlender&amp;hellip; google it :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/bringing-the-dirt&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/bringing-the-dirt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the music is a bit more pedestrian&amp;hellip; and just Akai MPC Live mk2 all the way baby&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just tired I guess? Having a hard time finding inspiration? I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;hellip; maybe I just need to sleep better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said&amp;hellip; I guess it&amp;rsquo;s time to head towards the direction of the bed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - Always</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/12/jamtember2021-track-always/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 15:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3156</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mostly happy with how this track came out&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/always&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/always&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picture is just of the SP-202&amp;hellip; just thought it looked kinda cool all lit up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The track itself came together pretty quickly, though I did have to go tweak a number of samples once I ran it through YAM&amp;hellip; all of a sudden I was noticing all kinds of clipping and noise. The atmospheric sound at the beginning was full of so many pops and clips. I didn&amp;rsquo;t remove all of them, but definitely reduced it a bit by just tweaking the program. The bass was just super noisy, probably as a result from having run it through the SP-202 a bit, so I had to drop a LPF on it to clean it up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - Flexing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/11/jamtember2021-track-flexing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 10:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3150</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Something that I was working on last month, and dug up to make sure it got completed&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/flexing&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/flexing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is from the zoo we visited in Hawaii.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The track itself I worked on while visiting my sister and came about from trying to prep some content for jamming with my brother in law. We got a couple good jam sessions in, but nothing recorded. This particular track was something that I was just up in the morning messing with and had saved off for a while and figured it was something worth saving to work on and finishing later. Up at 6am this morning, got a long day ahead, and figured it was as good a time as any to run it across the finish line!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#Jamtember2021 Track - Miss You</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/02/jamtember2021-track-miss-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 18:05:07 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3034</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Had a slightly longer lunch break than intended, but came to this track as an end point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/miss-you&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/miss-you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is another one from the walk. Just some train tracks that I had to walk over, and look like a good time to snap a quick picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly though, what I had for lunch. Chicken Tikka Masala, and boy did it hit the spot! Sure it was store bought, packaged, and needed to be reheated, but it is what I had available at the time, or I could have had some fajita leftovers, but I think I am saving those for tonight.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#Jamtember2021 Track - You&#39;re All Invited</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/01/jamtember2021-track-youre-all-invited/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 17:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3026</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is on! Going to hit up a track a day, with the goal of hitting 300 tracks posted to soundcloud by the end of the year. This should get me within striking distance of, six tracks left to do afterwards I think&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ll have to try and just hit that before the end of the month. Maybe do a couple tracks a day to fill it out :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/youre-all-invited&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/youre-all-invited&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yorgos Arabatzsis Mastering 2.0.2 Released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/08/27/yorgos-arabatzsis-mastering-2-0-2-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 13:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3000</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yorgos just released the 2.0.2 mastering suite for the Akai MPC Live/X/One using some of the new features in the 2.10 firmware. If you already have the suite you should have gotten an email, and he also posted some information on the MPC Forums thread &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mpc-forums.com/viewtopic.php?f=48&amp;amp;t=189006&#34;&gt;YA MASTERING TEMPLATE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is what I just posted in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mpc-forums.com/viewtopic.php?f=48&amp;amp;t=189006&amp;amp;start=180&#34;&gt;thread&lt;/a&gt;, but adding here for posterity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a track with and without using the YA Mastering Template 2.0.2. Anything that sounds bad here is frankly on me for not taking a bit more time to adjust and get the sonics under control.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - Hungers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/08/26/track-hungers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 18:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3006</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This track started while I was out visiting my sister and her family last week. Was just sitting on a chair and knocking out some sounds to see what would stick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/hungers&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/hungers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is from a library, the venting looked interesting so a snapped a picture. Ran it through a Ps Camera filter (elements?) just to see how it would look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track is a mix of loops I grabbed, and loading up some synths and using pad performer to try and get some other sounds in tune with the loops I was grabbing. Not rocket science, but the way that the loops were reported as a key in the MPC Sample Edit section made it a bit awkward to figure a few things out. Mostly because the MPC refuses to acknowledge flats, so it always thinks everything is sharp. Not a big deal per se, but it can mean that you&amp;rsquo;ve got to think through what key/note range it thinks content is in and then break it down into what you are actually going to play. Sure if you do it right it all matches up regardless if you are sharp or flat, but it can mean that the way you think about some of the notes is just off, if that makes sense?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - Right in the Kisser</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/02/06/track-right-in-the-kisser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 14:56:16 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=2034</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s kind of funny&amp;hellip; because after doing the two months of making a track a day back to back&amp;hellip; I feel like my flow has transitioned to just putting stuff down in a different sort of way, making it a bit more raw&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/right-in-the-kisser&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/right-in-the-kisser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is from a few years back, when Amy was more of a spring chicken. she&amp;rsquo;s still quite an active dog, but she definitely prefers to be laying down on a lap, or being held. Still curious to explore and see new things, but not quite so bold as she once was.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Quiet Heart</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/31/jamuary2021-quiet-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 21:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1942</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last day for #jamuary2021&amp;hellip; and I&amp;rsquo;m happy to look towards doing some more music still, but probably at a slower pace so that I can focus on tracks a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/quiet-heart&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/quiet-heart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is of the fire pit that we built&amp;hellip; going to miss it when we move to the new house, but we&amp;rsquo;ll create another one :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The track came together pretty quickly while I was watching my daughter play the sims, make a character of me&amp;hellip; who she promptly made broke, and then I guess I was then homeless. She had my avatar doing a lot of weird things. It makes me wonder what my daughter thinks of me sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Foundation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/23/jamuary2021-foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 14:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1857</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 23&amp;hellip; just a handful more to put together to wrap up the month!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/foundation&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/foundation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is from a trip to Puerto Rico&amp;hellip; probably around twenty years ago now. Just a quick snap that I took while driving by the beach. The water down there is amazing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting the track together, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d work on something a bit more experimental, so not quite so traditional drums and sounds, and just see how it came together. Overall, I am relatively happy with it, but the mixing seems off. I spent some time trying to adjust the levels, but I think there&amp;rsquo;s some EQ and filtering that would need to be done to really make the track pop. I did my best by ear, but I got stuck in a few areas where having some visuals to go with the EQ to see where harmonics are probably would have helped be a bit more precise, instead of just using a low pass and high pass filter to just remove sounds completely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Bleeding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/22/jamuary2021-bleeding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 18:47:03 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1848</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 22&amp;hellip; and this is a very noisy DnB track&amp;hellip; so considered yourself warned&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/bleeding&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/bleeding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pictures is of a family friend&amp;rsquo;s dog, that just looked super evil for the day. I might have to play with the picture again, because it could really turn into something special. Not today though&amp;hellip; because it&amp;rsquo;s just about time to start preparing for tomorrow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track is just a straight up noisy DnB track&amp;hellip; I initially wasn&amp;rsquo;t intending to get so gritty but everything just kind of fell into place that way. I had a ton more FX I had layered in, but had a bit of a hard time figuring out if you can automate turning FX on and off (turns out as far as I can tell you cannot).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - You Alright</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/21/jamuary2021-you-alright/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 19:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1833</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 21 was not going to be a happy house track&amp;hellip; but yet&amp;hellip; bring on the bright and happy vibes&amp;hellip; I guess I could use it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/you-alright&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/you-alright&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The painting is from when I used to record art lessons and post them online&amp;hellip; I think I did about 100 episodes, under the title &amp;ldquo;Painting in Five&amp;rdquo;. This particular one was showing how to paint out a rough sketch, and I&amp;rsquo;m quite certain it was based off of the lion from the MCM Grand. At any rate, the idea was to just show people how to quickly get some things down without thinking too much about whether it was good or bad. And now&amp;hellip; about twenty years later, I am doing a track a day just to get myself to put something down. Maybe I should bring back the &amp;ldquo;In Five&amp;rdquo; concept in the blog? I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about it, but haven&amp;rsquo;t committed to anything yet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - High and Tight</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/19/jamuary2021-high-and-tight/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 14:19:08 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1795</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;January 19th&amp;hellip; and on track numero nineteen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/high-and-tight&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/high-and-tight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is from a game of air hockey with my daughter from years ago. Something we used to do a lot at the local kid casino&amp;hellip; but she is too old for that now :D.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The track was made using drums from MPC Tutor&amp;rsquo;s latest drum kit&amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mpc-samples.com/product.php/315/the-underground-crates/&#34;&gt;The Underground Crates&lt;/a&gt;. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for some new drums definitely check it out. I&amp;rsquo;m digging this MPC Expansion so far, and can see it having a lot of mileage. The rest of the track is just a chopped up bass and chopped up guitar sample. Nothing too exciting&amp;hellip; and I had a vocal track with it, but it was just too much. I ended up just going for keeping this track simple and chilled out today&amp;hellip; so it isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly special&amp;hellip; but I really liked how chilled out and fun it sounded.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Piece of Mine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/18/jamuary2021-piece-of-mine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 18:24:43 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1787</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the eighteenth track for #jamuary2021&amp;hellip; only thirteen(?) to go?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/piece-of-mine&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/piece-of-mine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picture is from my dog Amy&amp;hellip; she was totally chilling the other day. Well, honestly, she chills every day! That&amp;rsquo;s her secret, she&amp;rsquo;s always relaxed. Except when the wind is blowing leaves around&amp;hellip; then she&amp;rsquo;s full attack mode. Other than that though, she&amp;rsquo;s conserving her energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For you folks out there not making stuff&amp;hellip; whether it is dope or whack&amp;hellip; come on&amp;hellip; get yourself out there! I&amp;rsquo;m definitely hearing some great stuff coming from folks just trying to put things down, but there&amp;rsquo;s quite a few peeps with a lot of gear just sitting on their laurels. Get your freak on and put something together!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Fears for Tears</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/17/jamuary2021-fears-for-tears/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 17:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1744</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 17&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/fears-for-tears&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/fears-for-tears&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is from a painting I did years ago&amp;hellip; I think I gave it to my mom? *shrug*&amp;hellip; somebody probably still has it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track came together pretty fast. I started with a pretty basic drum beat and bass line, and tweaked the FX, pitch, etc&amp;hellip; a bit to get a bit more of an interesting sound. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t long before I added in the piano. This is just a chopped up loop, and I decided to do something different, and work on make a 32 bar playing of the chops, instead of doing my usual 4 or 8 bar play through and then working with the loops. I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to consider this in the future, as it was both fun to see different ways I could utilize the sample, but I also got a few interesting places I normally wouldn&amp;rsquo;t get to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Almost There</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/16/jamuary2021-almost-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 16:51:46 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1736</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 16&amp;hellip; it may be cold outside but it is getting warm in here&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/almost-there&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/almost-there&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is a chocolate cake we had for Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day&amp;hellip; really good&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure my wife picked it up at Whole Foods&amp;hellip; if I remember correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the track it&amp;rsquo;s another mix of chops and synths&amp;hellip; and auto sampling&amp;hellip; and mistakes. I spent a lot of time looking for sounds that I felt would work together, so this track feels pretty good. Normally I&amp;rsquo;d upload the auto sampled synth&amp;hellip; but it has echo in it&amp;hellip; making me have to record every single note for the group, and then this makes it hard to use outside of a 96bpm standpoint&amp;hellip; as well&amp;hellip; it also only works for the notes I sampled which&amp;hellip; put it in the rather not so useful category for a general standpoint. I may try and find a good delay/reverb match to make it into a generic MPC patch&amp;hellip; but for now it just felt kind of strange to upload something so rigid and honestly kind of single purpose.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Data Repeater</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/06/jamuary2021-data-repeater/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 19:25:25 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1630</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just spent most of the day doing small things&amp;hellip; so figured I&amp;rsquo;d wrap this turkey up :D&#39;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/data-repeater&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/data-repeater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is from some resin structures we made as a family this year. My dad was all about how copper killed COVID or something silly, so he sent us some. I didn&amp;rsquo;t buy into it, and I don&amp;rsquo;t think he did either, but we ended up all doing remote family molds to just try and make something interesting. I had never poured resin like this before, so it was interesting at least to see the process up close and personal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Silent Grace</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/05/jamuary2021-silent-grace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 15:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1623</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day five&amp;hellip; and I am still alive!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/silent-grace&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/silent-grace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture comes from a Barnum and Bailey Circus show that we brought our daughter to. She loved it. Definitely was weird though&amp;hellip; we were near the front of the stadium and these massive and majestic creatures still looked so small. We offered our daughter to go see them up close after the show, but I think she was three at the time and was terrified to get anywhere near them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MPCBB #299 - Aeon&#39;s Regret</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/04/mpcbb-299-aeons-regret/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:46:41 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1614</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dropping off a track for MPC Forums Beat Battle #299&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/mpcbb299-aeons-regret&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/mpcbb299-aeons-regret&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I rolled this track together in what&amp;hellip; less than an hour I think? I just did lazy/manual chops by playing the track and tapping out the pads&amp;hellip; I know it&amp;rsquo;s a bit sloppy, but honestly it sounded fine, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t looking to make a masterpiece. From there I knocked out a bit of drums to just have something to flip to, and was off to the races.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Method of Attack</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/04/jamuary2021-method-of-attack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 15:09:12 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1606</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day four is a bit more rocking today. Went in a kind of house/trance direction&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/method-of-attack&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/method-of-attack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture comes from a trip to Disney World that my wife and I took our daughter to for her third birthday. She doesn&amp;rsquo;t remember the trip at all today, but at the time she had a blast. When she was younger she was quite a clingy kid, and I can still remember how sore my shoulders were because she refused to walk anywhere and instead wanted to ride on my shoulders for the entire trip. Do not recommend&amp;hellip; the shoulder part&amp;hellip; the Disney trip was great :D&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Mad Cap</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/03/jamuary2021-mad-cap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 20:22:21 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1598</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day three&amp;rsquo;s track is in the house!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/mad-cap&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/mad-cap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image comes courtesy of one of my wife&amp;rsquo;s trips to New York City with her friends years ago. I repurposed it for my track&amp;hellip; hopefully she doesn&amp;rsquo;t mind :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned yesterday that I started working on this track yesterday right after throwing in the towel for day two, and I really dig how this track came out. I decided to keep the flow super short, so it is just a Main section, Drop section, and Outro section&amp;hellip; so absolutely nothing fancy, but I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like it needed much else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Biggest Regret</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/02/jamuary-2021-biggest-regret/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 20:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1590</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day two of #jamuary 2021&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/biggest-regret&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/biggest-regret&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture comes courtesy of my daughter finding a frog in the backyard over the summer and we caught a few pictures of it. She was super excited to have found such a small critter hanging out in the back yard and just wanted to get a few close ups of the little guy (or gal).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fiddled with this track a bit throughout the day and it never quite came together the way I wanted. I tried to play everything out by hand as much as possible, and well&amp;hellip; I find it okay. The transitions between sections are particularly week again, and I know I could have done better to build up more energy if I had just had the time. Instead I decided to cut my losses on this track and move forward to preparing for day three instead&amp;hellip; which meant this track suffered.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Ninth Circle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/31/jamcember-ninth-circle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 18:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1568</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s to slugging out the last track for December, and heading into the new year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/ninth-circle&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/ninth-circle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track came about from creating an audio track from a 32 bar loop on the Access Virus TI2 Darkstar. I automated a few parameters and figured it sound cool enough to add some drums and FX to it. I wanted to try and get something slower and more droning this time around, instead of some of the faster and more manic tracks I have been laying down the last month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Deeply Stricken</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/30/jamcember-deeply-stricken/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 23:57:48 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1561</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The second of two remaining tracks for the month!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/deeply-stricken&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/deeply-stricken&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this track has several key groups that I auto sampled off of both my Access Virus TI2 Darkstar and Waldorf Iridium. I figured I&amp;rsquo;d upload the patches for those interested or who are just looking for some synth sounds to play with&amp;hellip; so you can get them below. I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother trimming anything&amp;hellip; so the file is a bit large&amp;hellip; but go nuts and have fun!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Cause and Effect</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/29/jamcember-cause-and-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 18:29:33 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1526</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just two more of these to go&amp;hellip; holy smokes what a month!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/cause-and-effect&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/cause-and-effect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picture comes courtesy of a sunset in Aruba from a couple years back. Took the family to go see the island, and we all had a blast. Heck even got my wife into the ocean for a little bit, despite her being completely afraid to hop into water!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get the notes I played around with Orb Composer a bit in order to come up with note progressions for Arp/Bass/Chord/Melody&amp;hellip; The key is Ab, Major scale with a chord progression of i-iv-vii-II, or Abmb7/Eb, Dbm/Ab, Gbmb7, and Bbb/Fb. I tried to use the MPC Live Performance Pads to operate in the correct scale&amp;hellip; maybe it worked? I didn&amp;rsquo;t play out too much live so it isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly like it probably mattered much.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Emotional Adjustment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/27/jamcember-emotional-adjustment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 02:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1511</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is not what I had intended to create&amp;hellip; but that seems to be par for the course for trying to do a track a day :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/emotional-adjustment&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/emotional-adjustment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intent for this track was to put some content together in Reason and then make some create patterns that changed chord structures throughout the song. Started off good, made a bunch of chords, arpeggios, and bass lines to flow in a Bb Minor&amp;hellip; chord progression of I-VII-v-ii&amp;hellip; resulting in Bbmb7, AbM7, Fm/Ab, Cmb7&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - A Grave Decision</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/26/jamcember-a-grave-decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 18:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1505</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Was struggling to pull anything together for day 26. I started a bunch of tracks but nothing really grabbed me. Must be a downer from all the excitement from Christmas. *shrug*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/a-grave-decision&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/a-grave-decision&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt like I was just pulling things together randomly&amp;hellip; and then when I&amp;rsquo;d start to track out different sections nothing felt like it felt like it worked together. Heck, I removed half of this track because it just didn&amp;rsquo;t sit in place correctly and the transitions were quite jarring. It is possible that I am just getting tired of making a track a day, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s just the mood.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MPCBB 268 - Relaxing Action</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/25/mpcbb-268-relaxing-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 13:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1500</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There weren&amp;rsquo;t any other entries, so I figured what the heck and put together a track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/mpcbb298-relaxing-action&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/mpcbb298-relaxing-action&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sample itself was pretty basic, so I figured I would work on chopping it up and just finding a drum kit to play to it. I wanted to focus as much as possible on keeping the original audio track playing throughout the track without it sounding too repetitive, this meant making variations to work through, and seeing what worked. Ultimately I wanted some of the shorter chops to play longer through this process, so a quick detune of 6 semitones had me pretty well sorted so that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any gaps of silence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Saturday Night Jive</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/25/jamcember-saturday-night-jive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 13:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1493</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My track for Christmas&amp;hellip; woo!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/saturday-night-jive&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/saturday-night-jive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another track that I tried to go for a more minimal sound, and it was made up of only three loops. I know the track itself is not very complex or technical, but I worked on making up for it by making a few variations of each loop to get some variety in the flips. Given that I am still doing a new track a day, and time has been at a premium, this gave me a bit more time to be picky on the loops that I chose to work with in order to put the track together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - East Coast Comfort Food</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/24/jamcember-east-coast-comfort-food/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 01:37:35 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1488</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Merry Christmas Eve!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/east-coast-comfort-food&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/east-coast-comfort-food&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put this track together from just three samples&amp;hellip; a drum break&amp;hellip; an acoustic bass&amp;hellip; and a piano melody. Nothing too fancy, but I wanted to spend the time today making different patterns from the different samples and then mixing it up and seeing how it came together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not exactly stoked by the track itself, but it does feel like it is worth taking the time to make a few change ups this way, even if I&amp;rsquo;m limited to doing a track a day. Honestly, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too much more work, and I think where the results worked&amp;hellip; well they did work out well. It&amp;rsquo;s just that I need to make the time to do it. Normally for these daily tracks I have been trying to just get one 4 or 8 bar chunk sounding &amp;ldquo;just right&amp;rdquo;, but then I end up trying to make it sound interesting by dropping sections, building, etc&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Fortress of Self</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/22/jamcember-fortress-of-self/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 14:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1472</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mixing it up a bit for the twenty second track&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/fortress-of-self&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/fortress-of-self&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture comes courtesy of a trip to Munich. Not so much a tourist type of city, but there&amp;rsquo;s a lot to see there. I think that particular shot came from a train ride that I took with my family to go check out the Olympic Stadium out there. It was interesting to see, but kind of sad at the same time to see something that had so much funding and investment put into it that ended up not being kept up and maintained as much as you&amp;rsquo;d hope. I suspect that a lot of the Olympic areas around the world are like this, and I suppose when things get back to normal I will have to travel around to check out more for myself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - New Found Glory</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/21/jamcember-new-found-glory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 16:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1465</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is Monday the 21st, and that means it is time for the 21st track!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/new-found-glory&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/new-found-glory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is from my trip to Athens Greece with some filters on it. Nothing fancy, but the statue was incredible to see in person. It&amp;rsquo;s made out of plexiglass or glass and stacked up to look like a person. We walked by the statue quite a bit for our family trip, and would definitely go there again!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Tea In The Dark</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/20/jamcember-tea-in-the-dark/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 23:58:28 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1455</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day twenty&amp;hellip; I can feel that the end of jamcember is nearing :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/tea-in-the-dark&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/tea-in-the-dark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I went back to the now &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo; standard of making some loops in Reason Studio, working on some sound design to get some interesting sounds, and then bouncing the loops out to be chopped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few things I tried to switch it up. First, I made four bar loops, but extended them out to eight bars, because I wanted the ambience to flow through to the start of the first bar, instead of hearing the loop in the first bar kind of catch up. Something sounds a bit off&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s possible that I have an LFO that is not sync&amp;rsquo;d to the track, or maybe my copy/paste of notes was bad. I tried it&amp;hellip; and while it didn&amp;rsquo;t work quite how I wanted, well&amp;hellip; it still produced results.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Sudden Death</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/19/jamcember-sudden-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 22:23:41 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1448</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The nineteenth day is upon me&amp;hellip; and I called &amp;ldquo;Sudden Death&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/sudden-death&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/sudden-death&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is in fact no death, but I named it as such because I really don&amp;rsquo;t have much time left for the rest of the day, and had to pull something together in about 30 minutes. So instead of doing sound design in reason, today I just loaded up a pre-made drum kit&amp;hellip; from &amp;lsquo;LoFi Soul and Future Beats&amp;rsquo; and just went to town to knock it out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - The Long Way</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/18/jamcember-the-long-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 15:40:58 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1437</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Eighteen days, it&amp;rsquo;s been eighteen days, dropping a beat every day, so many ways&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/the-long-way&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/the-long-way&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track&amp;hellip; I am still making loops in Reason Studio and looping them&amp;hellip; this might be the last one for the month&amp;hellip; not because I don&amp;rsquo;t like the results, but just so I can experiment with some other track making techniques&amp;hellip; or who knows&amp;hellip; go back to finishing off some older tracks. The next few days we shall see.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Where Will I Find You</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/17/jamcember-where-will-i-find-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 01:10:09 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1430</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day&amp;hellip; Seventeen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/where-will-i-find-you&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/where-will-i-find-you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just like this track&amp;hellip; guess I have nothing else to say about it today :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay&amp;hellip; I was being lazy yesterday&amp;hellip; cleaning up after the blizzard kind of got to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this track I really decided to pair down the frantic energy and focus a bit more on natural sounding instruments with some air, space, and environment to them. As I said yesterday, I am quite happy about how it came out, though mixing was a bit of a pain due to how different the levels were on all of the tracks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Yeeting It</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/16/jamcember-yeeting-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 17:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1421</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sixteen days feels like more time making a track a day than it really is :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/yeeting-it&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/yeeting-it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture comes courtesy of my wife&amp;rsquo;s hand while we were visiting in Bangalore last year and she asked to get some Henna artwork done on her hand. Had a great time out there and would love to go back. The food was incredible!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the track, probably approaching the last days during this month of pulling content off of Reason Studio daily and then chopping up loops for inspiration, so I&amp;rsquo;ll be looking around for another sound source or two for the month just to push myself in other directions. I&amp;rsquo;ve been itching to do some sound recording, and who knows, maybe I go industrial?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Why Are You Here</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/15/jamcember-why-are-you-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 12:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1415</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fifteen fifteen fifteen fifteen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/why-are-you-here&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/why-are-you-here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still having a blast making loops in Reason and exporting it out to the MPC for chopping up. This track had a lot going on with it, and I had fun making the initial four bars&amp;hellip; but once I got started tracking it out into a song things really went sideways. The transitions just didn&amp;rsquo;t work and the track started to fall apart. I think it was more a case of a few different sounds just not supporting each other very well and while I was having fun making the four bar loop it wasn&amp;rsquo;t obvious, but when trying to put transitions together it became a bit jarring.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Welcome Tangerine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/14/jamcember-welcome-tangerine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 22:53:43 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1408</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Has it already been fourteen tracks?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/welcome-tangerine&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/welcome-tangerine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track needed some mixing love, I tried to nail it, but I still think the saw synth is a bit intense. Perhaps this is what the track needed? I&amp;rsquo;m not sure. After this many tracks can I really be sure of anything?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I am sure that all of the content was yet again produced in Reason Studio, and I ran it through the Yorgos Arabatzsis Mastering. I&amp;rsquo;m getting a bit more of a handle with both making loops in Reason Studio 11, and working with YAM to get the sounds I am looking for, and pushing the sounds I don&amp;rsquo;t like back.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Faerie Dust</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/13/jamcember-faerie-dust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 14:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1401</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The thirteen day is upon us, and it is good&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/faerie-dust&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/faerie-dust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another track that I spent some time putting together four bar loops in Reason Studio 11 in order to get some content that I could chop up and mangle in the MPC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything too special about the chops, but the bass line was played out a bit wonky to start, and I just kind of went with it. The first two bars are super simple, and then the last two bars get a lot more complex. From there, I built a lot of the melody and chords around it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Hello Sputnik/Goodbye Sputnik</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/12/jamcember-hello-sputnik-goodbye-sputnik/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 15:09:27 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1391</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the twelfth day, there was two&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/hello-sputnik&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/hello-sputnik&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/goodbye-sputnik&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/goodbye-sputnik&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track was a ton of fun to put together. I wanted to change my perspective on making tracks this month, and decided to focus on chopping up samples, but 100% making my own content. So this project started as a deep dive into Reason Studio 11 to really really really get into some sound design. I knew I wanted to go glitchy and spacey, and I think I pretty well delivered on those themes in this track. So all drum patterns, loops, everything were initially created in a 30 minute session in Reason, and then I bounced and exported six tracks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Depth of Ra</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/09/jamcember-depth-of-ra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 22:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1371</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The ninth day of December has yielded the ninth track of the month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/depth-of-ra&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/depth-of-ra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track was put together using only the plugins and fx available from the MPC Live in standalone mode, so no samples, loops, or any other audio content. I wanted to see what I could put together using the new drum machine, electric, tube, and bass plugins to put something together. A few of the tracks I really drizzled on the delay and feedback, and I tossed a gated filter for good measure. So, today was the creation of a totally new beat out of the box, and just seeing where it would take me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Smoke and Scotch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/08/jamcember-smoke-and-scotch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 13:24:18 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1362</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rise and shine! Is it day eight already?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/smoke-and-scotch&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/smoke-and-scotch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well I am certainly embarrassed. Instead of going through &amp;ldquo;weeks old&amp;rdquo; tracks, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d dig deep and see what gems might be out there that are a year or more old&amp;hellip; and I found this little number. Out of the box it was nearly ready to go, and for the life of me I could not tell you why I never got around to just putting a bow on it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - This Is My House</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/07/jamcember-this-is-my-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 20:44:25 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1352</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seventh day, strong day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/this-is-my-house&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/this-is-my-house&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a picture of my house when I first bought it. My daughter used to call it potato brown. My wife and I have done so much work on this place over the years, and are in the process of moving into another house. I&amp;rsquo;ll miss this house, but it was my first house, and it&amp;rsquo;ll hold a special place for me and my family!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Powerful Feeling</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/06/jamcember-powerful-feeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1341</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to day numero six. I started this little number about two weeks ago&amp;hellip; just before I wanted to try and put out a track a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/powerful-feeling&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/powerful-feeling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is&amp;hellip; probably eight years old now? There were some monks making mandalas in my home town and I have some interesting videos of the work they did. The level of concentration is impressive to put together these images, and you can see they are using masks to make sure the do not disturb the sand while they are making the picture. It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty cool process, and it was fun to watch. My daughter got a kick out of it, and I have a video where one of the monks helped her make her own tiny image out of sand.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - From Left Field</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/05/jamcember-from-left-field/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 14:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1331</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s day five already&amp;hellip; and I pulled together another track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/from-left-field&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/from-left-field&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The painting is a water color that I did years ago&amp;hellip; probably over fifteen years ago. I happened to find it while going through my old notebooks looking for some blank paper. It&amp;rsquo;s not that great, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be using the other side to do some paintings for a project I am working on with my sister. So long sort of interesting tree and wild&amp;hellip; what is that&amp;hellip; a sunset?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Unbalanced Balance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/03/jamcember-unbalanced-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 17:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1309</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 3&amp;hellip; still at it :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/unbalanced-balance&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/unbalanced-balance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This started as a four bar loop about two or three weeks ago on my Akai MPC Live mk2, and I just left the main loop running for like an hour and didn&amp;rsquo;t get sick of it. The drums were all on the same track and I did need to separate those out, but beyond that I had a good enough mind to keep the bass, wurli, and sitar sounds on their own tracks, so it wasn&amp;rsquo;t overwhelming to dig in and actually start making different sections of the song.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - My Peaceful Day</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/01/jamcember-my-peaceful-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 17:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1297</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First track for #jamcember and trying to do a track a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/my-peaceful-day&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/my-peaceful-day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a lofi track to relax to. Yeah I know it&amp;rsquo;s kind of noisy&amp;hellip; as the lofi folks like? A lot of vinyl, tape, and other random clicks and clacks. All done on the MPC Live mk2. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably keep all of the tracks done through the MPC Live mk2 this month just to really dig into it a bit more and see if 2.9 has either weird workflow bugs I trip over or things that get me to think about working on the tracks differently inside the box.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
