<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Access-Virus-Ti2-Darkstar on NearTao&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/access-virus-ti2-darkstar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Access-Virus-Ti2-Darkstar on NearTao&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 00:30:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/access-virus-ti2-darkstar/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Feeling of Falling Down</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/20/jamuary2021-feeling-of-falling-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 00:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1818</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 20 and I just went for more ambient&amp;hellip; so veg out a bit and see where it takes you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/feeling-of-falling-down&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/feeling-of-falling-down&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture comes courtesy of my back yard. Well I sold my house, so technically now it is the new owner&amp;rsquo;s back yard, but I am currently still living here. Setup a lease back arrangement while I am waiting on the new place. About a month to a month and a half to go&amp;hellip; and believe me, I am ready&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s about time to get my damn music studio back together so I can get access to sounds that I want when I want them. That said, it&amp;rsquo;s been quite nice to be working with a greatly reduced set of sound sources&amp;hellip; so it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been an issue by any stretch of the imagination.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Almost There</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/16/jamuary2021-almost-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 16:51:46 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1736</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 16&amp;hellip; it may be cold outside but it is getting warm in here&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/almost-there&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/almost-there&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is a chocolate cake we had for Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day&amp;hellip; really good&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure my wife picked it up at Whole Foods&amp;hellip; if I remember correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the track it&amp;rsquo;s another mix of chops and synths&amp;hellip; and auto sampling&amp;hellip; and mistakes. I spent a lot of time looking for sounds that I felt would work together, so this track feels pretty good. Normally I&amp;rsquo;d upload the auto sampled synth&amp;hellip; but it has echo in it&amp;hellip; making me have to record every single note for the group, and then this makes it hard to use outside of a 96bpm standpoint&amp;hellip; as well&amp;hellip; it also only works for the notes I sampled which&amp;hellip; put it in the rather not so useful category for a general standpoint. I may try and find a good delay/reverb match to make it into a generic MPC patch&amp;hellip; but for now it just felt kind of strange to upload something so rigid and honestly kind of single purpose.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Awkward Forgiveness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/15/jamuary2021-awkward-forgiveness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1723</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fifteen tracks for January&amp;hellip; woo!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/awkward-forgiveness&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/awkward-forgiveness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture&amp;hellip; I believe is from Disney, from the animal park resort. I am pretty sure I mentioned how much my daughter loved that trip. We had a blast, and it was great to see all of the different animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track is a mix of chops, and synths. I started by chopping up a break, and then moved on to finding some guitar sounds to fill out some of what I thought was going to be a lead and the bass&amp;hellip; but well&amp;hellip; the bass sound was decidedly not inspiring&amp;hellip; and I kind of drowned up the guitar sound in a lot of this track with some of the synths (whoops). So not the end of the world, and something that could be patched up with some mixing, but my intent here was to work on keeping things in key, or as in key as I could without totally knowing what I was doing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Come on Over</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/11/jamuary2021-come-on-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 17:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1686</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Trying to pull things I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning over the last month and a half together into a more coherent type of track&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/come-on-over&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/come-on-over&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is from one of my trips to the Czech Republic&amp;hellip; forget when&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s definitely a lot of stunning architecture out there, and absolutely worth checking out. About a third of the organization that I used to manage was out there, so I&amp;rsquo;d probably be out there two to three times a year to check in on everybody, see how things were going, get feedback, and make sure the the remote team members knew that I was a living and breathing human being.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Old Haunts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/10/jamuary2021-old-haunts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 14:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1680</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day ten&amp;hellip; was on a roll&amp;hellip; and then I fell off :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/old-haunts&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/old-haunts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image is from a trip years ago that we took our daughter to the Boston Commons and is of the paddle boat that you can take a little tour around the duck pond. Our daughter was never super excited to get on the boat, and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure we ever did at that age, now she&amp;rsquo;s probably too old to think it would be something fun to do. Honestly, having done the ride before myself, it&amp;rsquo;s a little pricey, and you don&amp;rsquo;t really get too much excitement out of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Long Voyage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/09/jamuary2021-long-voyage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 18:23:27 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1666</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alright back again messing with TraTraTra Transpose!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/long-voyage&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/long-voyage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boy, the picture is from about four years ago&amp;hellip; Amy is looking impressively squinty&amp;hellip; might have been from the flash, I don&amp;rsquo;t really recall. Looked like a goofy enough picture to work with for today&amp;rsquo;s track though. She&amp;rsquo;s watching you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I took my own personal advice from yesterday and only applied transposes to the track level, and not the sequence level of the song. I figured that way I&amp;rsquo;m not having drums hop all over the place and can have some more control over what is going on. It was a little bit more work, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t insurmountable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - My Time Here is Done</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/08/jamuary2021-my-time-here-is-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 18:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1654</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The track was named as such&amp;hellip; because I threw my hands up in desperation. *not* a good track, but I did learn something&amp;hellip; but first&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/my-time-here-is-done&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/my-time-here-is-done&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the picture comes courtesy of the dang thing that the MPC Live did to twist up my song.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/f7a5f8df-cb19-42c9-b42a-304d5e1d45a1%5F1%5F105%5Fc.jpeg?w=1024&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, above is the drum track&amp;hellip; but let me explain how I got there&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I figured I would play around with transpose on sequence mode&amp;hellip; just do a pattern of I/IV/I/V&amp;hellip; (or no semitone offset, +4 semitone offset, no semitone offset, +5 semitone offset). With me so far? I basically just copied my main sequence twice, second sequence I put a +4 semitone transpose on the sequence, and for the third sequence I put a +5 semitone transpose on the sequence. I then went to song mode and just did the pattern Seq 1, Seq 2, Seq 3, Seq 4&amp;hellip; and then converted the whole thing back into a sequence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Hamburgled</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/07/jamuary2021-hamburgled/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 15:13:25 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1640</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That dang squirrel&amp;hellip; taking my food!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/hamburled&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/hamburled&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting this track together was fun&amp;hellip; but I did struggle a bit (again) with audio tracks, external midi, and exporting the file. I know I grumbled about this before, but Akai really needs to get an ability to mix in from the inputs for a track if/when you need to. I suppose posting everything to audio tracks is fine, but the workflow is just wonky to me. I&amp;rsquo;ll quit my belly aching on it, but it did lead to a bit of a mess uploading a track that was missing a core synth part. On the pro soundcloud account it&amp;rsquo;s not a *huge* problem to replace a track, but boy was it funny to go back and listen to the track and notice it was missing. It&amp;rsquo;s something I can fix in my on process for creating and publishing songs, but&amp;hellip; well&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s a hassle. Also&amp;hellip; to be fair, even if there was a checkbox to use external gear to get it in from the inputs I&amp;rsquo;d probably still complain about it being a problem because then I&amp;rsquo;d probably double up sounds, or cause myself other problems. Maybe it is fine Akai? Maybe! This is just something that&amp;rsquo;s been such an ingrained workflow in DAWs though, that it does lead me to at least one area where the MPC in standalone isn&amp;rsquo;t quite enough as a DAW. Everything inside the box it is cool, but exporting out content it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work quite so hot. /grumbling off&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Data Repeater</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/06/jamuary2021-data-repeater/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 19:25:25 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1630</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just spent most of the day doing small things&amp;hellip; so figured I&amp;rsquo;d wrap this turkey up :D&#39;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/data-repeater&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/data-repeater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is from some resin structures we made as a family this year. My dad was all about how copper killed COVID or something silly, so he sent us some. I didn&amp;rsquo;t buy into it, and I don&amp;rsquo;t think he did either, but we ended up all doing remote family molds to just try and make something interesting. I had never poured resin like this before, so it was interesting at least to see the process up close and personal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Silent Grace</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/05/jamuary2021-silent-grace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 15:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1623</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day five&amp;hellip; and I am still alive!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/silent-grace&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/silent-grace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture comes from a Barnum and Bailey Circus show that we brought our daughter to. She loved it. Definitely was weird though&amp;hellip; we were near the front of the stadium and these massive and majestic creatures still looked so small. We offered our daughter to go see them up close after the show, but I think she was three at the time and was terrified to get anywhere near them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Method of Attack</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/04/jamuary2021-method-of-attack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 15:09:12 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1606</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day four is a bit more rocking today. Went in a kind of house/trance direction&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/method-of-attack&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/method-of-attack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture comes from a trip to Disney World that my wife and I took our daughter to for her third birthday. She doesn&amp;rsquo;t remember the trip at all today, but at the time she had a blast. When she was younger she was quite a clingy kid, and I can still remember how sore my shoulders were because she refused to walk anywhere and instead wanted to ride on my shoulders for the entire trip. Do not recommend&amp;hellip; the shoulder part&amp;hellip; the Disney trip was great :D&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Mad Cap</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/03/jamuary2021-mad-cap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 20:22:21 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1598</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day three&amp;rsquo;s track is in the house!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/mad-cap&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/mad-cap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image comes courtesy of one of my wife&amp;rsquo;s trips to New York City with her friends years ago. I repurposed it for my track&amp;hellip; hopefully she doesn&amp;rsquo;t mind :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned yesterday that I started working on this track yesterday right after throwing in the towel for day two, and I really dig how this track came out. I decided to keep the flow super short, so it is just a Main section, Drop section, and Outro section&amp;hellip; so absolutely nothing fancy, but I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like it needed much else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Biggest Regret</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/02/jamuary-2021-biggest-regret/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 20:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1590</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day two of #jamuary 2021&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/biggest-regret&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/biggest-regret&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture comes courtesy of my daughter finding a frog in the backyard over the summer and we caught a few pictures of it. She was super excited to have found such a small critter hanging out in the back yard and just wanted to get a few close ups of the little guy (or gal).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fiddled with this track a bit throughout the day and it never quite came together the way I wanted. I tried to play everything out by hand as much as possible, and well&amp;hellip; I find it okay. The transitions between sections are particularly week again, and I know I could have done better to build up more energy if I had just had the time. Instead I decided to cut my losses on this track and move forward to preparing for day three instead&amp;hellip; which meant this track suffered.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Requiem for a Soul</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/01/jamuary2021-requiem-for-a-soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 21:08:45 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1577</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well it looks like I am back for another month of jamming out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/requiem-for-a-soul&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/requiem-for-a-soul&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, the picture is of my oldest dog, Amy (pronounced Emmy). I was trying to find a picture that might feel a little dreamy, where you might not quite know what was going on, was maybe a little shocking, but not really in the terrifying space. This was a picture from taking Amy home from being spayed, and we had to put the cone on her head to keep her from licking the wound. She is by no means intimidating, and is actually one of the sweetest dogs you could find, but this picture does make her look a little haunted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Ninth Circle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/31/jamcember-ninth-circle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 18:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1568</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s to slugging out the last track for December, and heading into the new year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/ninth-circle&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/ninth-circle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track came about from creating an audio track from a 32 bar loop on the Access Virus TI2 Darkstar. I automated a few parameters and figured it sound cool enough to add some drums and FX to it. I wanted to try and get something slower and more droning this time around, instead of some of the faster and more manic tracks I have been laying down the last month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamcember - Deeply Stricken</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/30/jamcember-deeply-stricken/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 23:57:48 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1561</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The second of two remaining tracks for the month!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/deeply-stricken&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/deeply-stricken&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this track has several key groups that I auto sampled off of both my Access Virus TI2 Darkstar and Waldorf Iridium. I figured I&amp;rsquo;d upload the patches for those interested or who are just looking for some synth sounds to play with&amp;hellip; so you can get them below. I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother trimming anything&amp;hellip; so the file is a bit large&amp;hellip; but go nuts and have fun!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
