<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Health on NearTao&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Health on NearTao&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 21:27:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/health/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wrist Update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/05/06/wrist-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 21:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2747</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the picture that&amp;rsquo;s not real smoke/steam, but boy does it feel like there is something going on in my wrist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saw a nurse practitioner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty sure it&amp;rsquo;s not CTS. I noticed a lump on my wrist now that the swelling is down a bit&amp;hellip; and it is likely I&amp;rsquo;ve got a ganglion cyst near my palm attached to one of the tendons. I can feel it is a bit mushy on the tendon, and it moves when I move my fingers. It&amp;rsquo;s quite possible that this additional mass is pushing on some of the veins, and it&amp;rsquo;s likely also getting caught up on my other tendons when I move my hand.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unsubscribing from Podcasts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/10/05/unsubscribing-from-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 12:32:06 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1037</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know about others, but I have picked up quite a collection of Podcasts that I have subscribed to over the years. This has resulted in many hours spent listening to story telling, comedy, news, educational, and a whole slew of other topics. With the pandemic, and the shift in how I use my time, I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the time while driving to sit down and really listen, which has resulted in a massive backlog of nearly a hundred hours of unlisted to podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pulling It Back Together</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/08/25/pulling-it-back-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 18:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=932</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t know about other folks out there, but the way the world has changed over the last few months just seems like another planet. My wife and I are doing everything we can to keep our daughter in as socially normal atmosphere as possible, but we’re really keeping to ourselves otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been weird too, because just as COVID-19 broke out I was starting a new job, getting ready to meet new people, and drive new projects. My job is fully online now, which is a larger change than I anticipated. Previously I was traveling a lot, getting together with people to make sure we were moving products, and overall very highly connected. Now I am keeping people focused in meetings, helping get programs on the rails or stay on the rails,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Picking Up the Pace</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/07/21/picking-up-the-pace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 15:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=712</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The picture is courtesy of a family of six foxes that have been living in our back yard for the last two seasons. We&amp;rsquo;ve been seeing them around for five or six years now. Definitely our suburban outdoor pets now. We&amp;rsquo;re not feeding them directly or anything&amp;hellip; but they are certainly enjoying all of the wildlife that our bird feeders and gardens attract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on just walking faster&amp;hellip; I know, sounds silly, but the effort is really keeping my heart rate up higher. I used to get shin splints from running, and I&amp;rsquo;m just trying to keep this activity as low impact as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Not closing move rings...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/07/13/not-closing-move-rings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 14:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=694</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So here is a bit of a quandary for me. About a week and a half ago I hit a 59 day streak for closing all of the rings on the Apple Watch, and then it stopped. In the last two weeks I have not been closing all of my rings despite my exercise right being frequently over flowing. What is going on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent some time thinking about this and if I should be upset with myself or not. I had been really looking to get healthier over the last few months, and boy do I feel like I have in some ways disappointed myself by not closing all of the rings. As with many things in life though, I had to spend some time considering why this may not be the case.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Step to This</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/07/03/step-to-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 13:24:41 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=639</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I hit a 53 day move/stand/exercise streak, and I am not going to lie to you, mentally it has not gotten too much easier than it has been. Meaning, I am still doing my best to get up and move around, but there continue to be days where I do question how important this is to me. I guess it is more philosophical in some ways, because yeah, I know this is important for my health, but a big question that keeps coming up for me is why. Why do I want or need to be healthier? Do I need to loose weight? How much better shape do I need to be in? These questions are certainly all normal, and I do have the answers to them for myself, but I&amp;rsquo;m finding it important to remind myself more often.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Longest Move Streak</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/06/25/longest-move-streak/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 13:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=611</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The picture is of my dog Amy, she loves sun bathing after long walks. She just had her sixth birthday, so she deserves a little downtime now and then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, today I hit a longest move streak of 45 days. That is probably 40 more days than any of my previous move streaks. I will admit, there have been a few days in there where I just didn&amp;rsquo;t want to exercise. I had a late start, maybe got a mile into walking, and by the time I got home with the heat I just didn&amp;rsquo;t want to go out again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Walking the Dogs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/06/20/walking-the-dogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 15:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=563</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve still been taking the dogs out on walks with me, and trying to get both of them at least a mile a day. The oldest pooch Amy continues to be super stubborn. The first eighth of a mile she just stops. Today I took a picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/62bd7513-1b0d-484e-8ab3-f0a9f5199f80_1_105_c.jpeg?w=1024&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No more walks dad!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have tried a couple of tactics to change this behavior, and so far have not had any success.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exercise Update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/06/18/exercise-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 17:21:35 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=581</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to the health app, I now have a 38 day streak of exercise! Two weeks ago I was complaining about just feeling sore everywhere, and now I feel sore in just a few muscles when I push myself for walks. And walk I have, I am still managing 2-3 miles on average a day, and I feel great. Getting through the spring allergy season is always brutal for me, but I made it through the worst of my allergies. Go me!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Still Streaking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/06/04/still-streaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 14:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=494</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I hit twenty four days of closing the workout rings on my Apple Watch in a row yesterday. The rings are Move - 740 calories, Exercise - 30 minutes, and Stand - 12 hours. I&amp;rsquo;ve found a roughly two to three mile walk will get me there for the day, and takes me about 30-40 minutes to complete. I can also hit the Calories goal with about twenty minutes of running, but that has been a bit rougher for me. My allergies kick in, and I have work induced asthma. I&amp;rsquo;ll work through it better in the future, but as it has warmed up and gotten more humid outside, I haven&amp;rsquo;t really wanted to run.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thinking About Habits</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/05/31/thinking-about-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 22:45:06 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=483</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a lot more self reflective lately, and I can definitely understand people getting stuck in their own heads through all of this self isolation. Right now I&amp;rsquo;m focussed on two things&amp;hellip; breaking old habits&amp;hellip; and making new habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**Breaking Habits&lt;br&gt;
**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Caffeine&amp;hellip; while it&amp;rsquo;s nice&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to get out and get energy drinks and soda every day, and I do not want it in the house&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming&amp;hellip; was spending a *lot* of time just playing video games&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Waiting for &lt;strong&gt;something&lt;/strong&gt; to happen&amp;hellip; a lot of time was wasted just waiting for somebody else to do stuff with me&amp;hellip; now I just say &amp;ldquo;good to go&amp;rdquo; and they are either with me or not&amp;hellip; no judging&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**Making Habits&lt;br&gt;
**&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Motivated Exercising</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/05/30/keeping-motivated-exercising/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 17:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=474</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have hit 20 consecutive days now of closing all three rings on my Apple Watch, and I am wondering how much further I will go. To skip a day or two is not that bad, especially when I go back and check out my move data from the last two years. I think I broke my move streak of what was three, or maybe it was five for the first time this month. Sure, it is a little sad that I had not been consistently exercising, but it is what I am doing today that is important.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activity Update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/05/28/activity-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=458</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As many of you have experienced with social distancing and stay at home orders, it is still hard to keep moving. I am used to getting a lot of movement in from work, but from staying at home I had been finding myself being a bit of a couch potato and just sitting in my chair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m at week two of allowing my Apple Watch to remind me to keep moving. Normally I have been ignoring the &amp;ldquo;you can do it messages&amp;rdquo;, especially when they come in at 10pm, but the last two weeks I have filled all those silly circles every day. You know what? I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to make a habit of it. Honestly, it&amp;rsquo;s taken this kind of drastic change in my life to see that I need to take a more active role in my personal health, and I do have more free time because I don&amp;rsquo;t have to drive to work every day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Staying Active</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/05/21/staying-active/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 15:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=428</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I suspect I am not alone in this, but I checked my weight a few weeks back, and I&amp;rsquo;ll say I was not shocked to have gained a few pounds when I checked my weight on the scale. Still, it didn&amp;rsquo;t exactly make me happy when this is usually the season I&amp;rsquo;m dropping a bit of weight from going outside and hiking, doing outdoor projects, or just walking around the neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Distanced Gaming</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/05/15/social-distancing-gaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 13:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=418</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just writing this for families that, like mine are separated by distance, and are looking for some ways to be able to socially interact together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When getting together with my extended family, we&amp;rsquo;ve always had a blast playing board games and video games together. Given the current state of social distancing and the miles we are away from each other, it has effectively become impossible to see each other in person.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life Sometimes...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/12/31/life-sometimes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 17:35:43 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=251</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my dogs got super sick, and needed a trip to the emergency room. She&amp;rsquo;s doing well now, but it was pretty touch and go for a couple of weeks. The worst thing was that she just was not interested in eating, and she lost a lot of weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/cc89b23b-f8dc-491e-855b-69d143a9ae36%5F1%5F105%5Fc.jpeg?w=1024&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As other pet owners know, the doggie cone of shame sucks. Fortunately we didn&amp;rsquo;t have to use it this time, but we did need to get her the inflatable neck brace to keep her from losing stitches. I was concerned she was going to hate it, but apparently having a portable pillow around your neck at all times is nice because she found the strangest places to get comfortable and go to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
