<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Pocket-Operator on NearTao&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/pocket-operator/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pocket-Operator on NearTao&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:27:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/pocket-operator/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #06 - Something</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/06/beatober2021-06-something/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:27:56 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3347</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And now for something completely different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uFkvE6DVNqs?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I just decided to do what I could with the pocket operators I have on hand&amp;hellip; PO-32, PO-33, PO-35&amp;hellip; and see what would come from it. I&amp;rsquo;ll definitely get back to the MPC Live and Eurorack, but just needed a change of pace for a bit. Probably will do another PO track or two for the time being and go for something a bit longer, I suspect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No More Technology - #Jamuary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/01/11/no-more-technology-jamuary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 21:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=349</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No eurorack modules were harmed in the making of this video. The PO-32 (Tonic) makes up the drums, the PO-35 (Voice) is how I got the &amp;ldquo;No More Technology&amp;rdquo; hook, and&amp;hellip; the lead/bass came from some Eurorack mess. I recorded all of this into Ableton Live for some FX processing. All of this was recorded back in October/November, and I&amp;rsquo;ve meant to create a finished track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of #Jamuary though, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d break out some gear and refine the track a bit more. I&amp;rsquo;m really trying to cap myself to about 30-60 minutes of production time this month for each song. This is good in some ways because it&amp;rsquo;s forcing me to get ideas down, but it is bad in a few other ways since I&amp;rsquo;m really not mixing/mastering anything. Leaving this track with a bit more of a tinny sound than I&amp;rsquo;d like, but hey it is what it is.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Its my Jam - PO-33 Track</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/01/10/its-my-jam-po-33-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=340</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The image is courtesy of a road trip I did with my family from the East Coast out to Montana. On the way back we stopped at an amethyst mine, and I got some really cool pictures of some older beat up vehicles. There was some really cool stuff going on here, and we got some neat amethyst crystals to bring back home with us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the song, nothing too fancy here, just using samples of thumps and bumps from everyday objects. A lot of the magic is just pitching things up and down, using filters&amp;hellip; and then just jamming it out. I&amp;rsquo;m going to stick with the PO-33 a bit longer, but a lot of the initial magic playing around with the FX again is a bit gone, it has now gone from being novel to producing some pretty similar sounds to my ear. The device is still fantastic, and it might just be time for me start considering what I am going to move on to for a device to keep going on making tracks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glass Mythology - PO-33 Track</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/01/09/glass-mythology-po-33-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=330</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The image comes courtesy of a business trip to Bangalore. The pool with the blue lights looked amazing so I had to take a picture. I&amp;rsquo;ll have to keep an eye out for more of these eye catching images&amp;hellip; and maybe I can do a better job getting a &amp;ldquo;live&amp;rdquo; photo on my phone&amp;hellip; or a video&amp;hellip; so I can work out some neat video tricks versus just having a video of me clicking on guitar pedals and such.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Afternoon Breeze - PO-33 Track</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/01/08/afternoon-breeze-po-33-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=317</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The image is from my daughter. While we took a trip out to Montana she kept borrowing my phone to take strange pictures with odd filters. This is one of many featuring one of our dogs. It looked intense enough to be a good track image. Enjoy the image of my dog slowly zooming in while listening to a electro song plays!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funny thing&amp;hellip; I was going to do another house track, and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I&amp;rsquo;d place it quite in that genre, is it electro house? I don&amp;rsquo;t think it is fast enough for Techno&amp;hellip; Somebody who has more refined taste might be able to clarify the music genre for me. I just thought it sounded cool!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winter Happiness - PO-33 Track</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/01/07/winter-happiness-po-33-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 18:40:30 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=308</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I used some Washi tape to label the write and record on the PO-33 on the case. I keep pushing the wrong one and deleting samples or otherwise overwriting stuff I don&amp;rsquo;t want to. I&amp;rsquo;m just not keeping the two clear in my mind. Also, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t help that the write button with the white dot reminds me of a record button&amp;hellip; but yeah, it is still me! :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently I&amp;rsquo;m really sticking with one or two drum loops, some vocals chopped up by and amateur (well the PO-33), an instrument sound, and maybe a bass sound. I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to do something different to push myself to not fall into a track. And&amp;hellip; This track fell out of the sky! Well rather, I just recorded off some more samples to see what I could do to push the PO-33 a bit more. By pushing, I mostly mean doing even more FX and changing the FX up more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Tiny House - PO 33 Track</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/01/07/my-tiny-house-po-33-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 02:12:54 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=301</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had intended in jamming out on the MPC today, but I ended up grabbing the PO 33 again&amp;hellip; Producing another small track. Seriously folks, I am surprised at how much big sound can come out of such a small device! This is maybe 30 minutes worth of playing around max.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want a laugh, this is maybe seven, max eight, seconds of audio samples. If I actually put the effort in to trim down the wasted space in the drum track, I might be able to get it down to four or five seconds. Honestly, I&amp;rsquo;m not bothered by it, but it really goes to show even with the old school hardware and multiple limitations, those older machines really could knock out some bangers without too much effort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Early Morning Chat - PO-33 Track</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/01/05/early-morning-chat-po-33-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=291</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although I&amp;rsquo;ve been happily selling off gear, I&amp;rsquo;ve still got the Teenage Engineering Pocket Operators I picked up a while back. I was feeling like putting something together super fast, and while I was planning on recording off samples, creating drum programs, all that fun stuff&amp;hellip; I also didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spend too much time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip; I reached for my trusty PO-33 and decided to sample in some beats. Originally I was going to use the internal microphone, but while this is sometimes interesting, there was a bit too much background noise (ie, the kid wouldn&amp;rsquo;t stop singing Frozen songs). I had to use the line in, which honestly does tend to have a fuller sound, the microphone is fine, but often it does lack the bottom end a bit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
