<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Akai-S1000 on NearTao&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/akai-s1000/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Akai-S1000 on NearTao&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 21:16:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/akai-s1000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>S950 and S1000 White Noise and Drum Break Comparison</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/11/27/s950-and-s1000-white-noise-and-drum-break-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 21:16:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1272</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A conversation started on MPC Forums about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mpc-forums.com/viewtopic.php?f=11&amp;amp;t=206423&#34;&gt;MPC &amp;amp; S900/950 Routing Question&lt;/a&gt;. We got into details about how the S900/S950 worked, which then lead into S900/S950 samples sounding more full on the S1000 and later. I ended up taking a stab at sampling both white noise and a drum break on the S950 with a bandwidth of 3000 and 19200, and then playing the notes across the key group to get some samples together. Below is the project and recordings from the S950 and S1000 for your own listening.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Akai S1000 Screen Repair</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/10/07/akai-s1000-screen-repair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 23:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=1064</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I turned on my S1000, to find that the screen backlight was no longer working. Bummer that I had replaced it last year&amp;hellip; but I figured I&amp;rsquo;d take it apart and see if I could get the old girl working again. Just in case, I also bought a replacement display&amp;hellip; so that I could replace that in the event that something went horribly wrong. Stay tuned to learn that yes&amp;hellip; something did go horribly wrong.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Akai S1000 Record Knob Repair</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/05/26/akai-s1000-record-knob-repair/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 21:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=440</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been working on restoring an Akai S1000 that I picked up on eBay, and it has needed some help. To put it nicely the previous owner seems to have let it go, and maintenance was not on the forefront of their mind. Not a big problem per se, but the box it arrived in was a mess, and it was very poorly packed. I don&amp;rsquo;t think that this S1000 had seen much love in a long time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
