<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Stbb-Forever on NearTao&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/stbb-forever/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stbb-Forever on NearTao&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 20:38:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/stbb-forever/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>STBB #705 - Dance Boy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/09/09/stbb-705-dance-boy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 20:38:58 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=995</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/stbb-705-dance-boy&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/stbb-705-dance-boy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another STBB track! We had three tracks to work with this week, and I pulled a little something from all of the tracks. I mostly focussed on trying to sculpt the sounds with some filter to give everything a bit of room. The only sample I pulled from externally was a drum loop that I chopped up to give the drums a bit more depth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I definitely spent more time on this track than I meant to, and it didn&amp;rsquo;t come out as great as I had hoped, but it still sounds kind of fun. Probably got to get back to vocals in STBB tracks if I want to have a chance at competing over there though :D&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - STBB 698 - Security Blanket</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/07/23/track-stbb-698-security-blanket/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 11:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=773</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/stbb-698-security-blanket&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/stbb-698-security-blanket&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I said in the previous post, this track had to come together quite quickly&amp;hellip; and this is maybe at best an hour worth of work. I scrambled to get it together and then added some decorative vocals and a baseline to boot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all seriousness this track is a bit over compressed, you can hear it especially when the hi hats slam into the available headroom. I guess I got too carried away with everything in the short amount of time&amp;hellip; but I got what I got :D.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - STBB #696 - Disco Gummy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/07/07/track-stbb-696-disco-gummy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 18:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=661</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For this week, the drop was what&amp;hellip; 300+ clips. The rules were to use at least three, and you had to put product placement in your track of at least five seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/stbb-696-disco-gummy&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/stbb-696-disco-gummy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the &lt;a href=&#34;https://stbbforever.com/viewtopic.php?f=2&amp;amp;t=701&#34;&gt;STBB Beat Battle #696 Funky-Disco-Trip&lt;/a&gt; I tore threw a bunch of loops that I found interesting to work with, and decided to use Ableton Live this time to put it together. I haven&amp;rsquo;t used Ableton Live a whole lot in the last few years, but I still mostly know my way around, and it&amp;rsquo;s like riding a bicycle right, just hop back on?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - STBB #695 - Running Forever</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/07/01/track-stbb-695-running-forever/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 23:14:35 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=634</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/stbb-695-running-forever&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/stbb-695-running-forever&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track comes courtesy of &lt;a href=&#34;https://stbbforever.com/viewtopic.php?f=2&amp;amp;t=691&amp;amp;sid=7d0cdf19c7200d2c7faafcb7c573a9ee&#34;&gt;STBB Forever BB #695&lt;/a&gt;, there were two tracks to chop up. The rules were effectively to chop whatever, use your own drums, no external instruments, and you needed to drop a change up in the track. I&amp;rsquo;m interested to see what others do this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to the MPC BB this week, I was really crunched for time to work on this. This time however I decided I would just do the track in the PO-33, and make it a quick flip. So I loaded the tracks into the MPC, but didn&amp;rsquo;t even bother chopping on the MPC, I just shuffled the starting point around the tracks and sampled in what ever I wanted to start or stop, and was able to get four or five interesting chops pretty quickly from the first track. For the second track, I just sampled roughly a loop, and let the auto chopper do it&amp;rsquo;s magic, or horrible destruction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
