<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>#Jamuary2021 on NearTao&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/%23jamuary2021/</link>
    <description>Recent content in #Jamuary2021 on NearTao&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 15:42:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/%23jamuary2021/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reflection on #jamuary2021 Challenge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/02/06/reflection-on-jamuary2021-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 15:42:05 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2055</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So… like a lunatic, I just wrapped up two months in a row of making and publishing a track a day.  If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in what I did last month, go check out the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/2020/12/31/reflection-on-jamcember-2020-challenge/&#34;&gt;#jamcember2020&lt;/a&gt; post. My goal was to publish a track to soundcloud, that no matter how good or bad, I was putting something up.  Trust me, there are some stinkers up there, but I also managed to put some content up that I think sounds great and stands on its own pretty well!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Quiet Heart</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/31/jamuary2021-quiet-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 21:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1942</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last day for #jamuary2021&amp;hellip; and I&amp;rsquo;m happy to look towards doing some more music still, but probably at a slower pace so that I can focus on tracks a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/quiet-heart&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/quiet-heart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is of the fire pit that we built&amp;hellip; going to miss it when we move to the new house, but we&amp;rsquo;ll create another one :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The track came together pretty quickly while I was watching my daughter play the sims, make a character of me&amp;hellip; who she promptly made broke, and then I guess I was then homeless. She had my avatar doing a lot of weird things. It makes me wonder what my daughter thinks of me sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Just Be</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/30/jamuary2021-just-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 22:20:39 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1933</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s day 30&amp;hellip; not much of a track&amp;hellip; but maybe it&amp;rsquo;ll grow up some day to be something bigger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/just-be&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/just-be&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a picture of little Zoe&amp;hellip; waiting expectantly to get in the car for a car ride. She&amp;rsquo;s a good girl and deserves as many rides in the car as she can get. Maria Gasolina is her nickname&amp;hellip; she loves to burn that gas :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dunno&amp;hellip; not much to say about the track today. I was trying to get a hip hop/pop (hip pop?) style track going&amp;hellip; and I feel like this is where the track a day is an impediment&amp;hellip; I just need more time to work through it, but I ended up spending about half the day with my parents&amp;hellip; hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen them since before December&amp;hellip; and they only live about 40 or 50 minutes away. Just been a crazy time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Some Class</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/29/jamuary2021-some-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 01:21:57 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1926</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/some-class&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/some-class&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is from my daughter playing piano for a recital. It was&amp;hellip; three years ago now? She&amp;rsquo;s been learning to play piano for five or six years now, and knows far more about playing music than I do. She can sight read, has very good finger posture, and knows her way around the keys. On the other hand, I try and talk to her about sampling, beat making, song structure, and these are things she doesn&amp;rsquo;t know how to do. Occasionally we will talk and bounce ideas off of each other, but she&amp;rsquo;s not into creating songs, just more interested in reproducing them right now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Ethical Bad Boy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/28/jamuary2021-ethical-bad-boy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 21:20:35 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1914</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;28 tracks this month&amp;hellip; and looking forward to a break&amp;hellip; just three more to go :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/ethical-bad-boy&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/ethical-bad-boy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is from years ago&amp;hellip; doing an extended family vacation out in Maine&amp;hellip; Jamaica Point?!? Great area, lots of trees, water, everything you could ask for if you wanted a secluded get away. I believe the place we stayed at was originally a camp, it could sleep probably 25-40 people&amp;hellip; massive/sprawling kitchen&amp;hellip; all that fun stuff. Ended up going out on a boat a lot&amp;hellip; plenty of hikes in the woods. It was fun :D&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Broken Garage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/27/jamuary2021-broken-garage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:33:57 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1908</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For day 27&amp;hellip; I missed the mark&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/broken-garage&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/broken-garage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So not really a garage&amp;hellip; but boy was that toy for my daughter busted. I ended up upgrading it with a bunch of additions like a tiny and working tv inside, fixed up the doorbell, it was a pretty rocking little house. When we got it though, it was broken as heck&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kind of like the song I put together. I was kind of thinking about going for a House track&amp;hellip; and as you listen to it you can tell I kind of split between an acid baseline, and some other sounds in there&amp;hellip; and never really committed to a garage track, or a UK track&amp;hellip; or anything else. It straddles the line, but not in a good way. I suspect I need to burn this track with fire&amp;hellip; but today I had been working on two or three other tracks to started out with&amp;hellip; and just never was happy with anything. I guess not every day can be decent or above.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Listless Nights</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/26/jamuary2021-listless-nights/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 02:12:06 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1900</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 26 was a bit hard to pull together&amp;hellip; several tracks started&amp;hellip; and just couldn&amp;rsquo;t commit to laying it down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/listless-nights&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/listless-nights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is just of the moon in my backyard&amp;hellip; I was trying to test out my camera, and for the purposes of what I was trying to do, well it failed&amp;hellip; or I need to learn more options for how to setup the camera on my phone&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s probably me&amp;hellip; which should be the name for my next bad track.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Heading Out West</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/24/jamuary2021-heading-out-west/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 23:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1865</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 24&amp;hellip; down to the home stretch!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/heading-out-west&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/heading-out-west&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is from&amp;hellip; oh my&amp;hellip; two summers ago now, took a road trip out to Montana with my parents, wife, daughter, and dogs. That&amp;rsquo;s my dad&amp;rsquo;s Jeep, hooked up to the back of the RV and ready to go. That trip was an experience, but I would absolutely do it again given the chance. Was a great opportunity to spend time with the family, just veg out on the road, and see a lot of things I just wouldn&amp;rsquo;t normally get a chance to see. Sometime I should go through the pictures and see if there is anything neat to write about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Foundation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/23/jamuary2021-foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 14:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1857</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 23&amp;hellip; just a handful more to put together to wrap up the month!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/foundation&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/foundation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is from a trip to Puerto Rico&amp;hellip; probably around twenty years ago now. Just a quick snap that I took while driving by the beach. The water down there is amazing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting the track together, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d work on something a bit more experimental, so not quite so traditional drums and sounds, and just see how it came together. Overall, I am relatively happy with it, but the mixing seems off. I spent some time trying to adjust the levels, but I think there&amp;rsquo;s some EQ and filtering that would need to be done to really make the track pop. I did my best by ear, but I got stuck in a few areas where having some visuals to go with the EQ to see where harmonics are probably would have helped be a bit more precise, instead of just using a low pass and high pass filter to just remove sounds completely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Bleeding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/22/jamuary2021-bleeding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 18:47:03 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1848</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 22&amp;hellip; and this is a very noisy DnB track&amp;hellip; so considered yourself warned&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/bleeding&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/bleeding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pictures is of a family friend&amp;rsquo;s dog, that just looked super evil for the day. I might have to play with the picture again, because it could really turn into something special. Not today though&amp;hellip; because it&amp;rsquo;s just about time to start preparing for tomorrow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track is just a straight up noisy DnB track&amp;hellip; I initially wasn&amp;rsquo;t intending to get so gritty but everything just kind of fell into place that way. I had a ton more FX I had layered in, but had a bit of a hard time figuring out if you can automate turning FX on and off (turns out as far as I can tell you cannot).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - You Alright</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/21/jamuary2021-you-alright/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 19:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1833</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 21 was not going to be a happy house track&amp;hellip; but yet&amp;hellip; bring on the bright and happy vibes&amp;hellip; I guess I could use it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/you-alright&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/you-alright&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The painting is from when I used to record art lessons and post them online&amp;hellip; I think I did about 100 episodes, under the title &amp;ldquo;Painting in Five&amp;rdquo;. This particular one was showing how to paint out a rough sketch, and I&amp;rsquo;m quite certain it was based off of the lion from the MCM Grand. At any rate, the idea was to just show people how to quickly get some things down without thinking too much about whether it was good or bad. And now&amp;hellip; about twenty years later, I am doing a track a day just to get myself to put something down. Maybe I should bring back the &amp;ldquo;In Five&amp;rdquo; concept in the blog? I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about it, but haven&amp;rsquo;t committed to anything yet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Feeling of Falling Down</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/20/jamuary2021-feeling-of-falling-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 00:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1818</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 20 and I just went for more ambient&amp;hellip; so veg out a bit and see where it takes you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/feeling-of-falling-down&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/feeling-of-falling-down&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture comes courtesy of my back yard. Well I sold my house, so technically now it is the new owner&amp;rsquo;s back yard, but I am currently still living here. Setup a lease back arrangement while I am waiting on the new place. About a month to a month and a half to go&amp;hellip; and believe me, I am ready&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s about time to get my damn music studio back together so I can get access to sounds that I want when I want them. That said, it&amp;rsquo;s been quite nice to be working with a greatly reduced set of sound sources&amp;hellip; so it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been an issue by any stretch of the imagination.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - High and Tight</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/19/jamuary2021-high-and-tight/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 14:19:08 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1795</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;January 19th&amp;hellip; and on track numero nineteen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/high-and-tight&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/high-and-tight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is from a game of air hockey with my daughter from years ago. Something we used to do a lot at the local kid casino&amp;hellip; but she is too old for that now :D.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The track was made using drums from MPC Tutor&amp;rsquo;s latest drum kit&amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mpc-samples.com/product.php/315/the-underground-crates/&#34;&gt;The Underground Crates&lt;/a&gt;. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for some new drums definitely check it out. I&amp;rsquo;m digging this MPC Expansion so far, and can see it having a lot of mileage. The rest of the track is just a chopped up bass and chopped up guitar sample. Nothing too exciting&amp;hellip; and I had a vocal track with it, but it was just too much. I ended up just going for keeping this track simple and chilled out today&amp;hellip; so it isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly special&amp;hellip; but I really liked how chilled out and fun it sounded.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Piece of Mine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/18/jamuary2021-piece-of-mine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 18:24:43 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1787</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the eighteenth track for #jamuary2021&amp;hellip; only thirteen(?) to go?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/piece-of-mine&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/piece-of-mine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picture is from my dog Amy&amp;hellip; she was totally chilling the other day. Well, honestly, she chills every day! That&amp;rsquo;s her secret, she&amp;rsquo;s always relaxed. Except when the wind is blowing leaves around&amp;hellip; then she&amp;rsquo;s full attack mode. Other than that though, she&amp;rsquo;s conserving her energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For you folks out there not making stuff&amp;hellip; whether it is dope or whack&amp;hellip; come on&amp;hellip; get yourself out there! I&amp;rsquo;m definitely hearing some great stuff coming from folks just trying to put things down, but there&amp;rsquo;s quite a few peeps with a lot of gear just sitting on their laurels. Get your freak on and put something together!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Fears for Tears</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/17/jamuary2021-fears-for-tears/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 17:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1744</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 17&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/fears-for-tears&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/fears-for-tears&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is from a painting I did years ago&amp;hellip; I think I gave it to my mom? *shrug*&amp;hellip; somebody probably still has it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track came together pretty fast. I started with a pretty basic drum beat and bass line, and tweaked the FX, pitch, etc&amp;hellip; a bit to get a bit more of an interesting sound. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t long before I added in the piano. This is just a chopped up loop, and I decided to do something different, and work on make a 32 bar playing of the chops, instead of doing my usual 4 or 8 bar play through and then working with the loops. I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to consider this in the future, as it was both fun to see different ways I could utilize the sample, but I also got a few interesting places I normally wouldn&amp;rsquo;t get to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Almost There</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/16/jamuary2021-almost-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 16:51:46 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1736</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 16&amp;hellip; it may be cold outside but it is getting warm in here&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/almost-there&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/almost-there&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is a chocolate cake we had for Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day&amp;hellip; really good&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure my wife picked it up at Whole Foods&amp;hellip; if I remember correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the track it&amp;rsquo;s another mix of chops and synths&amp;hellip; and auto sampling&amp;hellip; and mistakes. I spent a lot of time looking for sounds that I felt would work together, so this track feels pretty good. Normally I&amp;rsquo;d upload the auto sampled synth&amp;hellip; but it has echo in it&amp;hellip; making me have to record every single note for the group, and then this makes it hard to use outside of a 96bpm standpoint&amp;hellip; as well&amp;hellip; it also only works for the notes I sampled which&amp;hellip; put it in the rather not so useful category for a general standpoint. I may try and find a good delay/reverb match to make it into a generic MPC patch&amp;hellip; but for now it just felt kind of strange to upload something so rigid and honestly kind of single purpose.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Awkward Forgiveness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/15/jamuary2021-awkward-forgiveness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1723</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fifteen tracks for January&amp;hellip; woo!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/awkward-forgiveness&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/awkward-forgiveness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture&amp;hellip; I believe is from Disney, from the animal park resort. I am pretty sure I mentioned how much my daughter loved that trip. We had a blast, and it was great to see all of the different animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track is a mix of chops, and synths. I started by chopping up a break, and then moved on to finding some guitar sounds to fill out some of what I thought was going to be a lead and the bass&amp;hellip; but well&amp;hellip; the bass sound was decidedly not inspiring&amp;hellip; and I kind of drowned up the guitar sound in a lot of this track with some of the synths (whoops). So not the end of the world, and something that could be patched up with some mixing, but my intent here was to work on keeping things in key, or as in key as I could without totally knowing what I was doing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - It is Gone</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/14/jamuary2021-it-is-gone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 18:44:22 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1713</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wooooo&amp;hellip;. as my daughter would say&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/it-is-gone&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/it-is-gone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is from ages ago when we took my daughter to the Friendly Farm to see some animals when she was a toddler I think&amp;hellip; the FX may make the bunny look like it is taking off&amp;hellip; but if we&amp;rsquo;re being real, it was just laying on some concrete and could not care about us. We had no food, so the meat bags weren&amp;rsquo;t of any importance to it :D. Miss the days when she was excited to spend time with me, but now that she&amp;rsquo;s a teenager, well&amp;hellip; she&amp;rsquo;s got other interests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - What The</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/13/jamuary2021-what-the/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 18:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1702</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ooo&amp;hellip; this is bad&amp;hellip; like&amp;hellip; probably the worst thing I threw against the wall&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/what-the&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/what-the&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is a sunrise from the other day while I was on my way to take the dogs out for a walk. It is absolutely the best thing about this track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what happened? Well&amp;hellip; I wanted to try to do some production on a different machine&amp;hellip; and figured I&amp;rsquo;d dig up my MPC 500. You know&amp;hellip; the one I have only goofed around with once in a while over the last few years, so pretty much forgot how to do everything on it that I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Salt in the Wound</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/12/jamuary2021-salt-in-the-wound/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 18:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1695</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day twelve&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/salt-in-the-wound&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/salt-in-the-wound&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to slow the track down here&amp;hellip; and&amp;hellip; well&amp;hellip; I kind of like the sound of it, but you can tell just listening to it I drifted off into some mental space that wasn&amp;rsquo;t so focussed on the track&amp;hellip; I suspect this is what happens for creating a new track a day for a month and a half. I wanted to like it, and I wanted to feel like I was being productive, but instead I felt like I was just slamming content together. Worse, this was me just chopping loops up&amp;hellip; which normally I dig, but I think being the first day back to work, I just kind of got &amp;lsquo;meh&amp;rsquo; about it. Oh well&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s another three weeks to go of this?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Come on Over</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/11/jamuary2021-come-on-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 17:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1686</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Trying to pull things I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning over the last month and a half together into a more coherent type of track&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/come-on-over&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/come-on-over&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is from one of my trips to the Czech Republic&amp;hellip; forget when&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s definitely a lot of stunning architecture out there, and absolutely worth checking out. About a third of the organization that I used to manage was out there, so I&amp;rsquo;d probably be out there two to three times a year to check in on everybody, see how things were going, get feedback, and make sure the the remote team members knew that I was a living and breathing human being.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Old Haunts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/10/jamuary2021-old-haunts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 14:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1680</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day ten&amp;hellip; was on a roll&amp;hellip; and then I fell off :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/old-haunts&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/old-haunts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image is from a trip years ago that we took our daughter to the Boston Commons and is of the paddle boat that you can take a little tour around the duck pond. Our daughter was never super excited to get on the boat, and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure we ever did at that age, now she&amp;rsquo;s probably too old to think it would be something fun to do. Honestly, having done the ride before myself, it&amp;rsquo;s a little pricey, and you don&amp;rsquo;t really get too much excitement out of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Long Voyage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/09/jamuary2021-long-voyage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 18:23:27 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1666</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alright back again messing with TraTraTra Transpose!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/long-voyage&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/long-voyage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boy, the picture is from about four years ago&amp;hellip; Amy is looking impressively squinty&amp;hellip; might have been from the flash, I don&amp;rsquo;t really recall. Looked like a goofy enough picture to work with for today&amp;rsquo;s track though. She&amp;rsquo;s watching you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I took my own personal advice from yesterday and only applied transposes to the track level, and not the sequence level of the song. I figured that way I&amp;rsquo;m not having drums hop all over the place and can have some more control over what is going on. It was a little bit more work, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t insurmountable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Hamburgled</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/07/jamuary2021-hamburgled/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 15:13:25 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1640</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That dang squirrel&amp;hellip; taking my food!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/hamburled&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/hamburled&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting this track together was fun&amp;hellip; but I did struggle a bit (again) with audio tracks, external midi, and exporting the file. I know I grumbled about this before, but Akai really needs to get an ability to mix in from the inputs for a track if/when you need to. I suppose posting everything to audio tracks is fine, but the workflow is just wonky to me. I&amp;rsquo;ll quit my belly aching on it, but it did lead to a bit of a mess uploading a track that was missing a core synth part. On the pro soundcloud account it&amp;rsquo;s not a *huge* problem to replace a track, but boy was it funny to go back and listen to the track and notice it was missing. It&amp;rsquo;s something I can fix in my on process for creating and publishing songs, but&amp;hellip; well&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s a hassle. Also&amp;hellip; to be fair, even if there was a checkbox to use external gear to get it in from the inputs I&amp;rsquo;d probably still complain about it being a problem because then I&amp;rsquo;d probably double up sounds, or cause myself other problems. Maybe it is fine Akai? Maybe! This is just something that&amp;rsquo;s been such an ingrained workflow in DAWs though, that it does lead me to at least one area where the MPC in standalone isn&amp;rsquo;t quite enough as a DAW. Everything inside the box it is cool, but exporting out content it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work quite so hot. /grumbling off&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Data Repeater</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/06/jamuary2021-data-repeater/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 19:25:25 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1630</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just spent most of the day doing small things&amp;hellip; so figured I&amp;rsquo;d wrap this turkey up :D&#39;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/data-repeater&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/data-repeater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is from some resin structures we made as a family this year. My dad was all about how copper killed COVID or something silly, so he sent us some. I didn&amp;rsquo;t buy into it, and I don&amp;rsquo;t think he did either, but we ended up all doing remote family molds to just try and make something interesting. I had never poured resin like this before, so it was interesting at least to see the process up close and personal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamuary2021 - Requiem for a Soul</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/01/jamuary2021-requiem-for-a-soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 21:08:45 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=1577</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well it looks like I am back for another month of jamming out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/requiem-for-a-soul&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/requiem-for-a-soul&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, the picture is of my oldest dog, Amy (pronounced Emmy). I was trying to find a picture that might feel a little dreamy, where you might not quite know what was going on, was maybe a little shocking, but not really in the terrifying space. This was a picture from taking Amy home from being spayed, and we had to put the cone on her head to keep her from licking the wound. She is by no means intimidating, and is actually one of the sweetest dogs you could find, but this picture does make her look a little haunted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
