<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Uncategorized on NearTao&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/uncategorized/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uncategorized on NearTao&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 11:56:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/uncategorized/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Waste My Free Time, My Time is Not Free</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2025/08/05/dont-waste-my-free-time-my-time-is-not-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 11:56:40 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=4127</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Long time folks, I&amp;rsquo;ve mostly moved to YouTube and Patreon&amp;hellip; but *sometimes* I do remember this small corner of the internet. I swear I need to get some tools in place to help me manage all of the stuff I am putting together&amp;hellip; but that requires *more time*&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d rather spend my time actually responding to valuable questions and helping people out than writing a rant like this, but&amp;hellip; here we are&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Uncarved Block #001 - LoLife</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2025/03/07/the-uncarved-block-001/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 18:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=4115</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For anybody looking to remix some music and/or art, I&amp;rsquo;m setting up The Uncarved Block as a forum on my Discord server. The goal is to provide a place for people to take a track or idea, and remix it into something new, and get some feedback from the community on what worked well, options for other ideas, and suggestions for what to do next. This will come together as a Soundcloud playlist to put all of the tracks together and a live stream to go over as many tracks as possible to listen to as a group and provide some constructive feedback on what to do or try next.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In the top 2%?!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024/05/10/in-the-top-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 14:53:43 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=4039</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a weird one for me for sure. I got an email that congratulated me for being in the top 2% of earners for buymeacoffee.com. Before you all start celebrating me and my &amp;ldquo;wild success&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;m going to drop some details, some thoughts, and probably a few opinions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with where I am today. My online digital &amp;ldquo;footprint&amp;rdquo; is kind of a mess, where I have accounts for all kinds of services, and I sort of know why I put some content somewhere, but also feel like I&amp;rsquo;m probably spread a bit too thin if I was trying to make a living out of all of this. I&amp;rsquo;m not really trying to make a living out of all of this, so that&amp;rsquo;s a good thing, but due to my &amp;ldquo;anti-capitalistic&amp;rdquo; behavior, I also get a peek into understanding why all this social media stuff is so hard from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NearTao&#39;s Acid Drop Sample and Patch Pack Available Now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/12/25/neartaos-acid-drop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 14:39:52 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=4025</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First up, about half of the samples are available for free at , and an SP404 mk2 ready project is available with included patterns at .  Check out the content ahead of time to see if any of it interests you before you pick up this pack. The Free Samples file is just samples, and the Sp404 mk2 Project is for the SP404 mk2 only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/neartaos-acid-drop-free-samples.zip&#34;&gt;NearTaos Acid Drop Free Samples&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/neartaos-acid-drop-free-samples.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal Project Management</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/07/29/__trashed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 19:05:48 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=3962</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey everybody!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working through deciding what project management software to setup for myself personally, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking through several options. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of interesting paid software, open source software, and a lot of opinions of what is best to use, how they integrate together. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot to dig through, but understanding others&amp;rsquo; experience with a tool is certainly helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve used Atlassian Jira, Redmine, Microsoft Project, Smartsheets, Bugzilla (though this was a freakish hack), text files, Cultured Code Things, Apple Reminders, and a boat load of other options.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Sample Pack] SP404 mk2 Session 54</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/04/18/sample-pack-sp404-mk2-session-54/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 13:02:21 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=3935</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/session-54.5-by-sa-samplepack.zip&#34;&gt;session-54.5-by-sa-samplepack&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/session-54.5-by-sa-samplepack.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These samples were recorded as part of my In Five series for the SP404 mk2 Session 54.  I used a Teenage Engineering OP-1 and a Chase Bliss Audio Mood to do a bit of sound design/exploration and to have some fun.  Nothing fancy here, but since Spicy Boi asked over in the YouTube comments for the samples, I&amp;rsquo;m providing them for anybody to grab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Session 54.5&amp;rsquo; by Greg Sterling at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.neartao.com&#34;&gt;http://www.neartao.com&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.  To view a copy of this license, visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Five Overview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/04/07/in-five-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 15:24:40 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=3870</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;kf6gpe over on my discord server asked about my process, and while I am more than happy to have a discussion about it, I figured it might be worth writing down in a blog to capture for others in the future as a distinct artifact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I get too deep into this, I wanted to let you, the reader know, that I&amp;rsquo;ll be intermingling thoughts of what I do with why I do it. This post will probably straddle the line between practical advice and philosophical discussion. If that&amp;rsquo;s not your cup of tea that&amp;rsquo;s okay. There are definitely plenty of resources out there, and I wish you well in finding what you are looking for!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SP404 mk2 Polyphony</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/03/08/sp404-mk2-polyphony/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 20:01:58 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=3856</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well&amp;hellip; I finally decided to get back to working on the guide again&amp;hellip; and I&amp;rsquo;m giving a try streaming a bit of the process while also trying to solve some problems. Here are two streams that probably should have been one, but I just need to get used to having a bit of dead air or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stereo-samples-panned-mono-left&#34;&gt;Stereo Samples Panned Mono Left&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first video shows the creation of a pattern using stereo samples, and I pan them left. We do not get to 32 pads playing, as the first 16 pads are still playing in stereo using up all 32 notes of polyphony.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.10</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/01/17/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 14:47:05 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=3666</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a pretty huge update, yikes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.10.pdf&#34;&gt;neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.10&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.10.pdf&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got a bit obsessive over the last few days, and read just about every single post in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elektronauts.com/t/roland-sp-404-mk2/161021/3386&#34;&gt;Elektronauts&amp;rsquo; SP-404 mk2 thread&lt;/a&gt; as well as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gearspace.com/board/electronic-music-instruments-and-electronic-music-production/1362254-roland-sp-404-mkii-37.html&#34;&gt;Gearspace SP-404 mk2 thread&lt;/a&gt;. This is well over 4000 posts to read through, and took me the better part of four or five days to complete. Lot&amp;rsquo;s of good questions, and lots of good answers, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I am up for doing a repeat of that any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.9</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/01/13/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 01:45:31 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=3662</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Taking some time to experiment with the 1.14 firmware release that just dropped. Going to take a bit to roll some of that information up into the Guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.9.pdf&#34;&gt;neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.9&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.9.pdf&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big update for today was finally running the experiment to determine polyphony once and for all for the mk2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoiler: it&amp;rsquo;s 32 note mono sample polyphony. If you&amp;rsquo;re using stereo samples then you&amp;rsquo;ve only got 16 notes of polyphony.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More Great Roland SP Vids &amp;amp; Music</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/01/13/more-great-roland-sp-vids-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 01:43:15 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=3657</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some more vids on the SP to check out&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/zjJB_dMuEtY&#34;&gt;Teebs Boiler Room London&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/GP3Iln5QimE&#34;&gt;Late Night Boom Bap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/kZexUgywc8w&#34;&gt;Beat Tape #3 Messy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BiaBRJJVNkY&#34;&gt;Dibia$e at Roland Artist Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/01/11/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 01:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=3647</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few hours of work here today, wanted to get more done, but needed to do some family stuff like cook dinner (tomato soup and grilled cheese sandwiches), wash the dogs&amp;hellip; and whatever else took up the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.8.pdf&#34;&gt;NearTao&amp;rsquo;s SP-404 mk2 Guide 0.8&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.8.pdf&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This latest update is quite a bit more than I&amp;rsquo;ve done over the last few days, a lot of links added to the reference section&amp;hellip; some day I&amp;rsquo;ll get ahold of a service manual link to add in, or figure some things out and add some of that documentation, but for now just a lot of links mostly for videos people posted about the mk2, technical information, various forums. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably end up pruning it down a bit, but figured I&amp;rsquo;d see what it started to take shape as.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Great Roland SP Vids &amp;amp; Music</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/01/11/some-great-roland-sp-vids-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 01:06:36 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=3643</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s just some links to sp stuff&amp;hellip; Wanted to share!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2neMRqYkw_s&#34;&gt;Khryo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/c9ksTvWXrzU&#34;&gt;Tajima Hal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SkQxZZYXV1U&#34;&gt;Nymano&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/WbIxeHDHBeQ&#34;&gt;Madlib in Brasilintime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/SqxxtL8rIE0&#34;&gt;Dibiase Boiler Room LA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/CDPcmYGPRKA&#34;&gt;Beat Culture and the 404 - Dibia$e&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MT_5FHoLqqA&#34;&gt;MUJO - SP404 Jazzy Live&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OhV_ngSxZE0&#34;&gt;LOFI hip hop jams on the sp 404 mk2 - spvidz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=akCFhrcxUDc&#34;&gt;Why is Lo-Fi so popular?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/01/10/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 01:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=3635</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was done yesterday, but family interrupted and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get it posted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.7.pdf&#34;&gt;neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.7&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.7.pdf&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started some information about gain staging, and then got side tracked. I mean it is important, but maybe doesn&amp;rsquo;t make a *ton* of sense in the context of the mk2, still&amp;hellip; will keep it in here for now, and see what makes sense as the book progresses. If anything, having the gain staging section prompted me to go off and try an experiment with EXT SOURCE and the pad turning red. Short answer if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to read the book is that the pad turns red if you are digitally clipping. If you want this or want to avoid it is definitely up to you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/01/10/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 12:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=3625</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was done yesterday, but family interrupted and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get it posted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.6.pdf&#34;&gt;neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.6&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.6.pdf&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changes here amount to maybe another hour worth of work, primarily focussed on the Sampling section. I figured it would be a good idea to add a Gain Staging section, although this is stubbed out for now. I do feel like I finished the Controls for External Source section for now. I did start on the Microphone/Guitar section, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to get some pedals and guitars hooked up first to verify a few things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.5b</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/01/08/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-5b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 22:26:31 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=3622</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a few days kicking off writing a guide for the Roland SP-404 mk2. Today I got about four hours into working on this document, and there is still so much more to do! You can grab the currently latest version here&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.5b.pdf&#34;&gt;NearTao&amp;rsquo;s SP-404 mk2 Guide 0.5b&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.5b.pdf&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to get a couple more hours into the guide and created a 0.5b document. Some restructuring, adjusting some sections to Roland terminology, and working through the Sampling section a bit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tear It All Down!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/11/17/tear-it-all-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 18:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=3561</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, the Tape Grain Glitch case is apart&amp;hellip; as you can see from the image for the post&amp;hellip; and I&amp;rsquo;ve got some work to do before I get it back together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, I flipped the Ladik A-520 and P-520 modules so that I can access the jumpers while working inside the case. The way they were oriented I&amp;rsquo;d have to take them out and the case apart to get at the jumpers to adjust the signal level changes. The change in orientation didn&amp;rsquo;t make too many problems either, biggest is that the power jack from the larger board sits right over the screw for the rubber foot of the case, so I just put some electrical tape over it to ensure that I don&amp;rsquo;t accidentally cause a short in the case.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track - Looking For A Solution</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/11/15/track-looking-for-a-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 16:17:07 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=3557</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Felt good putting this together! :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/F9XIBjI1QNY&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/F9XIBjI1QNY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Custom YouTube Channel Name</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/11/03/custom-youtube-channel-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 14:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=3497</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well&amp;hellip; I hit 100 subscribers, which feels like an accomplishment&amp;hellip; hah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/c/NearTao&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/c/NearTao&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yep, that&amp;rsquo;s it, instead of the long string of random numbers and letters that once defined me, I now have a vanity URL. So&amp;hellip; special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The funny thing is that I can see in the analytics it&amp;rsquo;s not any of the music videos I am doing that are drawing people, it&amp;rsquo;s all the tutorials, of which I don&amp;rsquo;t think I have done any since June or July. Should I do more? I&amp;rsquo;ll have to think about it I suppose.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #09 - Fireside Break</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/09/beatober2021-09-fireside-break/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 23:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=3360</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yeah yeah&amp;hellip; joke title&amp;hellip; I spent the day outdoors and was dead tired at the end of the day bon firing&amp;hellip; enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/ajmqTgWpHT8&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/ajmqTgWpHT8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 #08 - Old Blood</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/08/beatober2021-08-old-blood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 23:47:12 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=3356</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another drop out&amp;hellip; just a beat focussed on the MPC Live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/old-blood&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/old-blood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There isn&amp;rsquo;t really anything too fancy going on, just some loops played through the MPC Live&amp;rsquo;s new 2.10 Firmware effect Half Speed, with some extra filtering and effect tweaking to get it into the audio space that I felt would work well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beatober2021 Jam Session #02 - Low Key Loki</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/10/02/beatober2021-jam-session-02-low-key-loki/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 23:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=3319</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip; it happened :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/lLjtoBAxNPk&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/lLjtoBAxNPk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/beatober2021-02-low-key-loki?si=ecbbafc8400940f78fce1cecbf052eee&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/beatober2021-02-low-key-loki?si=ecbbafc8400940f78fce1cecbf052eee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#jamtember2021 Track - Ripping It</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/06/jamtember2021-track-ripping-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 22:52:42 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=3067</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just kind of done for the day&amp;hellip; not thrilled with the track, I just know it could&amp;rsquo;ve come out better. Spent too much time trying to make it work, and also kind of feel like I should have just ditched it and moved on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/ripping-it&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/ripping-it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is some really amazing graffiti from Hawaii. some really talented artists out there! Wish I had time to see more of what was going on out there, but what I saw was definitely solid.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The musical box of shame...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/08/20/the-musical-box-of-shame/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 16:41:08 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2967</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure a lot of us have it. A box in the corner with some music gear, instruments, effects, or whatever, that we want to use but don&amp;rsquo;t really use. For me, this box was holding an OP-1, OP-Z, Microgranny, Organelle, and plenty of other things. All really fun and cool gear, but I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to use them lately, and just wasn&amp;rsquo;t getting much value or use out of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syncing your MPC Live mk2/X/One to Eurorak Pamela&#39;s New Workout</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/06/03/syncing-your-mpc-live-mk2-x-one-to-eurorak-pamelas-new-workout/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 16:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2907</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/sfs5zI07JQw&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/sfs5zI07JQw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This video shows how to sync up your MPC Live mk2/X/One over CV gates to a Pamela&amp;rsquo;s New Workout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I&amp;rsquo;m not too worried about the variance in the BPM that shows up at higher levels. I&amp;rsquo;ve monitored the gates being sent over CV and have seen that it is not dropping gates, so over time the average will be correct, even if there is a small variance in the BPM at a specific gate trigger.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Setup your Akai MPC Live/X using Bluetooth Midi with your iPad running Beatmaker 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/05/25/how-to-setup-your-akai-mpc-live-x-using-bluetooth-midi-with-your-ipad-running-beatmaker-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 12:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2899</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a short video to show how to get Beatmaker 3 and your Akai MPC Live/X to work over bluetooth together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/ZPV6N5IQS6w&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/ZPV6N5IQS6w&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to add more power connections to your Eurorack Case</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/05/18/how-to-add-more-power-connections-to-your-eurorack-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 13:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2803</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First, a quick video&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/vUi1UKNZvuE&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/vUi1UKNZvuE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve hit a problem&amp;hellip; my Eurorack plans require 22-23 power connections, and I only have 20 provided by my Make Noise case. Assuming that the power supply is sufficient, I can use a flying bus cable to add some more power connection points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B078J7RPJ3?psc=1&amp;amp;ref=ppx_yo2_dt_b_product_details&#34;&gt;Synthrotek Deluxe 10 Connection Flying Bus Cable&lt;/a&gt; from Amazon because I figured 10 additional connections ought to be more than enough. The cable is actually long enough to add connections to across the case, but I wanted to cut it in half to show that it&amp;rsquo;s possible to still use the cable since it has the proper connector on both ends as you can see below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
