<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>#Jampril2021 on NearTao&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/%23jampril2021/</link>
    <description>Recent content in #Jampril2021 on NearTao&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 21:22:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/%23jampril2021/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Eat My Homework</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/30/eat-my-homework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 21:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2739</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/eat-my-homework&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/eat-my-homework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Took my family to Boston, left the dogs home. Came back to the dogs having eaten up my notebook. Like WTF&amp;hellip; we were an hour late from your usual feeding time, was it necessary to eat up my Hobonichi? Fortunately they didn&amp;rsquo;t eat up any important notes, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure Tomo River paper is good for their digestive system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At any rate&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s the end of the month, not really sure what this track is, but it&amp;rsquo;s in the *shrug* whatever&amp;hellip; it is the end of the month, and I ran out of time for the day to really pull something together. Guess I need to live with my failure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Follow Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/29/follow-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 21:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2734</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/follow-me&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/follow-me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is from my daughter walking away from me going to the mall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wrist is still really sore. Talked to the nurse, they can get me in to see me in about a week. Said to try some Ibuprofen in the meantime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think hitting the pads is causing me problems, this is similar to some issues I&amp;rsquo;ve had in the past, but far more extreme. Not really sure, but stretching seems to help. Also trying to avoid typing quite so much for work. Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daddio</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/28/daddio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 21:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2728</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/daddio&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/daddio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still sucks hitting the pads, but I&amp;rsquo;m trying to take a bit more mind of hitting the pads. I want to finish off the month and not have too much &amp;ldquo;junk&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I probably spent more time than I should have, and it didn&amp;rsquo;t help my right wrist much, but I&amp;rsquo;m really trying to figure out where the pain is, and if it is more from typing, sitting at a desk, hitting stuff, or what. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I have CTS or something, but the palm of my hand is sore, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t mention before but my right index finger is now cold. That started about a week ago, the coldness, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t think anything about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laying Back</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/27/laying-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 21:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2723</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/laying-back&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/laying-back&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another picture of the 3 string my dad made for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still not in great shape wrist wise, hitting the pads sucks, but I wanted to pull something out, and at least I&amp;rsquo;m happy enough with it. Just tried to keep it super simple and not worry about it, so I can worry about myself. Going to try and end out the month, but need to take care of myself as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple Trash</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/26/simple-trash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 21:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2719</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/simple-trash&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/simple-trash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am legit concerned I have permanent damage in my wrist. I wanted to work on this track and the day was already rough, couldn&amp;rsquo;t pull anything else together. This is my post of shame. Peace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Am I Out</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/25/am-i-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 21:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2715</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/am-i-out&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/am-i-out&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really wanted to get more done, but my wrist is absolutely killing me. Not sure if I pulled something, popped something, strained it, or just getting old. I really dig what I started here but I cannot handle tapping, typing or anything out. Might be done guys.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Go</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/24/lets-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 21:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2711</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/lets-go&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/lets-go&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay forehead. Yes it is mine&amp;hellip; some picture of me with sunglasses, and probably thinking about how cool I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kind of basic, and maybe a little too stripped down, and yet I got something together. I guess I&amp;rsquo;m just not feeling it really. A lot is going on and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I am going to finish the month off or not. Deal with it? I am dealing with it, but a track a day, plus family, plus a full-time job&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s a lot sometimes. Especially when you don&amp;rsquo;t get started until the end of the day to make a track.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Too Many</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/23/one-too-many/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 21:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2707</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/one-too-many&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/one-too-many&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, a dead spider in a glass. I think I used the picture before&amp;hellip; so sue me :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another stab at the LoFi sound, this one has a bit too much going on, but I do like the worn out sound, and had fun going different places in the different sections. Another one that feels like a pretty good stab at moving more towards a finished track than I have been in the past.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>They Are Watching</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/22/they-are-watching/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 21:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2703</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/they-are-watching&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/they-are-watching&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image is a double exposure. My nephew painting me an Isaac for Christmas, and I got around to hanging it up again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the track, well it&amp;rsquo;s wonky and glitched out a bit, but was something fun and mysterious. Have to see what to do with it next!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Going Out There</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/21/going-out-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 20:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2699</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/going-out-there&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/going-out-there&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is just an error code from my printer. Why? Well why not!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as the track goes&amp;hellip; is this space elevator music? I have no idea, but it sure is cheery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So Small</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/20/so-small/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 20:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2694</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/so-small&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/so-small&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is of some wrapping paper I think&amp;hellip; boy I forget what I took it from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the track, wanted to try a dark LoFi kind of sound, and I kind of like what I nailed here, but the mix is too low, and it really needs some mastering to kick it into gear. Feels like something that&amp;rsquo;s near where I&amp;rsquo;d want a completed track to be though, so I dig it :D&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back of the Throat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/19/back-of-the-throat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 20:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2690</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/back-of-the-throat&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/back-of-the-throat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, that&amp;rsquo;s my mouth&amp;hellip; hah&amp;hellip; no screaming though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have no idea where this came from, but it just felt like a goofy kind of Summer DJ track to me. Not sure what to do with it, it probably needs some more high end sparkle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long Stretch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/18/long-stretch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 20:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2685</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/long-stretch&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/long-stretch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is from a bill that my dog ate. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I know the one. I&amp;rsquo;ve taped the bill back together, so it ought to be legal tender, but it just looked like something worth using for a track image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a ton of fun working on grooving with this track, and I think it&amp;rsquo;s on the list of something I really need to get back on and turn it into something to finish as a track. I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve got some work in front of me to get all these things moving :D&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Just Wanna</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/17/i-just-wanna/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 20:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2680</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/i-just-wanna&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/i-just-wanna&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip; I just scribbled this down in a notebook to get the picture&amp;hellip; nothing fancy, but I needed some kind of artwork and had no other idea what to do. Seems kinda cool though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the track itself, I wanted to spend some more time putting together the track, so there&amp;rsquo;s a bit more elements going on and it feels like a bit more complete of an idea to me at least. The Vox is okay&amp;hellip; I suppose I should&amp;rsquo;ve taken out the high end synth&amp;hellip; and just recorded my own vocals. Next time I do a month of tracks, probably need to force myself to do my own vocals and see where I go.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another Snowy Day</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/16/another-snowy-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 20:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2676</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/another-snowy-day&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/another-snowy-day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I literally cannot believe that it snowed today. But then again, welcome to New England baby&amp;hellip; the snow didn&amp;rsquo;t last that long, but we got probably 4-5 inches. Enough to notice and stick around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just wanted to make something chill for the day, so it&amp;rsquo;s nothing too crazy, but just kind of a laid back vibe. I mean yeah&amp;hellip; we&amp;rsquo;ve probably got the last day of snow for the season&amp;hellip; better relax and enjoy it!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jacked In</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/15/jacked-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 20:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2672</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/jacked-in&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/jacked-in&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright&amp;hellip; first&amp;hellip; I really had fun on this track, as short as it is. This feels like something I want to come back to and finish when I have some proper time to focus on it. The intent was to get something kind of light and refreshing&amp;hellip; and I feel like this hit that itch for me. Just a nice little wall of sounds all working together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silent Gris</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/14/silent-gris/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 18:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2666</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/silent-gris&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/silent-gris&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is just a silly little doodle I had done in my notebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the track, just trying to work out something a bit wonky and that felt off kilter today. I kind of dig the vibe, though I don&amp;rsquo;t know so much about the Vox. The track needed some vocals, but I think there&amp;rsquo;s something better to go in here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discfaux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/13/discfaux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 18:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2661</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/discfaux&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/discfaux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know why, but I got it in my head to try and do a bit of a disco track. The track kind of has the funk a bit, but I feel like it&amp;rsquo;s missing an element or two to make it really scream disco. As it stands, it feels like it is missing half the band, but I was running out of time to put something together and just wanted to see where this could get me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some What Funk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/12/some-what-funk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 18:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2654</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/some-what-funk&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/some-what-funk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is of a 3 string cigar box guitar my dad made for me. Something I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to get to work better for some time. I&amp;rsquo;ll get into it in a blog post somewhere, but my dad didn&amp;rsquo;t align a few parts correctly, so it needs some love!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the song, I was really just trying to go for a straight up hip hop/break beat kind of sound, and keep it moving. I like the track overall, but think it could use some stripping back of a few elements, and maybe add something a little different? I don&amp;rsquo;t know, seems like something I am poking on a bit for what I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting together lately. Time for some self reflection?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Go Hard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/11/go-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 18:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2644</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/go-hard&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/go-hard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright this track is just me messing around with FX&amp;hellip; mostly delay, and trying to make something that feels happier. I know it is super goofy, but it was fun to put together. Probably needs to be peeled back a little on that arp/synth part&amp;hellip; or get it&amp;rsquo;s own section to fill out&amp;hellip; but this just put a smile on my face while working on it :D&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Friendly Faces</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/10/friendly-faces/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 18:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2639</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/friendly-faces&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/friendly-faces&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture comes from a trip to Greece I took two years ago with my family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was trying to put something a bit more LoFi sounding together, and I kind of feel like I failed. The mix is just off, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really feel dirty enough. Overall, I find the bass too loud and it probably needs some major taming. What was I thinking? Uhm&amp;hellip; not sure lol!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dependable Record</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/09/dependable-record/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 18:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2633</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/dependable-record&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/dependable-record&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this track I was trying to think about transitions between sections a bit more, and trying to see how it would come together. I kind of think the higher end synth sound is a bit distracting, and the track would probably be better without it. Maybe a few too many elements?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am happy with the track feeling a bit more funky though, and trying to add in a few more somewhat random sounds moving in and out feels like a good effect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rockin Mystic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/06/rockin-mystic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 17:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2578</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another track for day six, and way happier with how this came out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/rockin-mystic&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/rockin-mystic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who said you can only do one track a day max? I had about 30 minutes free and ripped this one. I dig how it came out compared to the other track. I think most of what I like about it is that it&amp;rsquo;s simpler, and while it is pretty in your face, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have quite so much going on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lets Grab Lunch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/06/lets-grab-lunch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 17:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2570</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 6, and put this together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/lets-grab-lunch&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/lets-grab-lunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another Boss SP 303 sampled song, I spent a *lot* of time sampling into the SP 303, and then resampled back into the MPC. There are some things that I like here, but boy was it a lot of work, and honestly, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure the result was entirely worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like some of the sounds and how they came out, but I feel like this is not really that great. The Vox probably could use more work to make it different or change over time, and this is where I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m hitting a bit of a wall with producing exclusively on the MPC right now. Just a bit too much work to pull the audio apart and do something different with it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big Hammer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/05/big-hammer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 21:22:46 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2563</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day five of #jampril2021 and still going. Made another drum kit and posted it up on the discord server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/big-hammer&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/big-hammer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This track was still hitting it into the Boss SP 303 and just recording off more samples for the FX. Definitely getting faster at sampling into the 303 and then resampling back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tried track mutes with timing corrects which worked out alright&amp;hellip; then doubled up the track and layered in a new track with some additional sounds/enhancements to spice things up. The mix is a bit off, but happy enough with how the track came out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breathing In</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/04/breathing-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 23:33:42 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2516</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is day four track&amp;hellip; and another one working with the SP 303 to sample and mess with the FX a bit. What did I do exactly? Uh&amp;hellip; not sure&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/breathing-in&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/breathing-in&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another track of sampling into the SP 303, and running effects and stuff, and then sampling back into the MPC to make a finished drum kit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I played everything out with the Track Mute again&amp;hellip; but this time used TC. It helped a bit&amp;hellip; at least making it more obvious where problems were. Would try again hah.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where My Boys</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/03/where-my-boys/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 11:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2507</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 3&amp;hellip; This track I mostly wanted to mess around with the Boss SP 303 to understand the sampling workflow a bit better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/where-my-boys&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/where-my-boys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is Isaac from the game &amp;ldquo;The Binding of Isaac&amp;rdquo;. Cool kid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put this together I drove samples into the SP 303 C and D banks. They are much faster to sample on, even though it is still quite slow compared to modern standards. It was a pretty good way to test out the repair job that I did for the pads as well, since I was bouncing around a lot of the buttons, minus the pattern stuff. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how much I care to bother with pattern sequencing here when I can just resample everything into the MPC. So I filled up all 16 smart media sample slots between bank C and D&amp;hellip; The samples came in between a mix of raw, and sometimes with some effects already running, and I did end up adding effects on the way out back into the MPC as well to make a drum kit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spring is Here</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/02/spring-is-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 14:05:58 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2428</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This track is better than yesterday&amp;hellip; though still needs some tweaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/spring-is-here&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/neartao/spring-is-here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is just some flowers that my wife bought&amp;hellip; Calla Lilies if you&amp;rsquo;re interested. We&amp;rsquo;re trying to get more flowers in the house and make it feel more like home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the track, this is straight up another MPC Live track. I grabbed a handful of samples and just got to chopping. I know I could have done a better job getting some of the slices together, but I tried to do it by ear as much as possible, and hey, I continue to approve of the slightly wonky and janky sound. So it was a lot of using the threshold chop mode to get the party started, and then adjusting the start/end points a bit by ear. I know for sure that a few of the mistakes in the chops came from forgetting to turn off the linked slices afterwards, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t really been doing much for tracks over the last TWO months, which has gotten me quite a bit out of practice. Only done a few hit or miss beat battles in between, and I hadn&amp;rsquo;t even bothered to write up a post about them. Well, I do need to get myself more focussed again&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Damn Fool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/01/damn-fool/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 02:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.wordpress.com/?p=2440</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m being foolish, and figuring it is time for me to get back to a track a day. It is my punishment for being lazy for three months and hardly doing any tracks. To be fair I did move over the last three months, had no internet for a month, and was busy building shelving throughout the house, including an at least 30 hour project building a pantry. Excuses excuses&amp;hellip; now I need to get back off my butt!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
