<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland-Sp-404-Mk2 on NearTao&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/roland-sp-404-mk2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Roland-Sp-404-Mk2 on NearTao&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 16:29:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/roland-sp-404-mk2/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.36</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024/11/02/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-36/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 16:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=4074</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most importantly (for me at least) is I&amp;rsquo;m still kicking! For those who have been paying attention, I&amp;rsquo;ve been slowly branching out into other instruments on my YouTube channel, and starting to look into things like the Dirtywave M8, Roland P-6, and Ableton Move. There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of cool gear out there, and certainly not enough free time to cover it all. That said, I do try and keep the Guide going as new thoughts come to mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.33</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024/05/21/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 12:59:45 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=4063</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey everybody, it&amp;rsquo;s been a long time coming to get the guide updated for firmware 4.04, but it is finally here! What&amp;rsquo;s happened in between? Well I dropped the Quick Reference for the SP404 mk2, which was a lot of fun to make, but super time consuming. Plus within just a few days of releasing it, Roland dropped the 4.04 firmware update. I decided to invest the effort into updating the Quick Reference for 4.04 rather than the guide, and then I sunk time into getting some 4.04 videos out. It&amp;rsquo;s been a crazy couple of months!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.29</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/12/11/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 20:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=4018</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s an updated version of the guide. At this point, it is mostly changes coming in from people asking questions on my YouTube videos, and my curiosity to dig in and see if I can find suitable answers, solutions, or in some cases workflows. So the update is again an accumulation of a lot of minor tweaks and things I have learned about the SP404 mk2 from people asking questions that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know the answer to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.28</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/07/15/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 15:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3940</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a few simple tweaks for today based on some information I learned while running a few experiments (and answering questions) on my live stream at &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtube.com/live/LT8YEWt7zuY?feature=share&#34;&gt;https://youtube.com/live/LT8YEWt7zuY?feature=share&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan was to figure out a few volume maximums/limits, especially for recording. I decided to use the USB-C audio interface connection from the SP404 mk2 to my computer since it is a digital connection and I assume (a bit grossly perhaps) that it should be consistent for us. From here, I spent some time recording test tones, tried to record as loud as I could through the line ins and mic/inst jack without clipping, and then did some comparative analysis through Ableton Live to see how these various recordings compared to normalized audio.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.27</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/04/07/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 01:20:27 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3930</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a first pass to try and incorporate all of the changes that came in for Firmware 3.0. I am quite certain I&amp;rsquo;ve got to go back and rewrite sections, organize some data differently, and overall rethink how this guide is put together. That said, I did spend a lot of time trying to get everything together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.27.pdf&#34;&gt;neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.27&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.27.pdf&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.26</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/03/13/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 15:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3864</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;m behind on getting updates to 3.0. This still covers firmware 2.01, but I&amp;rsquo;ll be pivoting to 3.0 soon, I promise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.26.pdf&#34;&gt;neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.26&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.26.pdf&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just excited to see 3.0 drop, and this update was really just to get me back in the habit of writing updates, in prep for whenever something big happened. Last week I tried doing some live streams to chat with folks while also working on the guide, some of them worked, and some of them didn&amp;rsquo;t. If you catch a stream, feel free to drop in and say hi, ask questions, give suggestions, or anything else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.25</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/01/05/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 18:11:01 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3840</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip; a lot has happened over the last four(?!) months, for me personally&amp;hellip; not so much the mk2 guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.25.pdf&#34;&gt;neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.25&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.25.pdf&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s see, where to start? I got my first donation of $5 over at buymeacoffee.com, super cool, and big thanks. I know I keep telling you all it&amp;rsquo;s not necessary (it isn&amp;rsquo;t), and I keep doing all of this work for free, but I also want to say it is greatly appreciated. It&amp;rsquo;s going into my future gear purchase fund when I find the next device I want to dig into. I suspect I know what it will be, but well, let&amp;rsquo;s wait and see.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.24</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/08/04/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 08:24:01 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3802</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey folks, guess it&amp;rsquo;s been nearly three months since I last updated the guide. Yikes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.24.pdf&#34;&gt;NearTao&amp;rsquo;s SP-404 mk2 Guide 0.24&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.24.pdf&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first pass at trying to get the firmware 2.0 changes wrapped around my head. I know I missed a few section updates, mostly in the settings area, and I am sure there are some shortcuts I need to wrap around to getting added into the guide, but by and large I do feel like I understand it pretty well now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.23</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/05/13/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 20:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3773</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A request came in to add a shortcut section, so I added an Appendix G and tried to organize it in a way that made more sense to me than what information is in the official manual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.23.pdf&#34;&gt;NearTao&amp;rsquo;s SP-404 mk2 Guide 0.23&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.23.pdf&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anybody has been wondering where the updates have been for the guide, well I&amp;rsquo;ve partly been lazy, I have been trying to figure out how to improve the YouTube videos for the mk2, and well I went on vacation. The vacation was with my family, we drove about 1200 or so miles to get down to North Carolina, and I had a lot of fun at both the Ocean Isles Beach, and then we spent a day in South Carolina at Myrtle Beach. I did bring the mk2 with me, and was able to spend the first day with my nephew showing him a bit about the mk2, but he is more interested in his iPad and using Garage Band at this time. We had fun, but beyond that I hardly touched the mk2. Not for lack of trying, but it was a lot of driving, keeping friends and family entertained, cooking, and at the end of the day just being tired. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping I&amp;rsquo;ll get some more time in July with the mk2 on my trip to Brazil with my family&amp;hellip; *fingers crossed*.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.22</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/04/11/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 15:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3763</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The update is mostly focussed on the Midi and Companion App chapters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.22.pdf&#34;&gt;NearTao&amp;rsquo;s SP-404 mk2 Guide 0.22&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.22.pdf&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose the &amp;ldquo;big news&amp;rdquo; is that firmware version 1.15 dropped. It fixes a couple of bugs, I don&amp;rsquo;t think I ever hit them. Given this rather weak update for the mk2, my suspicion is that we&amp;rsquo;re not likely to see anything terribly interesting for firmware updates until the supply chain issues work themselves out. I get it, Roland wants to get the most market bang for the buck, and if they are continuing to sell through stock before it ever hits the shelves, then there is no reason to do anything expansive until they need to be able to drive more business. I&amp;rsquo;m happy to be proven wrong, but I just don&amp;rsquo;t think belly aching about the lack of new filters, or new features, or whatever you&amp;rsquo;d like is going to get much traction right now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.21</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/03/29/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 17:41:05 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3760</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The update is mostly focussed on system settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.21.pdf&#34;&gt;NearTao&amp;rsquo;s SP-404 mk2 Guide 0.21&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.21.pdf&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big section update is for the Chapter on the Utility menu, and for at least System, Pad Set, and EFX Set, I have added as much color and detail as possible without loosing my mind. I know I&amp;rsquo;ve said I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t try to recreate the manual, but I felt it was important to go over these sections because the interface does a poor job explaining what some of the settings are, and the manual isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly clear of why you would want to use some of these settings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.20</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/03/21/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 21:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3750</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is mostly about restructuring the guide&amp;hellip; and setting it up for a more consumable future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.20.pdf&#34;&gt;neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.20&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.20.pdf&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, didn&amp;rsquo;t mean to take so long, or be such a small update overall, but I guess I fell off the working on the mk2 wagon. Part of my time went to wrapping up artwork for a children&amp;rsquo;s book I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on with my sister for a year now, and I don&amp;rsquo;t know… I guess I just haven&amp;rsquo;t felt myself much the last two or three weeks. No big deal, but just kind of hit this funk. The &amp;ldquo;I am tired of being home all the time and never really seeing anybody&amp;rdquo; head space. Ended up taking a long weekend with my wife in Burlington VT while my parent&amp;rsquo;s watched our daughter and two dogs. Was good to get out, have a few beers, and if anything, it did give me a bit of a reset and clear my head some.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.19</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/03/01/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 20:34:41 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3742</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DJ Mode and the related topics are more or less done now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.19.pdf&#34;&gt;neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.19&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.19.pdf&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My daughter has school vacation this week and I decided to take the time off to both spend with her and get some more time into working on the guide. This update was actually really good in that it got me more thinking about how to write up DJ Mode over the last few days, as well as really thinking about what I think is actually valuable for the guide in general.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.18</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/02/27/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 21:33:13 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3733</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So Pattern Mode and the related topics are more or less done now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.18.pdf&#34;&gt;neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.18&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.18.pdf&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, between continuing writing up the guide, and making videos, I guess it&amp;rsquo;s out there and seems to be helping people out. I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting a bit of folks posting here or there. If you&amp;rsquo;ve written me a message someplace and I haven&amp;rsquo;t responded I promise I am not ignoring you, I&amp;rsquo;m just ignoring the forums so I can make sure I have time to write and record as my primary focus. I am trying to get around to catching up on the various forums once a week or so. Thanks to those of you have reached out though, it means a lot and I am glad I could help.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.17</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/02/18/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 23:59:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3719</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Boy, another big update. I was planning on moving to a weekly schedule for updates to be more consistent, but these bigger updates also feel more draining. I&amp;rsquo;ll have to think about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.17-2.pdf&#34;&gt;NearTao&amp;rsquo;s SP-404 mk2 Guide 0.17&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.17-2.pdf&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of this update is just writing up the effects section, and I tried to stick to give my thoughts and advice for the effects, rather than just rehashing whatever is in the manual. As with a lot of the guide, I&amp;rsquo;ll eventually come back and rewrite sections, or add some more content, but as it stands, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to write any more about bread and butter effects that you can find anywhere. Although it is alphabetical, you&amp;rsquo;ll certainly find where I started to loose my mind trying to write up something about some of the effects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.16</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/02/10/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 18:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3709</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alright, an absolutely epic update today. This one broke my brain working on it for about five hours straight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.16.pdf&#34;&gt;neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.16&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.16.pdf&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent a fair amount of time just getting the handful of pages written up about Skip Back. I had to chase down a few things that I thought I knew how they worked, but I wanted to make sure I captured it properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real work though, was filling out the previously titled Mixer section, and now renamed to Audio Signal Flow section. Just drawing the diagram was a lot of work, and then peeling apart each layer was an important onion to break down, but holy smokes. I kind of just gave up at the Limiter and Clipper section because I don&amp;rsquo;t see *anything* that remotely explains how they work for the mk2 or why they are there. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen some people mentioning the mk2 coloring their sound, and I wonder if there is something going on here&amp;hellip; which will require some experiments, but I am D O N E for the day. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll get more time on the book tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.15</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/02/09/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 02:49:23 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3705</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This update focus on the Sample Mode section, and I dumped in some of the related topics like Chromatic, Cue, and other things that can help determine how a pad may play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.15.pdf&#34;&gt;neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.15&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.15.pdf&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, I spent probably way too much time to figure out how End Mark works, but I figured it out and documented it. This helped land a few updates into the Sample Edit section to also add information about copy/delete for a sample. I kind of think I already typed this up in data management, but whatever&amp;hellip; if I duplicated information, well I can get around to fixing it when I get to a place where I am ready to start reviewing the document. For now, I&amp;rsquo;m just trying to get it as complete as I can.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.14</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/02/02/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 01:18:15 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3699</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spent some time on the Sample Edit section, and tried to think about how to discuss some workflows without getting into it too deeply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.14.pdf&#34;&gt;neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.14&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.14.pdf&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m trying to strike the right balance between opinions, thoughts on how to do things, and just stuff that feels like issues with Sample Edit. Maybe I am being too picky, or maybe these things could just work better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still happy with the mk2 though, and will continue writing things up. I&amp;rsquo;ve just started a new job, so trying to balance transitioning my old work, picking up new work, family, and working on music, has caused me to slow down a bit on the guide for a little bit. I promise I am still keeping at it though!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.13</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/01/26/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 02:36:35 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3692</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most of this update was filling in the Sample section to the best of my abilities within my time constraints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.13.pdf&#34;&gt;NearTao&amp;rsquo;s SP-404 mk2 Guide 0.13&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.13.pdf&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s some things that I thought I understood about sampling on the mk2, that I&amp;rsquo;m clearly going to have to go back to. I also skipped on the Skip Back section, because honestly, I think it deserves it&amp;rsquo;s own heading/section as it is quite distinct (though related) to sampling, and has some interesting workflow implications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.12</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/01/23/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 01:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3687</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This update was to try and fill in some information about the actual Data in the mk2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.12.pdf&#34;&gt;neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.12&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.12.pdf&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent some time trying to figure out the directory structure and format of different files. So far I haven&amp;rsquo;t figured out much about the .bin files, or how the mk2 might be storing or managing much of the data. This will take some time to work through, and I have a few ideas for experiments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Guide v0.11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/01/19/roland-sp-404-mk2-guide-v0-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3675</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another experiment, and trying to wrap up the Audio Input/Audio Export sections&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.11.pdf&#34;&gt;neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.11&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/neartaos-sp-404-mk2-guide-0.11.pdf&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got some ideas for linking some working session videos with the guide, so stay tuned for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last two days were mostly about trying to flesh out some of the existing sections some more. Primarily the audio input section, but that also drove me to adding a new section for audio output as well. I&amp;rsquo;m nearly done with these, and should be able to get into more detail for getting into sampling and adjusting samples soon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Couple of SP-404 mk2 tracks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/12/13/couple-of-sp-404-mk2-tracks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:06:19 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3602</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Still having fun with the mk2! I find it to occupy a nice space between my other gear, it&amp;rsquo;s not as powerful as the MPC Live as a sampler or for creating patterns, but there&amp;rsquo;s also something refreshing about being limited. Also, the product line has been quite focussed on resampling in the past, and the 404 mk2 really isn&amp;rsquo;t different from that regard. To get the most out of it you&amp;rsquo;re encouraged to sample from your line/instrument/mic inputs and use fx to sculpt a sound from there. Yeah yeah&amp;hellip; super natural for people who have been there, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been seeing some people saying they are not into resampling&amp;hellip; and what the SP to be something it probably never will be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 Firmware 1.13 Bugs, Issues, Concerns, Oddities, and Feature Requests</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/11/29/roland-sp-404-mk2-firmware-1-13-bugs-issues-concerns-oddities-and-feature-requests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 14:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3585</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These notes are all for SP 404 mk2 firmware 1.13.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bugs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In pattern mode there is a slight gap between the end of a pattern and the start back to 1.1.1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In pattern mode edit, you cannot adjust the start position of the pattern, only the end position.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exported samples do not contain the project they were from, just named “&amp;lt;bank 1-10&amp;gt; &lt;pad&gt; &lt;sample name&gt; Sample”.  The bank should be a-j to match naming, it should include the project, and there ought to be a way to name the sample.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exporting samples will overwrite whatever you have on the SD card without warning you that there is already a sample there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Issues&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland SP-404 mk2 - Second(?) Attempts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/11/26/roland-sp-404-mk2-second-attempts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 02:19:18 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3582</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Had some slight misinformation… the semitone changes with PITCH/SPEED are -12 semitones and +7 semitones for a range (effectively down 50% or up 50%). The CHROMATIC mode can do +/- 12 semitones. Obviously you can resample to stretch beyond this… but wanted to clarify that if you&amp;rsquo;ve got something specific you&amp;rsquo;re looking to do that you may want to make sure you know what mode(s) can do what.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I messed around for a couple hours today and was able to get a few samples going, dug into resampling and skip back… and you can def make some solid loops.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Roland SP-404 mk2 is in... Initial Thoughts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/11/26/the-roland-sp-404-mk2-is-in-initial-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 14:37:38 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://neartao.com/?p=3574</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Got mine Wednesday&amp;hellip; been knocking on the pads quite a bit. Never had a 404 (but got the 202 and 303)&amp;hellip; mostly a heavy MPC user&amp;hellip; so my thoughts come at this through mostly an MPC lens, but definitely with appreciation of where the SP line has come from in previous generations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the first things I did was hook up my iPad to the mk2 over USB C. I will tell you, this is an amazingly seamless connection that carries audio and midi data like a champ. Some apps you may have to worry about routing, but stuff like Koala Sampler and Korg Module Pro work wonderfully. You can throw audio and samples around so damn fast it&amp;rsquo;ll make your head spin, and is just *chef&amp;rsquo;s kiss* for bouncing effects back and forth. Even better, if you have Audio Bus 3 or AUM, you can access the stereo inputs, or two stereo outputs directly. Heck, you can even route to outputs 1/2/3/4 as mono, and get your iPad four mono track outputs as it honors those outputs correctly. All of this works without going into any special modes, or booting the 404 as a controller or anything else. Seriously a killer feature in my mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
